<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>WordPress Trac</title>
    <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/timeline</link>
    <description>Trac Timeline</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <generator>Trac 1.2.2</generator>
    <image>
      <title>WordPress Trac</title>
      <url>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/chrome/site/your_project_logo.png</url>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/timeline</link>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>Ticket #10201 (Remove user-specific caps) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 23:58:43 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10201#comment:4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10201#comment:4/1245283123000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
for reference: &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5255" title="#5255: task (blessed): Simplify role/capability for easier cap =&amp;gt; user lookups (closed: wontfix)"&gt;#5255&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5540" title="#5540: enhancement: User roles overhaul (closed: wontfix)"&gt;#5540&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5541" title="#5541: enhancement: Refactor and simplify WP_Roles (closed: wontfix)"&gt;#5541&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/2787" title="#2787: enhancement: New Method of storing and calculating cap2user and user2cap (closed: wontfix)"&gt;#2787&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reopened ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5942" title="#5942: feature request: Add Owner role (reopened)"&gt;#5942&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10201 (Remove user-specific caps) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 23:46:08 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10201#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10201#comment:3/1245282368000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
see also &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/2531" title="#2531: enhancement: Functions for registering additional capabilities and getting a list ... (closed: wontfix)"&gt;#2531&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5255 (Simplify role/capability for easier cap =&gt; user lookups) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 23:44:49 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5255#comment:21</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5255#comment:21/1245282289000000</guid>
      <description>wontfix: &lt;p&gt;
see &lt;a class="assigned ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10201" title="#10201: enhancement: Remove user-specific caps (assigned)"&gt;#10201&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5540 (User roles overhaul) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 23:44:31 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5540#comment:23</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5540#comment:23/1245282271000000</guid>
      <description>wontfix: &lt;p&gt;
see &lt;a class="assigned ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10201" title="#10201: enhancement: Remove user-specific caps (assigned)"&gt;#10201&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5541 (Refactor and simplify WP_Roles) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 23:44:16 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5541#comment:7</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5541#comment:7/1245282256000000</guid>
      <description>wontfix: &lt;p&gt;
see &lt;a class="assigned ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10201" title="#10201: enhancement: Remove user-specific caps (assigned)"&gt;#10201&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #2787 (New Method of storing and calculating cap2user and user2cap) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 23:43:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/2787#comment:22</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/2787#comment:22/1245282232000000</guid>
      <description>wontfix: &lt;p&gt;
see &lt;a class="assigned ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10201" title="#10201: enhancement: Remove user-specific caps (assigned)"&gt;#10201&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5942 (Add Owner role) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 23:43:32 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5942#comment:6</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5942#comment:6/1245282212000000</guid>
      <description>wontfix: &lt;p&gt;
see &lt;a class="assigned ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10201" title="#10201: enhancement: Remove user-specific caps (assigned)"&gt;#10201&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #2531 (Functions for registering additional capabilities and getting a list ...) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 23:43:13 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/2531#comment:26</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/2531#comment:26/1245282193000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Milestone&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
see &lt;a class="assigned ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10201" title="#10201: enhancement: Remove user-specific caps (assigned)"&gt;#10201&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #8663 (Allow customizing capabilities prefix through wp-config.php) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 23:42:22 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8663#comment:9</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8663#comment:9/1245282142000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
see &lt;a class="assigned ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10201" title="#10201: enhancement: Remove user-specific caps (assigned)"&gt;#10201&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10201 (Remove user-specific caps) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 23:40:04 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10201#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10201#comment:2/1245282004000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
so, basically, the consensus is:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;drop multi-role support
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;drop user-cap support
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;single-role on users
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;drop true|false thingy on has _cap|hsn't_cap (use role stuff instead)
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;make it so that user roles can be queried easily (we'd use a meta field with the role's key here)
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;
leaving this open for a week or two without touching it, so that sam can take a look if needs be.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10201 (Remove user-specific caps) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 23:14:01 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10201#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10201#comment:1/1245280441000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Owner&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Status&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Component&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
posting the raw log, will summarize later:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;ddebernardy: you mean roles control in admin like wp-roles did?
12:08 AM MarkJaquith
ddebernardy: here is my idea on roles:
12:08 AM jeffr0
wow, alot of people would be cheering if role management received an overhaul and was more user friendly/ more granular
12:08 AM Jane_
will post on dev blog later this week or more likely early next week with prioritization poll. hopefully using andy peatling's nifty drag and drop feature ranking system from buddypress site.
12:08 AM jeffr0
heh I saw Andys roadmap stuff
12:08 AM aaroncampbell
jeffr0: I think you're the first one to mention "sitemap"
12:08 AM rboren
http://bbpress.org/plugins/topic/user-roles-table-for-bbpress/
12:09 AM
Used on talkpress on some other places.
12:09 AM ddebernardy
aaroncampbell - I was meaning this:
12:09 AM
http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/2531#comment:20
12:09 AM
and rboren's reference
12:09 AM MarkJaquith
My idea: Get rid of the concept of negated capabilities. No one uses them. Get rid of the idea of standalone capability  granting. Almost no one uses it. Get rid of the idea of multiple roles. No one uses it. Just have wp_user_role = 'author' in the meta table.
12:10 AM Jane_
see you guys
12:10 AM Jane_ is now known as jane|dinner
12:10 AM aaroncampbell
ddebernardy: I thought that jeffr0 was talking about the permalink history.  Not sure I was correct, but is there a ticket for that one?
12:11 AM ddebernardy
oh, sorry, was meaning to reply to bi0xid
12:11 AM bi0xid
MarkJaquith: I think i don't understand. I use roles subscriber, author, editor and admin in almost all the blogs i admin. Do you want to eliminate them?
12:11 AM ddebernardy
yeah, permalink history would mean being able to drop all of the redirection plugins
12:11 AM MarkJaquith
bi0xid: no.
12:11 AM
bi0xid: by multiple roles, I mean a person who is both an admin and an subscriber.
12:12 AM bi0xid
ooh
12:12 AM
MarkJaquith:
12:12 AM MarkJaquith
You probably didn't know WP could do that. Because NO ONE uses it. :-)
12:12 AM bi0xid
MarkJaquith: agreed. If you want to have 2 profiles, then use 2 users.
12:12 AM Fredelig
:)
12:12 AM aaroncampbell
MarkJaquith: since there's not a limit to the number of roles, I think that the few people that use that could just create another role that is the equivalent to those two roles combined
12:13 AM ddebernardy
bi0xid - not so, if you've a membership plugin of sorts
12:13 AM MarkJaquith
aaroncampbell: exactly.
12:13 AM bi0xid
that's the poing
12:13 AM
*point
12:13 AM rboren
To get user with a certain cap, see which roles have that cap, see if user has one of those roles.
12:14 AM MarkJaquith
yep, rboren.
12:14 AM ddebernardy
and seeing which users have those roles amounts to querying all users
12:14 AM
it's a major problem atm
12:14 AM MarkJaquith
ddebernardy: indeed. users.php doesn't scale because of it.
12:14 AM ddebernardy
exactly
12:15 AM MarkJaquith
The authors dropdown doesn't scale because of it.
12:15 AM ddebernardy
ok, so I take it that new roles tables will have more traction?
12:15 AM nikolayb has left IRC (Read error: 54 (Connection reset by peer))
12:15 AM MarkJaquith
ddebernardy: I don't see that a table is needed.
12:15 AM ddebernardy
it's needed for joins
12:15 AM
you don't want this stuff in a meta table
12:15 AM MarkJaquith
you can use usermeta as user-to-role
12:16 AM ddebernardy
meta joining an integrer on a text field is not the most efficient thing there is
12:16 AM
sql joining even
12:17 AM MarkJaquith
agreed. But I don't think the speed you lose in storing it in usermeta is worth adding a whole new table just for that.
12:17 AM ddebernardy
if we decide to drop the true|false thingy as you suggest, we've less tables but it's less flexbile
12:17 AM
MarkJaquith - it is, when you implement a membership plugin
12:17 AM MarkJaquith
It's just as flexible. It may just require more roles to do it.
12:17 AM ddebernardy
it makes evry difference in teh world, in fact
12:18 AM
so much so, that the better membership plugins create a separate table, memberships
12:18 AM rboren
Well, a problem with usermeta is that you have to use db prefixes to get the role for a given blog.  Having a blog id would be nicer.
12:18 AM ddebernardy
and then user2membership and membership2post
12:19 AM nikolayb has joined the channel.
12:19 AM ddebernardy
rboren - there is a ticket related to a CAPS define, related to that
12:19 AM
added a patch a few days ago
12:19 AM
but obvious not relevant if we get the roles tables fixed
12:19 AM
because we also need to be able to sort out a common desire for users to have the same role across blogs
12:22 AM
#8663
12:22 AM wp-trac-bot
ddebernardy: http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8663 normal, normal, 2.9, hudatoriq-&amp;gt;hudatoriq, new, Allow customizing capabilities prefix through wp-config.php
12:22 AM Viper007Bond has left IRC ("http://www.viper007bond.com/ | http://www.finalgear.com/" )
12:23 AM MarkJaquith
Oh neat... that's been bothering me for a long time that you couldn't do that. I have a script that syncs the caps :-)
12:23 AM ddebernardy
anyway, is that a go for it for a role revamp in 2.9?
12:24 AM DD32
Little late i know, But Roles: Just simplify them, Dont bother with a new table unless its absolutely needed, Theres no need to move from an awkwardly complex system no-one uses, to another complex setup that no-one uses. - A single role per user + serialised caps for each role loaded once in memory, simple and do-able with the current layout
12:24 AM ddebernardy
or shall we stick to 8663?
12:24 AM photomatt
ddebernardy: to your earlier point of discussion, in many years of doing this I have seen zero correlation between a longer release cycle and more stable product
12:24 AM
in fact it seems to be the opposite
12:24 AM MarkJaquith
DD32: that would be my choice.
12:25 AM ddebernardy
DD32 - there's a half dozen tickets related to roles/caps
12:25 AM bi0xid
photomatt: people relax when having more time :P
12:25 AM MarkJaquith
Simple, no new tables. And we can totally handle upgrades without changing anyone's caps.
12:25 AM photomatt
so about 3 per year seems to be the best balance of plenty of room for testing and getting improvements into users hands as frequently as possible
12:25 AM ddebernardy
that are related to changing the way it's managed for all sorts of reasons
12:25 AM
photomatt - 3 per year is fine, not 4 :-)
12:25 AM DD32
ddebernardy: I dont care if there is, That doesnt make much of a difference, people have troubles with the current role system, Anyone who needs extreme grain control over it, can use a plugin, just like they have to do in the first place to change the roles caps anyway
12:26 AM ddebernardy
photomatt - are you in SF next month, so we can have a beer at some point?
12:26 AM jeffr0
what is this canonical plugins i keep hearing about. I don't understand what that means
12:26 AM photomatt
I'm actually gone all of july, until the very end
12:27 AM ddebernardy
that's fine, I'll be in Merced, probably for 2-3 months
12:27 AM photomatt
an obvious improvement for roles for 2.9 could be: there is no place in the interface that says what any role does
12:27 AM ddebernardy
just let me know when you're around (ddebernardy at yahoo.com
12:27 AM photomatt
even just a listing of capabilities in a human readable form would be a nice improvement for folks
12:27 AM DD32
jeffr0: Its for those who change their permalink strucutre so damn often. Ie. /2009/09/&amp;lt;postid&amp;gt;// - gets changed to /september/2009/&amp;lt;postname&amp;gt;/ and WP remembers the old format...
12:27 AM MarkJaquith
photomatt: I'd be up for simple role management if we got the whole system to a simple caps, bucket system.
12:27 AM aaroncampbell
jeffr0: The idea would be that a specific plugin would be the "recommended" solution for a particular issue, and rather than getting 50 developers to create 50 different competing solutions, they could work together on one.
12:27 AM photomatt
some checkboxes for modifying non-admin capabilities would be icing on the cake
12:27 AM DD32
oh.. wrong thing :)
12:27 AM jeffr0
no you're speaking of canonical urls
12:27 AM
lol
12:28 AM DD32
Still too early here :P
12:28 AM aaroncampbell
Also, as mentioned, there's the possibility to get those added as part of the testing process (or even as unit tests)
12:28 AM photomatt
MarkJaquith: I think the user side should be done before any backend changes
12:28 AM
unless there's something inherit in the current structure that prevents us from moving forward
12:28 AM jeffr0
I know some plugin authors are already working behind the scenes together, collaborating together
12:28 AM
would this system help that?
12:28 AM photomatt
the consensus seems to be it's too flexible, not too little
12:29 AM ddebernardy
photomatt - there is. it prevents the likes of list authors with cap A or B to scale, for one thing
12:29 AM MarkJaquith
photomatt: yep. Too much flexibility, and it's actually constraining performance. Could do UI first, but it wouldn't support any of the soon-to-be-deprecated features.
12:29 AM aaroncampbell
jeffr0: yeah, but I think it's just an idea at this point.  it was mentioned in photomatt's state of the word in SF.
12:29 AM ddebernardy
and it prevents plugin authors from having a ready API to add memberships
12:29 AM MarkJaquith
Like multiple roles per person, or role + additional cap.
12:31 AM ddebernardy
right
12:31 AM aaroncampbell
jeffr0: I talked about it a little in part 2 of my summary of the state of the word from SF: http://wpinformer.com/state-word-wordcamp-part-2/ ...I'm not much of a writer, but it's there
12:31 AM photomatt
MarkJaquith: I think having a UI would be a good constraint for us when we want to do a rearchitect in a future version
12:32 AM
because creating the UI will force us to figure out what people actually want from it
12:32 AM
what the most popular plugins are doing with it, etc
12:32 AM
without taking out the plumbing before we have a place to pee
12:32 AM
so to speak
12:32 AM ddebernardy
photomatt - no no, the good membership plugins are ignoring wp roles altogether
12:32 AM bi0xid
Sorry guys. Off to bed. Must be awake in 5 hours to work ^_^. Will read u tomorrow.
12:32 AM ddebernardy
precisely because it's not query'able
12:32 AM bi0xid is now known as bi0xid[a]
12:33 AM aaroncampbell
MarkJaquith: just to add my two cents, I use "role + additional caps" fairly regularly, but I'm not against having to create a new role to do that.
12:33 AM photomatt
ddebernardy: point me to the plugins, I'm happy to take a look at them
12:33 AM MarkJaquith
aaroncampbell: And the upgrade could create that new role for you.
12:33 AM ddebernardy
photomatt - they're all paid for stuff, sadly
12:33 AM photomatt
then I don't care about them
12:33 AM ddebernardy
but wp wishlist, for one, is one of them
12:33 AM
and my own (yet to be released, so not very relevant) is another
12:34 AM photomatt
if people are restricted to a single role, which is totally fair, then we could put an index back into wp_users using the old user_level field (or a new one) which would make querying easy-peasy
12:34 AM ddebernardy
I plan to place mine in the wp repo
12:34 AM
and I'd ideally want the roles table revamped by then
12:34 AM aaroncampbell
MarkJaquith: true.  Another FYI, I use Role Manager (http://www.im-web-gefunden.de/wordpress-plugins/role-manager/) and I think it's pretty popular.
12:34 AM ddebernardy
else I'll just add a few more defines
12:34 AM
and db tables
12:34 AM MarkJaquith
photomatt: the only issue is that you can have different roles on different blogs, so you can't store it in the user table.
12:35 AM jeffr0
role manager is very popular
12:36 AM ddebernardy
as much as role manager is popular it still doesnt' make it possible to query users who can edit posts or pages, for instance
12:36 AM DD32
MarkJaquith: Thats the only case i see against it..  infact, integrating with other sites/setups is the only time you'd use a roll+cap or multiple roles ideally..
12:36 AM photomatt
as far as I can tell role-scoper is the most popular role plugin, and #657 overall
12:36 AM ddebernardy
and that's like.. a must have, based on teh role/caps tickets
12:36 AM MarkJaquith
DD32: I'm not talking about multiple roles on one blog. Multiple roles on multiple blogs. One role per blog.
12:36 AM photomatt
MarkJaquith: good point, so in usermeta it should say
12:37 AM
*stay
12:37 AM MarkJaquith
photomatt: but as role in plaintext only.
12:37 AM photomatt
yep
12:37 AM ddebernardy
ok, let me get this right
12:37 AM photomatt
I've always liked the approach of capabilities as a big array, which anyone could filter
12:37 AM DD32
MarkJaquith: Ah yeah slight mis-understanding there.. But yeah ok that makes sense
12:37 AM photomatt
rather than being stored in the DB as primary store after installation
12:38 AM
there's nothing in the code we can rely on any role existing, iirc
12:38 AM MarkJaquith
photomatt: you can still do that. Most of the sites I create, I hardcode roles using pre_option_* filters
12:39 AM ddebernardy
photomatt - see the performance/optimization tickets
12:39 AM
and a few template tickets
12:39 AM photomatt
yeah but when you do that you're making assumptions -- we do the same on wp.com
12:39 AM MarkJaquith
What assumptions?
12:39 AM ddebernardy
there are a few that relate to not being able to query users having a cap
12:40 AM photomatt
ddebernardy: I'm familiar with the problem. if you'd like me to look at a specific ticket, please link it
12:40 AM MarkJaquith
ddebernardy: it's roundly agreed that cap-to-user is needed. I've been honking that horn for over three years.
12:40 AM Viper007Bond has joined the channel.
12:40 AM ddebernardy
#2787
12:40 AM wp-trac-bot
ddebernardy: http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/2787 normal, normal, Future Release, markjaquith-&amp;gt;jacobsantos, new, New Method of storing and calculating cap2user and user2cap
12:40 AM ddebernardy
#2531
12:40 AM wp-trac-bot
ddebernardy: http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/2531 normal, normal, Future Release, markjaquith-&amp;gt;jacobsantos, new, Functions for registering additional capabilities and getting a list of all capabilities
12:40 AM clioweb has left IRC ()
12:40 AM photomatt
MarkJaquith: that nothing has modified in the DB. usually when I use a pre_option hook it feels like a hack
12:40 AM ddebernardy
#5942
12:40 AM wp-trac-bot
ddebernardy: http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5942 normal, normal, Future Release, tellyworth-&amp;gt;, new, Add Owner role
12:40 AM ddebernardy
#5255
12:40 AM wp-trac-bot
ddebernardy: http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5255 normal, normal, Future Release, markjaquith-&amp;gt;jacobsantos, new, Simplify role/capability for easier cap =&amp;gt; user lookups
12:40 AM ddebernardy
#5540
12:41 AM wp-trac-bot
ddebernardy: http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5540 normal, normal, Future Release, tellyworth-&amp;gt;jacobsantos, new, User roles overhaul
12:41 AM ddebernardy
#5541
12:41 AM photomatt
ddebernardy: no need for a ticket flood, feel free to filter
12:41 AM wp-trac-bot
ddebernardy: http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5541 normal, normal, Future Release, tellyworth-&amp;gt;jacobsantos, new, Refactor and simplify WP_Roles
12:41 AM MarkJaquith
photomatt: I think of it as a hedge against silly users updating things they shouldn't be.
12:41 AM photomatt
otherwise it's annoying
12:41 AM ddebernardy
need more? :-)
12:42 AM
sorry ;-)
12:42 AM photomatt
was the role system from owen? I don't remember that
12:42 AM ddebernardy
I think so, yeah
12:43 AM MarkJaquith
yes. as with the original role manager plugin.
12:43 AM photomatt
this is a pretty good summary of how I still feel 3 years later: http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/2531#comment:10
12:44 AM MarkJaquith
He over-engineered it.
12:44 AM ddebernardy
MarkJaquith - agreed, that is totally needed in my experience of role management as well
12:44 AM
photomatt - agreed, but only one one front
12:45 AM
that caps can be managed as a serialized array
12:45 AM
roles, however, should not
12:45 AM MarkJaquith
photomatt: my only objection to that remains that people adding new roles have to store them somewhere.
12:45 AM ddebernardy
if you want to allow the viewing of this or that post by members of this or that product, then you need a table
12:45 AM MarkJaquith
So why not have a canonical storage location?
12:46 AM photomatt
the pivot point to me is whether we want them to be editable in core
12:47 AM ddebernardy
and even then, the current setup introduces performance issues related to fetch all users with this or that cap, in wp
12:47 AM MarkJaquith
Without any editing, I agree. Hardcode that sucker and use IDs.
12:47 AM photomatt
if not, then new plugins with new roles would just filter the array and add them, or a "role manager" plugin would override the array with something pulled from the DB, in however it wants to store it
12:47 AM jeffr0
editable as in checkboxes and drop down menus?
12:48 AM ddebernardy
jeffr0 - yes
12:48 AM MarkJaquith
photomatt: upgrade issues sort of box us in on that... unless we want to break people's custom roles.
12:48 AM photomatt
ddebernardy: since that's not core functionality, a plugin having a new table to optimize for its use case is totally fine
12:49 AM
that's why I suggested it in alex's patch on #5540
12:49 AM wp-trac-bot
photomatt: http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5540 normal, normal, Future Release, tellyworth-&amp;gt;jacobsantos, new, User roles overhaul
12:49 AM ddebernardy
photomatt - I'm fine with the idea, as long as it's clear-cut and clearly defined as wontfix for the remaining tickets in WP :-)
12:50 AM
your statement prompts me to close like... about 20 or so performance related tickets as wontfix
12:50 AM photomatt
the closest it gets to core is in MU, which has to jump through hoops to get the users of a blog
12:50 AM
ddebernardy: don't jump the gun, it's a discussion
12:50 AM ddebernardy
photomatt - that's interesting
12:50 AM
define users of a blog
12:50 AM
it's all users with edit cap, no?
12:51 AM
if so, you're making my point (for 4-5 extra tables) exactly
12:51 AM JamesCollins has joined the channel.
12:51 AM MarkJaquith
it's all users with a role on that blog.
12:51 AM photomatt
any role
12:52 AM ddebernardy
so that's only a two tables -- roles, user2role
12:52 AM
role could be defined in the db, and that's no biggy
12:52 AM
until we need to fetch users with a specific cap
12:52 AM
if we need that, we also need role2cap and user2cap
12:52 AM
so two extra
12:52 AM photomatt
ddebernardy: it's being done now without additional tables, and has been for years
12:52 AM
it's just annoying
12:53 AM DD32
fetch specific: Thats simpler to just do an array filter, get the list of roles, query users based on roles
12:53 AM ddebernardy
yaya, I realize, but it coudl scale a lot better with the extra tables (and indexes)
12:53 AM DD32
scale past what? 10 roles and 50 caps?
12:53 AM ddebernardy
I'm not managing wp.com though, only you have the gory details ;-)
12:53 AM photomatt
the key in scaling is usually caching, not as much normalized data storage
12:54 AM ddebernardy
dd32: on a mu install such as wp.com we're talking hundreds of thousands of actual users
12:55 AM
photomatt - not so, even with memcached on you won't get past the bottleneck that goes, fetch all users, foreach users that has this cap add to array
12:55 AM DD32
ddebernardy: Yes, Which is why you'd optimize user fetching on roles, but actual cap -&amp;gt; user would be done as a PHP cap-&amp;gt; roles, then a SQL of roles -&amp;gt; users. Still scales very well for thousands of users if the user-&amp;gt;role part is optimized
12:55 AM MarkJaquith
ddebernardy: that's not how you'd do it...
12:55 AM
figure out which roles have the cap. Easy, done in PHP, very fast.
12:56 AM
With roles in hand, do one query on usermeta.
12:57 AM ddebernardy
MarkJaquith - until you've users who have several roles
12:58 AM MarkJaquith
ddebernardy: I was proposing dropping multi-role.
12:58 AM ddebernardy
and even then, if you've a user who has caps on top of roles, your query is erroneous ;-)
12:58 AM MarkJaquith
And I was proposing dropping caps on tops of roles.
12:58 AM
wp_user_role =&amp;gt; 'editor'
12:58 AM ddebernardy
I'm fine with both ideas and will be happy to contribute the patch, as long as it's a clear-cut decision
12:59 AM rboren
All customization done through roles.  One role per user.
12:59 AM ddebernardy
as long as we can get all of those performance tickets closed I'm happy
12:59 AM rboren
Has the benefit of simplicity.  Most priv systems are confusing as hell.
12:59 AM aaroncampbell
I need to go, but I agree with MarkJaquith ...drop the multiple roles per user, drop the added caps (make new roles instead), and keep it relatively simple (IMO)
12:59 AM ddebernardy
rboren - they sure are
1:00 AM DD32
and mutli-blog systems would still be clear-cut, as the role for the other blogs would be different meta rows..
1:00 AM ddebernardy
ok
1:00 AM
so are we all agreeing with dropping multi-roles and user caps?
1:00 AM rboren
Seems like.
1:00 AM ddebernardy
photomatt?
1:01 AM photomatt
rboren: I like that
1:01 AM ddebernardy
ok
1:01 AM
let's do that
1:01 AM rboren
Makes code and queries much simpler.  And UI could be pretty simple too.
1:01 AM DD32
Before making a rush to close all those tickets though, Just think it over and open a new ticket based on that idea, see the reaction, and then close the non-needed stuff.....?
1:01 AM photomatt
MU is handled by the prefix
1:01 AM
DD32: makes sense
1:01 AM rboren
DD32: Mark and I have a ticket where we debated this very thing somewhere.
1:01 AM photomatt
rboren: what would the compatability implications be?
1:02 AM rboren
For stock WP, no problem. For those who use role manager, could be some headaches.
1:02 AM MarkJaquith
I really think it can be handled in upgrade.
1:02 AM rboren
Might need something to translate multiple roles + caps into new roles.
1:02 AM MarkJaquith
rboren: yep.
1:03 AM
If a role doesn't exist with those exact GRANT capabilities, we create one.
1:03 AM photomatt
do any plugins enable multiple roles?
1:03 AM
on a single blog
1:03 AM ddebernardy
#10201
1:03 AM MarkJaquith
I've never seen it.
1:03 AM wp-trac-bot
ddebernardy: http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10201 normal, normal, 2.9, Denis-de-Bernardy-&amp;gt;, new, Switch roles to use single role, and no user-specific caps
1:03 AM rboren
Haven't look at role manager forever. Is it even maintained any more?
1:03 AM MarkJaquith
rboren: by someone else, I believe.
1:04 AM ddebernardy
rboren - it is, but not very well
1:04 AM
photomatt - yes, membership plugins
1:04 AM DD32
Alright, 9am, better get to work. - Someone save a chanlog and post it up later please? (If theres anything else further said)
1:04 AM ddebernardy
we're absolutely guaranteed to break all of the poorly written ones if we implement this
1:05 AM rboren
Off to the airport. Dropping off the wife. Later all.
1:05 AM ruslany has joined the channel.
1:05 AM ddebernardy
by poorly written ones, I'm meaning those that are sub-optimal from a db performance standpoint
1:06 AM
DD32: will add a big copy of the discussion in 10201
1:06 AM jeffr0
heh
1:06 AM ddebernardy
I actually like this idea
1:07 AM
it means membership plugins need to manage their own multi-role tables
1:07 AM
and that is good
1:07 AM
because roles and memberships are different animals
1:07 AM MarkJaquith
Yay. Three years and I finally got consensus on this! :-D
1:07 AM ddebernardy
:-)
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #8589 (Bulk Upgrade Plugins) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>dd32</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 23:12:37 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8589#comment:17</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8589#comment:17/1245280357000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Here's how I think it could be implemented without requiring javascript and without reaching any resource limit:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Sounds good to me.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The other option is for UI like:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt; Upgrading Plugin 1  / 4
----------------------
..Usual Plugin upgrade stuff....
----------------------
 Continue with next plugin (Hidden usually, just for non-js compat)
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
with the ---- section being in an iframe... its an option... But i like your idea more i think.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10200 (Cron not running) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>hailin</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 23:07:11 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10200#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10200#comment:2/1245280031000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
This is maybe a result of options cache stomping on each other.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In my debugging, I've noticed that options cache (cron) is seriously out of sync with the corresponding db records, especially when the user shedules multiple future posts within a few minutes. But it does seem to be caused by some changes in 2.8, because I saw this issue resurfaced again in the past several days.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10133 (Dashboard feeds not loading) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>hallsofmontezuma</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 23:04:35 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10133#comment:7</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10133#comment:7/1245279875000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Cc&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Check the PHP memory for the process.  I've noticed on some servers it asking for a ton of memory when loading simplepie.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10201 (Remove user-specific caps) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 23:02:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10201</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10201/1245279756000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
See IRC discussions from June 18th 2009
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The current role system is rather complicated, But has a lot of flexibility
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A lot of the flexibility isn't even used by most (ie. the ability to have a user with a Roll + a single capability)
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The role system starts having trouble with a high number of users
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;To look up every user with a certain cap. it requires loading all the users, and then checking individually.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The proposed changes are:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;That we reduce the complex system to something much more simple:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Roles are retained: 1 role per meta entry, and since the meta API allows for multiple values for the same key, this would have the benefit of multiple roles, and direct lookups.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;However:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Remove the ability for a user to be part of a Role, and have an extra capability added on top of that.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;This has the ability to significantly increase performance, As now:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Looking up users with a specific cap is easy:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Filter the role list for roles with that cap
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;SQL the usermeta table for users in those roles
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Select those users (if needed, else return the ID's)
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;An upgrade path is available which doesnt require extra tables, and reduces the ammount of serialization
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The other option is a whole new set of tables.. which.. those who are sane (And there are some insane people in WP Dev..) realise that its not really needed.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fine grain control has never been possible from WP without a plugin, Nothing would change here, If a user wants fine grained control over permissions, They'd still have to run a plugin, Its just that that plugin may have to do more heavy lifting now -- since wordpress's API/role system would be simpler and not support the extra fangledangles.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #8589 (Bulk Upgrade Plugins) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>scribu</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 22:50:27 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8589#comment:16</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8589#comment:16/1245279027000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Cc&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #8589 (Bulk Upgrade Plugins) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>scribu</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 22:49:05 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8589#comment:15</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8589#comment:15/1245278945000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Oups... bad formatting. Here's the readable list:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;User chooses multiple plugins for upgrade.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;ol start="2"&gt;&lt;li&gt;Store the plugins to be upgraded in an option (maybe use set_transient()).
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;ol start="3"&gt;&lt;li&gt;For each plugin, do the normal upgrade.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;ol start="4"&gt;&lt;li&gt;If all went well, do a JS redirect to the next plugin, or show a "Continue..." button.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;
4*. If there was an error, show a "Continue upgrading other plugins?" button.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #8589 (Bulk Upgrade Plugins) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>scribu</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 22:48:11 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8589#comment:14</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8589#comment:14/1245278891000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8589#comment:3" title="Comment 3"&gt;ydekproductions&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
What if we set up a queue in the session for what updates need upgraded.  When one is complete, it refreshes the update page, the next item in the queue is handled.  Error or not, it just automatically goes through the requests and makes it happen.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Here's how I think it could be implemented without requiring javascript and without reaching any resource limit:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;User chooses multiple plugins for upgrade.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Store the plugins to be upgraded in an option (maybe use set_transient()).
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;For each plugin, do the normal upgrade.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If all went well, do a JS redirect to the next plugin, or show a "Continue..." button.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;
4*. If there was an error, show a "Continue upgrading other plugins?" button.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10010 (Pings and Trackbacks are not working) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>dd32</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 22:32:28 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10010#comment:45</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10010#comment:45/1245277948000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Pings are different from trackbacks. Cron doesn't have to run..
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Pings/Trackbacks both run via Cron dont they? I think that changed in a recent version.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #8910 (Limit the RSS widget from using its own url) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 22:31:09 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8910#comment:7</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8910#comment:7/1245277869000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Milestone&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #8663 (Allow customizing capabilities prefix through wp-config.php) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>aaroncampbell</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 22:25:35 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8663#comment:8</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8663#comment:8/1245277535000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Cc&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #2531 (Functions for registering additional capabilities and getting a list ...) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>aaroncampbell</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 22:23:55 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/2531#comment:25</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/2531#comment:25/1245277435000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Cc&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #8910 (Limit the RSS widget from using its own url) reopened</title>
      
        <dc:creator>casabsolute</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 22:14:33 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8910#comment:6</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8910#comment:6/1245276873000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Apologies - Reopening because we had a major server issue/database corruption related directly to this bug and was told at the Wordpress MU forums that this is a Wordpress issue, not strictly MU.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Check this post here for further info - &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://mu.wordpress.org/forums/topic/9431?replies=8#post-76328"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://mu.wordpress.org/forums/topic/9431?replies=8#post-76328&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Our server was getting slammed with GET / HTTP/1.0 requests over and over and over - several per second - rampant unneccessary usage of CPU cycles.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
We finally tracked the issue down to the built-in RSS widget -
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If blog address = &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://myblog.funblog.com"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://myblog.funblog.com&lt;/a&gt; and feed is at = &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://myblog.funblog.com/feed"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://myblog.funblog.com/feed&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If using the RSS widget to display the most recent posts from the blog it is activated on, user MUST input the feed address "EXACTLY" as above.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Adding a trailing slash - such as = &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://myblog.funblog.com/feed/"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://myblog.funblog.com/feed/&lt;/a&gt; - OR - not adding /feed - such as = &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://myblog.funblog.com"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://myblog.funblog.com&lt;/a&gt; - inside the widget causes the server to go into an infinite loop when someone brings up that blog in their browser window.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In our case, it also corrupted database tables and filled the server logs/space on the server until it was tracked down and resolved.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Possible resolutions -
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha"&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add a check into the built-in RSS widget to not allow invalid URLs (those with a trailing slash or without /feed at the end).
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;ol class="loweralpha" start="2"&gt;&lt;li&gt;Make it clearer (stupid-proof) that the built-in RSS widget is to be used for OUTSIDE feeds, and that the Archive widget can be used to display Recent Posts from the blog you are adding it to (same end product the user is probably looking for in reaching for the RSS widget first, but doesn't realize it's just that easy and is over-thinking it).
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
      <category>reopenedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #4967 (Obsolete the RSS 0.92 feed) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>aaroncampbell</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 22:06:28 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/4967#comment:26</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/4967#comment:26/1245276388000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Cc&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #4967 (Obsolete the RSS 0.92 feed) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 22:05:34 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/4967#comment:25</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/4967#comment:25/1245276334000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
said westi:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;ddebernardy: I am happy to drop them if we have all the hooks in place (I think we do) to allow a plugin to bring them back
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
said rboren:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;Worth considering for 2.9 , I reckon.  Not something that gets me worked up either way.
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #4967 (Obsolete the RSS 0.92 feed) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 22:04:57 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/4967#comment:24</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/4967#comment:24/1245276297000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
said Mark:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;ddebernardy: I'm finally leaning towards yes on dropping those old formats. The argument was that it wasn't hurting anything. But if we have to expend effort fixing them...
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #9959 (wp_rel_nofollow_callback adds too many rel/nofollow attributes) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>aaroncampbell</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 21:25:22 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/9959#comment:11</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/9959#comment:11/1245273922000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Cc&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #9959 (wp_rel_nofollow_callback adds too many rel/nofollow attributes) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 21:21:49 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/9959#comment:10</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/9959#comment:10/1245273709000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
per IRC discussion, there also is a separate issue. unless I'm mistaking, it's possible to add a link in a comment without nofollow, as such:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;&amp;lt;a
href="url"&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10199 (the_author_meta('user_url'); links to post, not users website) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 21:04:28 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10199#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10199#comment:3/1245272668000000</guid>
      <description>worksforme: &lt;p&gt;
please disable all plugins and make sure it's still occurring then
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10199 (the_author_meta('user_url'); links to post, not users website) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 21:01:54 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10199#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10199#comment:2/1245272514000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Component&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10200 (Cron not running) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>azaozz</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 20:51:08 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10200#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10200#comment:1/1245271868000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Priority&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Severity&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
There are some changes to wp-cron in 2.8, see &lt;a class="changeset" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/10521" title="Cron spawning improvement, see #9005"&gt;[10521]&lt;/a&gt;. Use the native cron if available or try adding
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;define('ALTERNATE_WP_CRON', true);
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
to wp-config.php.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10200 (Cron not running) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>firmdot</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 20:40:47 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10200</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10200/1245271247000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Since upgrading to 2.7 and now 2.8 we're unable to schedule posts. The error is missed schedule.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There are a number of people having this issue too, check page 3 for the most recent reports:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://wordpress.org/support/topic/221086/page/3"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://wordpress.org/support/topic/221086/page/3&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #7835 (Change text in discussion settings for email notifications) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 20:35:49 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/7835#comment:7</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/7835#comment:7/1245270949000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Milestone&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #6379 (Image Insert section is confusing, not properly separated from Image ...) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>janeforshort</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 20:15:39 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/6379#comment:6</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/6379#comment:6/1245269739000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Type&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Will be redoing the upload UI for 2.9. Will keep this ticket open as an enhancement to make sure we cover the issue in redesign.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #7835 (Change text in discussion settings for email notifications) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>janeforshort</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 20:12:31 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/7835#comment:6</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/7835#comment:6/1245269551000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Type&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Summary&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
These email settings (and the wording) are still there in 2.8. Planning to look at settings in-depth for 2.9/3.0 including personal options vs blog options, so changing this ticket to make simple text change in 2.8.1, and we will address the bigger problem in 2.9.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Change "Email me" to "Email blog admin" if that is still the functionality that is triggered.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5183 (General Meta-Data Table) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 20:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5183#comment:17</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5183#comment:17/1245269280000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Milestone&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10195 (Unable to update plugins using automatic update over SSH2 since ...) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 20:07:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10195#comment:6</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10195#comment:6/1245269256000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Milestone&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10199 (the_author_meta('user_url'); links to post, not users website) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 20:06:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10199#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10199#comment:1/1245269212000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Severity&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Milestone&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10198 (get_option( 'siteurl' ) should return https in some cases) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 20:06:23 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10198#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10198#comment:2/1245269183000000</guid>
      <description>invalid</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #8589 (Bulk Upgrade Plugins) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 20:05:30 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8589#comment:13</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8589#comment:13/1245269130000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
see &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10197" title="#10197: feature request: Upgrade more than one plugin at once (closed: duplicate)"&gt;#10197&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
WP 2.8 introduced separate views for plugins, including Upgrade Available.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
On this screen, it makes sense to be able to select multiple plugins and upgrade them all at once.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Currently, &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://www.prelovac.com/vladimir/wordpress-plugins/plugin-central"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;Plugin Central&lt;/a&gt; does this using iframes.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10197 (Upgrade more than one plugin at once) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 20:04:55 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10197#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10197#comment:2/1245269095000000</guid>
      <description>duplicate: &lt;p&gt;
see &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8589" title="#8589: enhancement: Bulk Upgrade Plugins (closed: duplicate)"&gt;#8589&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10196 (Receive 2 moderate email or 2 notify comments email) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 20:01:24 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10196#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10196#comment:1/1245268884000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Milestone&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
steps to reproduce?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10191 (WordPress not determining if a request is a 404) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>sivel</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 19:54:18 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10191#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10191#comment:2/1245268458000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Cc&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Changeset [11594]: Bump</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 19:51:34 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11594</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11594/1245268294325608</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Bump
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>changeset</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Changeset [11593]: More menu fixes</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 19:51:09 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11593</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11593/1245268269790198</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
More menu fixes
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>changeset</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Changeset [11592]: More menu fixes</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 19:50:38 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11592</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11592/1245268238527633</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
More menu fixes
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>changeset</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10010 (Pings and Trackbacks are not working) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>jmulley</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 19:45:20 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10010#comment:44</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10010#comment:44/1245267920000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Pings are different from trackbacks. Cron doesn't have to run..
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10199 (the_author_meta('user_url'); links to post, not users website) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>jmulley</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 19:39:32 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10199</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10199/1245267572000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
The code,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;&amp;lt;?php the_author_meta('user_url'); ?&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
links to the post, not the users website. any idea how to fix it?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>9927.3.patch attached to Ticket #9927</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ramiy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 19:27:28 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/9927/9927.3.patch</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/9927/9927.3.patch/1245266848000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
sorry, here is the latest
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>9927.2.patch attached to Ticket #9927</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ramiy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 19:25:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/9927/9927.2.patch</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/9927/9927.2.patch/1245266746000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
ver.2
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10190 (Plugin Dependency Class API) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 19:25:09 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10190#comment:7</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10190#comment:7/1245266709000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
@mike: If any, my main point is that this depend should be in a readme file. If a plugin has known depends, we'd want to add a Depends: field, either in the plugin's file or in its readme file, and have WP refuse to install the plugin (or automatically install and activate its depends) if the depends are not present.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
That plugins aren't all hosted on wp.org should not be a valid argument. It's very possible to look at the plugin/readme headers from within WP before activating.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10198 (get_option( 'siteurl' ) should return https in some cases) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 19:17:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10198#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10198#comment:1/1245266256000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Use the site_url() function.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #6352 (Tabindex bugs in trunk) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 19:17:09 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/6352#comment:8</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/6352#comment:8/1245266229000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/6352#comment:7" title="Comment 7"&gt;Elpie&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But, really, maintenance would be a whole heap easier if tabindexes were removed and attention paid to a logical document order. I find that even without any changes, I can get around the backend very quickly by keyboard, as long as I have first deleted all tabindexes.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
please attach the patch
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5598 (Ctrl+S autosave for new posts) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 19:14:35 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5598#comment:4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5598#comment:4/1245266075000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10108 (Invalid HTML in get_search_form()) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 19:12:37 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10108#comment:5</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10108#comment:5/1245265957000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Attached patch drops it all on the front end. please close the ticket if we're not interested.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>10108.diff attached to Ticket #10108</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 19:12:01 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10108/10108.diff</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10108/10108.diff/1245265921000000</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10198 (get_option( 'siteurl' ) should return https in some cases) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>dawning</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 19:10:41 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10198</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10198/1245265841000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id="TheIssue"&gt;The Issue&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
When I load up wp-admin under https, I notice in the html source returned, that there are several references to content on my site that are not referenced as https, but rather as http. I believe this bug stems from &lt;em&gt;get_option( 'siteurl' )&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="SomeEvidence"&gt;Some Evidence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In one case, the foliopress wysiwyg plugin, the plugin fails to render at all and it seems the offender is a call to &lt;em&gt;get_option( 'siteurl')&lt;/em&gt; returning &lt;em&gt;&lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://&lt;/a&gt;&amp;lt;correct stuff&amp;gt;&lt;/em&gt; rather than &lt;em&gt;&lt;a class="ext-link" href="https://"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;https://&lt;/a&gt;&amp;lt;correct stuff&amp;gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Reproduction"&gt;Reproduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I've seen this occur under a few circumstances. Here's some steps to reproduce one of them.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Steps"&gt;Steps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Set &lt;em&gt;define ('FORCE_SSL_ADMIN', true);&lt;/em&gt; in wp_config.php
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://foliovision.com/downloads/foliopress-wysiwyg-0.91.zip"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;Foliopress Wysiwyg&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Enable Foliopress &amp;amp; attempt to edit a page (should be forced to connect under https).
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3 id="Result"&gt;Result&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You'll find the WYSIWYG won't appear. If you look at the page source, you'll see references to it's components are pointing to &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://&lt;/a&gt; addresses. This can be traced back to line 167 of &lt;em&gt;foliopress-wysiwyg-class.php&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="OtherReproductions"&gt;Other Reproductions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I've had this occur without the forced ssl admin directive in wp-admin.php. I find if I just point my browser to the https url of my site, the same effect occurs.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="OtherComments"&gt;Other Comments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I've tested this both on Windows (running &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://www.wampserver.com/en/"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;WAMP&lt;/a&gt;) and on Linux (running Ubuntu/LAMP). Of course that shouldn't make a difference, and it doesn't. The behavior remains in both cases.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Severity"&gt;Severity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
For me this is nearly a blocker level severity, which is why I'm declaring it as "major".
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="SimilarTicket"&gt;Similar Ticket&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10198#9008" title="#10198: defect (bug): get_option( 'siteurl' ) should return https in some cases (closed: invalid)"&gt;#9008&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10190 (Plugin Dependency Class API) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>mikeschinkel</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 18:55:28 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10190#comment:6</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10190#comment:6/1245264928000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
While I'm not ready to support inclusion of this specific patch as I'm having a discussion about doing something similar but more involved on wp-hackers I'd like to ask Denis-de-Bernardy why he thinks it better to depend on often inexperienced plugin authors to do version checking when much of it can be done in the core?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Moving to the core increases consistency and robustness for the end user (who blames WordPress not the plugin when things go wrong) and doing so in the core allows for hooks to be defined for plugin authors to augment or override dependency determination thus making it more obvious to a plugin authors that they need to do dependency checking and also how to do it.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10190 (Plugin Dependency Class API) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ShaneF</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 18:13:26 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10190#comment:5</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10190#comment:5/1245262406000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10190#comment:1" title="Comment 1"&gt;Denis-de-Bernardy&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As much as I like the idea, I think this should be dealt with by the plugins themselves, or internally over in wordpress.org (using the readme files).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Not all plugins are released via WordPress.org.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5120 (_wp_unfiltered_html_comment breaks XHTML validity) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Elpie</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 17:23:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5120#comment:18</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5120#comment:18/1245259430000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Milestone&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>default-theme-comments.diff attached to Ticket #5120</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Elpie</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 17:17:12 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/5120/default-theme-comments.diff</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/5120/default-theme-comments.diff/1245259032000000</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>classic-theme-comments-patch.diff attached to Ticket #5120</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Elpie</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 17:16:47 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/5120/classic-theme-comments-patch.diff</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/5120/classic-theme-comments-patch.diff/1245259007000000</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5120 (_wp_unfiltered_html_comment breaks XHTML validity) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Elpie</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 17:07:34 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5120#comment:17</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5120#comment:17/1245258454000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I'm sorry, but I fail to see why this was closed again. This bug still exists, its not a new bug, and its easy enough to fix.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There are two issues here - theme developers not placing the do_action inside a block level element. This should be documented in the Codex for reference and the default themes updated.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The second issue is that the core uses XML ID syntax in three files (apart from the themes): comment-template.php, admin-ajax.php and wp-comments-post.php.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
_wp_unfiltered_html_comment needs to be changed to an ID that starts with a letter. Would renaming this to wp_unfiltered_html_comment cause any issues?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Fixing both these will allow frontend themes to render as valid XHTML.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I will add the diffs for the default themes shortly. Once I have tested the ID changes I will add patches for those too.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5120 (_wp_unfiltered_html_comment breaks XHTML validity) reopened</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Elpie</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 17:05:49 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5120#comment:16</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5120#comment:16/1245258349000000</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>reopenedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5120 (_wp_unfiltered_html_comment breaks XHTML validity) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>mrmist</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 16:41:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5120#comment:15</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5120#comment:15/1245256910000000</guid>
      <description>invalid: &lt;p&gt;
It was closed for the reason guillep2k said -
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Sorry: this is in fact a new bug. I am reclosing this and opening a new one.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #6352 (Tabindex bugs in trunk) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Elpie</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 16:20:37 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/6352#comment:7</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/6352#comment:7/1245255637000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/6352#comment:6" title="Comment 6"&gt;Denis-de-Bernardy&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
anyone who develops an admin theme has a heck of a job working around the limitations of the core tabindexes
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It's not that nasty, actually. It merely needs some docs...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I just hack the core ;)
But seriously, even the tabindex in the default themes is problematic. Have you ever tried to navigate from the frontend? As soon as you load a page/post that has comments enabled, the first tab you do drops you straight down to the comment form. This completely breaks the document flow and throws users in places they don't expect to be.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The tabindex in the backend is unnecessary as long as the document is ordered. If they absolutely MUST stay, here's what I would do to improve them...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Rename the files so the UI names match the file names - they don't currently, which is confusing. This is important, particularly to keyboard users who can see what appear to be strange locations displaying in their browser bars.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Make sure there is a tabindex for every link in the logical flow of the document - otherwise users get taken from tab to tab, then to the non-indexed links afterwards, which is not necessarily the same document flow that mouse users get.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But, really, maintenance would be a whole heap easier if tabindexes were removed and attention paid to a logical document order. I find that even without any changes, I can get around the backend very quickly by keyboard, as long as I have first deleted all tabindexes.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Someone else want to test this and chime in?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10031 (Rendering problem with larr/rarr entities) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Elpie</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 16:09:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10031#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10031#comment:2/1245254992000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Cc&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It's a font rendering bug. IE8 has a couple as well (cannot render some glyphs in certain fonts. &amp;amp;bull; is one that comes to mind).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The problem with using laquo/raquo is that these are quotation marks, telling screen reader users that the content inside is a quotation. They get read  « as "left double  angle quote" and » as "right double angle quote" (some assistive devices even spit out "left-pointing double angle quotation mark") which is a whole lot of mess when they are incorrectly used to create a pretty visual display.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Far better (IMO) to leave WP alone and hope the browser bugs are sorted quickly.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10108 (Invalid HTML in get_search_form()) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Elpie</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 15:51:19 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10108#comment:4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10108#comment:4/1245253879000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Cc&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10108#comment:2" title="Comment 2"&gt;ryan&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Those are WAI-ARIA landmark roles, which always generate debate. :-) See &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/9408" title="#9408: enhancement: WAI-ARIA landmark roles in default theme to increase accessibility (closed: fixed)"&gt;#9408&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You know, WordPress uses so much JavaScript that adding roles through js would work, while also satisfying those who want to output validating X/HTML.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I've been using this successfully for awhile:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;
function setRoleAttribute(id, rolevalue) {
	if(document.getElementById(id)) {
		document.getElementById(id).setAttribute("role", rolevalue);
	}
}
function setAriaRoleElementsById() {
	//Add all Id:s and aria roles here
	setRoleAttribute("header", "banner");
	setRoleAttribute("content", "main");
	setRoleAttribute("sidebar", "complementary");
	setRoleAttribute("footer", "contentinfo");
	setRoleAttribute("menu", "navigation");
	setRoleAttribute("searchform", "search");
}
window.onload=function(){ setAriaRoleElementsById(); }
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It's accessible to assistive devices and browsers. The roles are not output if JavaScript is off, but if its off WAI-ARIA roles and properties are not needed either.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The other advantage of adding the roles through js is that as new roles are defined, updating the script is much easier than hunting through the code to hardcode them.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5598 (Ctrl+S autosave for new posts) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Elpie</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 15:43:13 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5598#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5598#comment:3/1245253393000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Cc&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If it was done, it doesn't work ;)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It's a really bad idea. Ctrl +S is a common browser keyboard shortcut. In Opera, Firefox and others Ctrl +S triggers a "Save page as" dialog for saving a web page locally. Overriding browser behaviour can lead to undesired results and can have a huge impact on accessibility. (Screen readers such as JAWS also use Ctrl +S for saving local copies of pages). For this reason, many people find the Gmail hotkey unusable and confusing (it also doesn't work in all browsers - just another thing to consider!)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Hotkeys in WordPress would be very useful, but they need to be hotkeys that are not already in use by browsers and assistive devices.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10197 (Upgrade more than one plugin at once) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>scribu</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 13:20:34 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10197#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10197#comment:1/1245244834000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Cc&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10197 (Upgrade more than one plugin at once) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>scribu</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 13:20:24 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10197</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10197/1245244824000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
WP 2.8 introduced separate views for plugins, including Upgrade Available.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
On this screen, it makes sense to be able to select multiple plugins and upgrade them all at once.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Currently, &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://www.prelovac.com/vladimir/wordpress-plugins/plugin-central"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;Plugin Central&lt;/a&gt; does this using iframes.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10195 (Unable to update plugins using automatic update over SSH2 since ...) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>rmckern</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 12:38:21 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10195#comment:5</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10195#comment:5/1245242301000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I'm not bashful. It's available at &lt;a class="ext-link" href="https://secure.orangefort.com/util/phpinfo.php"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;https://secure.orangefort.com/util/phpinfo.php&lt;/a&gt;.
I'm assuming that'd be this part, listed here:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;Registered PHP Streams	php, file, data, http, ftp, compress.bzip2, compress.zlib, https, ftps, ssh2.shell, ssh2.exec, ssh2.tunnel, ssh2.scp, ssh2.sftp, zip
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Please let me know if you're seeing something off. I did build and install ssh2 from PECL, and I tried reinstalling it when things blew up (to no avail).
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #9568 (Allow users to log in using their email address) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 11:06:05 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/9568#comment:33</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/9568#comment:33/1245236765000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Sometimes, you need to register users without prompting them to enter a username. When importing data from a separate application, for instance. How about I change it as follows:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Require the username on signup
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If username = email, allow user to edit it and refuse to save until he picks one
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Once username &amp;lt;&amp;gt; email, refuse to edit username
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;
That way, we'd have the best of both worlds. Thoughts?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #8553 (preg_replace_callback in do_shortcode returns empty for large posts) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 10:54:48 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8553#comment:36</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8553#comment:36/1245236088000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Adding a /x param to make things more readable... The current one is:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;"/
(.?)                # optionally catch an extra bracket used to escape shortcode
\[($tagregexp)\b    # begin shortcode
  (.*?)             # optional attributes (non-greedy, stops on close bracket)
  (?:(\/))?         # optional slash to indicate a closing tag, not always set
  \]                # closing bracket
(?:                 # optional content and closing shortcode
  (.+?)             # the content
  \[\/\2\]          # close shortcode with a back reference
)?
(.?)                # optionally catch an extra bracket used to escape shortcode
/x"
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
you're suggesting:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;"/
(.?)                # optionally catch an extra bracket used to escape shortcode
\[($tagregexp)\b    # begin shortcode
  ([^\]]*?)         # optional attributes (non-greedy), equivalent to using a dot
  (\/)?             # optional slash to indicate a closing tag, always set
  \]                # closing bracket
(?:                 # optional content and closing shortcode
  (.+?)             # the content
  \[\/\2\]          # close shortcode with a back reference
)?
(.?)                # optionally catch an extra bracket used to escape shortcode
/x"
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
the suggestion in &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/9264" title="#9264: defect (bug): Self closing shortcodes (closed: fixed)"&gt;#9264&lt;/a&gt; is the following:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;"/
(.?)                # optionally catch an extra bracket used to escape shortcode
\[($tagregexp)\b    # begin shortcode
  (.*?)             # optional attributes (non-greedy, stops on close bracket)
  (?:(\/))?         # optional slash to indicate a closing tag, not always set
  \]                # closing bracket
(
  ?(4)              # stop if we already have 4 back references
                    # it would mean we've a slash bracket
  |                 # else
  (?:               # optional content and closing shortcode
    (.+?)           # the content
    \[\/\2\]        # close shortcode with a back reference
  )?
)?
(.?)                # optionally catch an extra bracket used to escape shortcode
/x"
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A few notes:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Using your patch would remove the possibility for the optimization in &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/9264" title="#9264: defect (bug): Self closing shortcodes (closed: fixed)"&gt;#9264&lt;/a&gt; (since we'd always have.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Your attribute-related regex might be a bit more efficient from a performance standpoint.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Personally, I was hoping that the optimization in the other ticket would allow you to do [foo/] in order to optimize your way through the mess.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
All of these patches, however, leave a few fundamental issues behind:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Something like [foo[bar] get treated as a foo shortcode with [bar as an attribute
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;ol start="2"&gt;&lt;li&gt;We can get brackets in a shortcode's content, which can potentially lead to nested shortcodes:
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;[foo]bar[][/foo]
[foo][bar/][/foo]
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;ol start="3"&gt;&lt;li&gt;A non-closed shortcode can gobble up an entire document before the regex bails and decides that it has no closing shortcode:
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;[foo]
long document that runs into the backtrack limit starts here
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
It's the two last points which I believe are troubling. I take it that some users actually want brackets in shortcodes, so fixing point 2 probably isn't an option. Bailing after, say, 1000 characters after the start of the content might be a good bet.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Would you mind attaching your post's source in a text file, exactly as it is in the WP editor, and specify the plugins you're using?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10196 (Receive 2 moderate email or 2 notify comments email) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>bolsolution</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 10:43:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10196</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10196/1245235416000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Hola,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I having a wordpress blog with version 2.7.1.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In my blog configuration, when some body post comments..My Blog system will sent me 1 notify email...But i found out that the blog admin have sent me 2 email at the same time....
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Thx.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10186 (Add global $server_version) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 10:11:20 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10186#comment:8</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10186#comment:8/1245233480000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Forgot to change $is_iis7 just now..
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>10186.patch attached to Ticket #10186</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 10:10:48 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10186/10186.patch</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10186/10186.patch/1245233448000000</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10127 (User roles not translated) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>pavelevap</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 10:01:02 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10127#comment:4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10127#comment:4/1245232862000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
And on this websites there is also problem with Timezone selection - there is nothing to select and page ends after this selection, so it is not possible to Update changes, because there is no button.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10187 (wp_redirect and canonical redirect do not work as expected on IIS) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 10:00:20 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10187#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10187#comment:2/1245232820000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Patch updated due to &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10186" title="#10186: enhancement: Add global $server_version (closed: wontfix)"&gt;#10186&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>10187.patch attached to Ticket #10187</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 09:59:55 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10187/10187.patch</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10187/10187.patch/1245232795000000</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10127 (User roles not translated) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>pavelevap</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 09:54:30 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10127#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10127#comment:3/1245232470000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Cc&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Also on some websites (PHP 5.2.9), after using Czech version, only "Right Now" widget is loaded and then nothing (only many Javascript errors in Firefox console). After deactivating Czech version everything works well...
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10186 (Add global $server_version) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 09:52:44 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10186#comment:7</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10186#comment:7/1245232364000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Summary&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I have uploaded a new patch that generates $server_version instead of $iis_version.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10186 (Add global $server_version) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>dd32</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 09:14:21 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10186#comment:6</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10186#comment:6/1245230061000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
If it was a problem, Introducing a new variable for it for future..
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;$apache = apache_version();
$iis = iis_version();
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
leaving $is_... alone for back compat
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10186 (Add global $server_version) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>dd32</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 09:12:39 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10186#comment:5</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10186#comment:5/1245229959000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
What do you think?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I think its possible. However, a point that we dont need to worry about.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;$version = 10.4;
var_dump( $version == true );
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h1 id="true"&gt;true&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
PHP will evaluate anything non-false/null/zero to be true in the above example.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
(Of course, $version === true would be false, But thats going to be rarely used, a triple check along with a true.. most people are just going to do &lt;code&gt;if($iis)&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10186 (Add global $server_version) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 09:10:28 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10186#comment:4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10186#comment:4/1245229828000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Will break ($is_iis === true).
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10186 (Add global $server_version) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 09:07:32 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10186#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10186#comment:3/1245229652000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
However, it is possible that some fcuntion may be checking those $is_ variables as boolean. I am afraid that changing them to version numbers may break compatibility with them.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
What do you think?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10186 (Add global $server_version) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>dd32</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 08:56:23 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10186#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10186#comment:2/1245228983000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I was thinking of that for browsers as well, Ie, If Opera is &amp;gt;=  10, or IE 5 or 6.. etc..
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10186 (Add global $server_version) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>dd32</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 08:55:44 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10186#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10186#comment:1/1245228944000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
The other option, is to change the $is_* variables to the version (if known).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
ie.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;if ( test for iis )
  $is_iis = (is version known?) ? version : true;
}}
same for apache and all the others too..
{{{
if ( $is_apache )
}}}
would still work, just as long  as its non-null/non-false/non-zero
semi-crazy idea..
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10195 (Unable to update plugins using automatic update over SSH2 since ...) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>dd32</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 07:52:43 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10195#comment:4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10195#comment:4/1245225163000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Component&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Sockets are not needed at all.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Using the ssh2.sftp wrapper is much faster and efficient than using the temp file + scp send method (by as much as a half in processing time required)..
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Can you check your phpinfo to see if the ssh2.sftp wrapper is available? It should be available if you've compiled the SSH2 extension (OR at least, any recent version of it) yourself.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you could post the entire phpinfo somewhere i can see it that'd be great, you can email it if you want, WordPress @ dd32.id.au
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #9568 (Allow users to log in using their email address) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>westi</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 07:02:27 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/9568#comment:32</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/9568#comment:32/1245222147000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Not sure that making username optional is the right way to go.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It feels like it would be nicer to work like quite a few other sites do and that is required you to pick a username on signup but then let you log in with your username or your email address at a later date.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #9900 (allow larger value for thread_comments_depth_max) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>westi</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 06:56:37 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/9900#comment:12</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/9900#comment:12/1245221797000000</guid>
      <description>fixed: &lt;p&gt;
(In &lt;a class="changeset" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11591" title="Improve description of comments_per_page option. Fixes #9900 props hailin."&gt;[11591]&lt;/a&gt;) Improve description of comments_per_page option. Fixes &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/9900" title="#9900: defect (bug): allow larger value for thread_comments_depth_max (closed: fixed)"&gt;#9900&lt;/a&gt; props hailin.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Changeset [11591]: Improve description of comments_per_page option. Fixes #9900 props hailin.</title>
      
        <dc:creator>westi</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 06:56:34 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11591</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11591/1245221794729333</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Improve description of comments_per_page option. Fixes &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/9900" title="#9900: defect (bug): allow larger value for thread_comments_depth_max (closed: fixed)"&gt;#9900&lt;/a&gt; props hailin.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>changeset</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #8553 (preg_replace_callback in do_shortcode returns empty for large posts) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Brusdeylins</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 06:51:03 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8553#comment:35</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8553#comment:35/1245221463000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Hi,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Bug 9264 is NOT THE SOLUTION ! (of course, it is an other topic...)
I tested it on my long article "Yahoo Finance API"
&lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://www.brusdeylins.info/projects/yahoo-finance-api/"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://www.brusdeylins.info/projects/yahoo-finance-api/&lt;/a&gt;
(This article contains source codes with square brackets in it, you have to face this!)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In the Attachment in 9264 you are still running over the first closing bracket of the first shortcode tag: (.*?)
This don't make sence if your shortcode names should not contain any brackets... So replace the (.*?) like described above...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
About 9264:
the (\/)? allows you to use shortcode tags like [NAME/] at the beginning. And with (?:(.+?)\[\/\2\])? the closing tag is optional. So you can use tags combinations like:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;[x]...[/x]
[x/]...[/x]
[x]
[x/]
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10195 (Unable to update plugins using automatic update over SSH2 since ...) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>rmckern</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 04:28:35 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10195#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10195#comment:3/1245212915000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Sockets &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; enabled. Here's the snippet from phpinfo():
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;'./configure' '--host=i686-redhat-linux-gnu' '--build=i686-redhat-linux-gnu' '--target=i686-redhat-linux' '--enable-sockets'
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
and
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;sockets
Sockets Support	enabled
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Other suggestions?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10184 (feed_links() cannot be removed from wp_head) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 04:11:42 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10184#comment:8</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10184#comment:8/1245211902000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Thanks dd32. Your suggestion worked.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10093 (SSH2 Install note for '--enable-sockets' to be complied in PHP) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 03:35:56 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10093#comment:9</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10093#comment:9/1245209756000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
See &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10195" title="#10195: defect (bug): Unable to update plugins using automatic update over SSH2 since ... (closed: duplicate)"&gt;#10195&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10195 (Unable to update plugins using automatic update over SSH2 since ...) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 03:35:24 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10195#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10195#comment:2/1245209724000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Sorry, &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10093" title="#10093: defect (bug): SSH2 Install note for '--enable-sockets' to be complied in PHP (closed: fixed)"&gt;#10093&lt;/a&gt;, not 10189.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10195 (Unable to update plugins using automatic update over SSH2 since ...) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 03:34:48 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10195#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10195#comment:1/1245209688000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
See &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10189" title="#10189: defect (bug): [Opera] [2.81-beta] theme_editor disabled by protective layer (closed: invalid)"&gt;#10189&lt;/a&gt;. Sounds like this could be the same issue.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10195 (Unable to update plugins using automatic update over SSH2 since ...) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>rmckern</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 01:56:43 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10195</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10195/1245203803000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
After upgrading to WordPress 2.8 on an Apache 2.2/Linux/PHP 5.2.9 machine, plugin and core auto-update was broken. The error returned is:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;Unable to locate WordPress Content directory (wp-content).
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
As per standard testing, I changed permissions to various and sundry forms ranging from 775 to 777 (apache runs as a user who belongs to the group that owns all files and directories underneath the document root). That fixed nothing. I tried disabling plugins (one at a time, and then all of them) and I tried going back to a bog simple default install. I then verified that things worked perfectly under WordPress 2.7.1 with the same configuration file. I then began to dig through the wp-admin backend and the codex, and set the following in wp-config.php which should have overridden the auto-discovery and used explicit paths for wp-content and plugins:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;define('FTP_PUBKEY','/home/ryan/.ssh/some_wordpress_key.pub');
define('FTP_PRIKEY','/home/ryan/.ssh/some_wordpress_key');
define('FTP_USER','ryan');
define('FTP_PASS',''); \\ There shouldn't be a need for a password, but it doesn't make a difference with or without one for this ticket
define('FTP_HOST','127.0.0.1:22');
define('FTP_BASE', '/home/ryan/path/to/my/site/public_html/');
define('FTP_CONTENT_DIR', '/home/ryan/path/to/my/site/public_html/wp-content/');
define('FTP_PLUGIN_DIR', '/home/ryan/path/to/my/site/public_html/wp-content/plugins/');
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The overrides were picked up by the ssh filesystem module. I dug through /wp-admin/includes/class-wp-filesystem-base.php and found where the overrides are applied (line 138) and modified it to pick up the overrides for SSH as well (as part of the testing process):
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;if ( strpos($this-&amp;gt;method, 'ftp' ) || strpos($this-&amp;gt;method, 'ssh2' ) !== false )
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This let WordPress find the wp-content directory but now I'm receiving the following:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;Downloading update from http://downloads.wordpress.org/plugin/stats.1.4.zip.
Unpacking the update.
Could not copy file /home/ryan/path/to/my/site/public_html/wp-content/upgrade/stats.1.410/stats/screenshot-1.png
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I've now traced that down through /wp-admin/includes/file.php and /wp-admin/includes/class-wp-filesystem-ssh2.php to the following failing function (lines 177 through 180 of class-wp-filesystem-ssh2.php):
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;function put_contents($file, $contents, $type = '' ) {
$file = ltrim($file, '/');
return file_put_contents('ssh2.sftp://' . $this-&amp;gt;sftp_link .'/' . $file, $contents);
}
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This is markedly simpler, and more direct than it was in 2.7.1:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;function put_contents($file, $contents, $type = '' ) {
$this-&amp;gt;debug("put_contents($file);");
$tempfile = wp_tempnam( $file );
$temp = fopen($tempfile, 'w');
if ( ! $temp )
return false;
fwrite($temp, $contents);
fclose($temp);
$ret = ssh2_scp_send($this-&amp;gt;link, $tempfile, $file, $this-&amp;gt;permission);
unlink($tempfile);
return $ret;
}
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The downside to this simplicity is that it doesn't bloody work on my system.
I'm just about stumped now, and I'm ready to cry uncle. Can anyone, at all, make heads or tails of what the hell is going on?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Changeset [11590]: Fall back to wp-tinymce.js if wp-tinymce.js.gz doesn't exist</title>
      
        <dc:creator>azaozz</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 01:08:05 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11590</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11590/1245200885291538</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Fall back to wp-tinymce.js if wp-tinymce.js.gz doesn't exist
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>changeset</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Changeset [11589]: Fall back to wp-tinymce.js if wp-tinymce.js.gz doesn't exist</title>
      
        <dc:creator>azaozz</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 01:06:32 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11589</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11589/1245200792802260</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Fall back to wp-tinymce.js if wp-tinymce.js.gz doesn't exist
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>changeset</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5120 (_wp_unfiltered_html_comment breaks XHTML validity) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>igroknow</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 01:00:19 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5120#comment:14</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5120#comment:14/1245200419000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Milestone&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5120 (_wp_unfiltered_html_comment breaks XHTML validity) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>igroknow</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 00:58:43 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5120#comment:13</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5120#comment:13/1245200323000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Version&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5120 (_wp_unfiltered_html_comment breaks XHTML validity) reopened</title>
      
        <dc:creator>igroknow</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 00:57:40 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5120#comment:12</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5120#comment:12/1245200260000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Why it is closed? It's easy to resolve that problem and it is a problem.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>reopenedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10194 (Theme Editor - Can't Edit Themes - Version 2.8) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 23:56:04 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10194#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10194#comment:2/1245196564000000</guid>
      <description>duplicate: &lt;p&gt;
See &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10189" title="#10189: defect (bug): [Opera] [2.81-beta] theme_editor disabled by protective layer (closed: invalid)"&gt;#10189&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #9807 (Trac Enhancement: Add a short text at the beginning of the create ...) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 23:43:49 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/9807#comment:11</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/9807#comment:11/1245195829000000</guid>
      <description>fixed: &lt;p&gt;
I think this is fixed. Searching can be left to bug wranglers. Trac search simply sucks.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #8553 (preg_replace_callback in do_shortcode returns empty for large posts) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 23:34:48 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8553#comment:34</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8553#comment:34/1245195288000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
@Brusdeylins - please try the alternative patch over at &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/9264" title="#9264: defect (bug): Self closing shortcodes (closed: fixed)"&gt;#9264&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>sp.2.diff attached to Ticket #10147</title>
      
        <dc:creator>link92</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 23:19:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10147/sp.2.diff</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10147/sp.2.diff/1245194390000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Better patch, now including &lt;a class="changeset" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/1042" title="tweaked get_lastpostdate and get_lastpostmodified a bit for consistency
"&gt;r1042&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10194 (Theme Editor - Can't Edit Themes - Version 2.8) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>jwjkp</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 23:18:29 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10194#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10194#comment:1/1245194309000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Addition: This issue has been confirmed (by me) in Firefox, IE, and Chrome.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #8553 (preg_replace_callback in do_shortcode returns empty for large posts) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Brusdeylins</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 23:12:31 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8553#comment:33</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8553#comment:33/1245193951000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Here my modified function in shortcodes.php:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;function get_shortcode_regex() {
	global $shortcode_tags;
	$tagnames = array_keys($shortcode_tags);
	$tagregexp = join( '|', array_map('preg_quote', $tagnames) );
	//return '(.?)\[('.$tagregexp.')\b(.*?)(?:(\/))?\](?:(.+?)\[\/\2\])?(.?)';
	  return '(.?)\[('.$tagregexp.')\b([^\]]*?)(\/)?\](?:(.+?)\[\/\2\])?(.?)';
}
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #8553 (preg_replace_callback in do_shortcode returns empty for large posts) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Brusdeylins</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 23:08:40 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8553#comment:32</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8553#comment:32/1245193720000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Cc&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Priority&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Hi,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
the resolution is descibed on my website (in german):
&lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://www.brusdeylins.info/wordpress/probleme-mit-shortcodes/"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://www.brusdeylins.info/wordpress/probleme-mit-shortcodes/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The problem is in shortcodes.php in the function get_shortcode_regex().
Here the RegEx has a non-greedy part between the brackets, which should exclude the closing bracket. This would reduce the memory usage of the backtracking process in the RegEx-Engine (the reason of this problem).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
My solution for the last line of this function looks like this (WordPress 2.8):
return '(.?)\[('.$tagregexp.')\b([&lt;sup&gt;\]]*?)(\/)?\](?:(.+?)\[\/\2\])?(.?)';
&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Here I also removed the non-catching brackets around the catching brackets around the slash after the non-greedy area... Don't know why these are existed...
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10194 (Theme Editor - Can't Edit Themes - Version 2.8) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>jwjkp</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 23:08:34 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10194</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10194/1245193714000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
In version 2.8 you can no longer edit any themes in the control panel unless you hit the screen options at the top and select "disable syntax highlighting".
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I have confirmed this bug on my blog, a friends, and a fellow wordpress user at #wordpress on Freenode.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You basically can't edit because the edit box is grayed out.  The save changes button is still there however.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10190 (Plugin Dependency Class API) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>logikal16</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 22:50:12 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10190#comment:4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10190#comment:4/1245192612000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
One more... this would allow authors to choose whether to see ALL plugins, or whether to see just ACTIVE ones:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;function get_plugin_versions($status = 'active') {
    require_once(ABSPATH . '/wp-admin/includes/plugin.php');
    $plugins = array();
    $all_plugins = get_plugins();
    $active_plugins = get_option('active_plugins');
    foreach ($all_plugins as $key =&amp;gt; $attr) {
        if ('active' != $status || in_array($key, $active_plugins)) {
            $plugins[$attr['Name']] = $attr['Version'];
        }
    }
    return $plugins;
}
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10184 (feed_links() cannot be removed from wp_head) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>dd32</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 22:41:09 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10184#comment:7</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10184#comment:7/1245192069000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
@dd32: I suspect that automatic_feed_links(false) is called by the plugin first, but then the templete calls automatic_feed_links(true).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
That sounds plausable..
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
try hooking wp_head rather early and try it then:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;add_action('wp_head', 'my_function', 5);
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5183 (General Meta-Data Table) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 22:33:24 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5183#comment:16</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5183#comment:16/1245191604000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
More reference, since IRC logs are broken:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;well, I don't think there's anything about the wp_terms table structure that prevents different terms from having the same name.  that's an api issue
11:53 PM ddebernardy
no no, it's a db issue underneath
11:53 PM filosofo
The foreign key thing could be solved with another table, wp_objects
11:54 PM ddebernardy
that's even worse than our current implementation
11:54 PM
and it won't allow the foreign key
11:54 PM filosofo
?
11:55 PM ddebernardy
well, unless you're meaning wp_objects is merging posts and links (heck, why not...), it's really not a good idea, because you'd merely add an extra table in the lot that doesn't fix the foreign key constraint problem
11:56 PM filosofo
right, that's what I mean.  all objects in one table
11:56 PM ddebernardy
FWIW, I've been playing with that idea fo the past 10 years or so
11:56 PM
the only implementation I found worthy of implementing was like this:
11:56 PM
table nodes (id)
11:56 PM
table foo (id references nodes(id))
11:57 PM
that way you're working on native structures
11:57 PM
and you still have native indexes
11:57 PM
but it actually comes down to lackings in database engines
11:57 PM
because what the above really should be is:
11:57 PM
table nodes (id)
11:57 PM
table foo inherits nodes
11:58 PM
with id shared across the board
11:58 PM
you can do that with a uuid field, basically. but your meta, e.g. created, modified, etc. then needs to be redefined in each table
11:59 PM ruslany__ has left IRC ("Leaving")
11:59 PM ddebernardy
in pgsql, inherit won't enforce unique indexes. and I'm not even aware of a similar keyword in mysql
12:01 AM filosofo
I was going to say, I didn't think you could do that in MySQL.  I don't think foreign keys are supported with all mysql storage engines.
12:01 AM ddebernardy
no, they're not. only in innodb, ndb, and a few more (but not myisam)
12:02 AM rodrigo_sampaio1 has left IRC ("Leaving.")
12:02 AM ddebernardy
still, it's generally good to be able to enforce them. it means the db is well designed if you can, and I'd like to make it possible to enforce transactions in 2.9 or 3.0.
12:04 AM filosofo
what about the db structure prevents different terms from having the same name?
12:04 AM ddebernardy
UNIQUE KEY slug (slug),
12:04 AM
in wp_terms
12:04 AM filosofo
ok, missed that.  So change that.
12:05 AM ddebernardy
no no, you want more than that, really
12:05 AM
by the same token, then other fields would want to be in wp_term_taxonomy
12:05 AM
with a unique index on slug/parent/taxonomy
12:05 AM
and the term table then disappears
12:06 AM
for the sake of marking the change, I'd suggest renaming the table as wp_taxonomies, so that old plugins end up miserably failing (or then, we'd add a pseudoview to make it backwards compat)
12:07 AM
I'd be curious to have the thoughts of rboren on all of this, though
12:11 AM sorich87 has joined the channel.
12:13 AM filosofo
so how about 3 tables: terms, taxonomies, objects
12:13 AM
we could move taxonomy definition into the db
12:13 AM ddebernardy
why terms and taxonomies?
12:14 AM
if you've an index on slug, held in taxonomies, then you can join that table on itself using ( slug ) where t1.id &amp;lt;&amp;gt; t2.id, and you've the same thing as terms
12:14 AM
the ultimate difference is, with three tables, you've three joins, with two tables, you've only two :-)
12:14 AM
and when you join tax join tax join tax as I and others do in a few plugins, it can make a huge difference
12:15 AM
query optimizers are generally lost after 8-10 joins and end up using a (slow) genetic algorithm to optimize query plans
12:15 AM filosofo
ok, but wouldn't there be a performance benefit?
12:15 AM sivel[a] is now known as sivel
12:16 AM filosofo
currently, to query a taxonomy you have to do a text search on varchar
12:16 AM
with a taxonomy table, you could make that an integer
12:16 AM ddebernardy
oh, that's what you mean
12:16 AM filosofo
db size would be smaller, too
12:17 AM ddebernardy
in this case yeah, agreeing with you, but the general trend in WP is to use php arrays for this kind of stuff
12:17 AM
I mean, we're using a serialized option to store roles :D
12:18 AM filosofo
I think everyone would like to move away from that
12:18 AM
the roles, I mean
12:18 AM ddebernardy
yeah, I hope I'll find enough time to get this done in 2.9
12:19 AM
but there are still a couple of things we'll want in varchar fields even if we do that, for the same of making thing pluginable
12:19 AM
take roles, for instance
12:19 AM filosofo
so a role is taxonomy
12:19 AM ddebernardy
by the same token as the taxo table you're describing, we'd want roles and caps defined in tables with ids references in a user2role table
12:20 AM
trouble is, this makes heavy queries
12:20 AM
in practice, it's better to have an enum field to store roles, and caps
12:20 AM
enum is really an int with another name
12:20 AM
now, to make the thing extendable, we actually want a varchar in there
12:20 AM
and the same holds for taxonomies/terms
12:21 AM
whatever we do, we'll end up with a varchar field to make things extendable
12:21 AM
and end up with the thingy containing post_tag, category, link_category (and cities, countries, and whatever plugin authors want it to contain)
12:22 AM filosofo
problem with role as enum is that it doesn't allow easy custom roles, right?
12:22 AM ddebernardy
exactly
12:22 AM
hence the need for a varchar in WP, even if it performs more poorly
12:23 AM filosofo
hmm, but see what I meant before is that in your wp_taxonomies table...
12:23 AM ddebernardy
yes?
12:23 AM filosofo
you'd have to query over zillions of varchars, instead of just a few in a taxonomy table.
12:24 AM ddebernardy
no no, you'd still have a single one - to fetch post_tag, or category, or link_category, or...
12:24 AM
picture it as the current term_taxonomy and terms combined
12:24 AM filosofo
right, if we combine present terms and taxonomy....
12:25 AM ddebernardy
and renamed for the sake of making things backwards compatible (we'd make subqueries or views available for plugins that dig straight into it)
12:25 AM filosofo
then if we want to query for the "post_tag" "my term", we have to query over the large terms table looking for "post_tag"
12:26 AM ddebernardy
it would contain the same number of rows as the current term_taxonomy table
12:26 AM
it would merely have a few extra fields to play with, avoiding a join, and adding for the possibility of extra indexes
12:26 AM filosofo
yes, that's why I think we need a taxonomy table.
12:27 AM ddebernardy
issue with a taxonomy table (as you're thinking, referencing what really ends up being an array in WP, or so I'm understanding), has to do with the register_taxonomy function
12:27 AM
I suspect
12:28 AM filosofo
just make register_taxonomy like add_rewrite_rule
12:28 AM
a one-time thing
12:28 AM ddebernardy
works too, but we end up breaking plugins in the process, if terms becomes a different animal
12:29 AM
filosofo
And this would improve the query_posts queries,
12:30 AM
because you could do one query
12:31 AM ddebernardy
correct
12:31 AM
hence the need for rboren feedback
12:31 AM
I mean, I'd be all +1 to break existing plugins and change the semantics of wp_terms
12:32 AM
but one of the core devs may end up wanting to keep backwards compat
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10167 (red box when creating new items such as category, tag, meta data) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 22:01:10 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10167#comment:9</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10167#comment:9/1245189670000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
@vachi: please post steps to reproduce.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5183 (General Meta-Data Table) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 22:00:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5183#comment:15</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5183#comment:15/1245189636000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Keeping more reference material:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;filosofo
ddebernardy, that would be a regression.  the taxonomy system is one of the best parts of wp, because of its abstractness.
11:48 PM ddebernardy
I'd vote for it being one fo the worst parts, myself
11:48 PM filosofo
why?
11:48 PM ddebernardy
well, for one thing, the current implementation has a shared terms table
11:49 PM
which prevents a category and a tag with the same slug from having the a different name (with/without cap)
11:49 PM
then, there is the wp_term_relationships table
11:49 PM
which contains cats, and dogs, and what not
11:49 PM
this prevents us from defining a foreign key if needs be
11:50 PM
and it underperforms what we'd get with a table for posts (it can contain tags and cats, that's no issue) and a separate one for links
11:50 PM
then, in the wp_taxonomies I suggested, we'd have a unique key on (taxonomy,slug,parent)
11:51 PM
or something like that involving the three fields
11:51 PM
that would allow to have a category with the same slug and multiple parents
11:51 PM
lastly, a key on slug (or the previous key) would still allow to join wp_tax on itself, in order to cross the boundaries on link terms and post terms
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10167 (red box when creating new items such as category, tag, meta data) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>vachi</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 21:46:33 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10167#comment:8</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10167#comment:8/1245188793000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
weird i got the same thing on a install on debian, checked it on the same server instance, using a clean install and iceweasel
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5183 (General Meta-Data Table) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 21:43:39 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5183#comment:14</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5183#comment:14/1245188619000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
just for reference:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;itching to produce a big patch along the lines of:
11:41 PM
drop table wp_terms; drop table wp_term_taxonomy; drop table wp_term_relationships;
11:42 PM
create table wp_taxonomies; create table wp_post2tax; create table wp_link2tax
11:42 PM
and then, create table wp_tax_meta;
11:43 PM
at some point
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5183 (General Meta-Data Table) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 21:38:17 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5183#comment:13</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5183#comment:13/1245188297000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
We should probably close this nonetheless. For performance sake, we'll be better off with a meta table *per* relevant table than one huge table that references things all over the place. This doesn't prevent us from having a generalized *API* to grab things, but the last thing we want is another table like wp_term_relationships that stores cats and dogs.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5183 (General Meta-Data Table) reopened</title>
      
        <dc:creator>westi</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 21:36:18 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5183#comment:12</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5183#comment:12/1245188178000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I don't see the taxonomy api as a place for storing metameta.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It doesn't fit at all what I would envisage meta meta containing.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>reopenedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #6801 (Should have a template file for front page) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 21:27:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/6801#comment:41</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/6801#comment:41/1245187672000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
@westi -- I'm pretty certain you'll wonder about this:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
front-page.php -&amp;gt; page template -&amp;gt; page.php
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
rather than:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
page template -&amp;gt; front-page.php -&amp;gt; page.php
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
the reasoning is, if a user specifies a page template (e.g. a sales letter template), he means it and wants that on the front page.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #6801 (Should have a template file for front page) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>westi</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 21:22:49 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/6801#comment:40</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/6801#comment:40/1245187369000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Owner&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Status&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #8923 (cron timeout is too short) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>westi</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 21:22:07 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8923#comment:21</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8923#comment:21/1245187327000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8923#comment:19" title="Comment 19"&gt;bueltge&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Many people have also this problem after update to 2.8:
wp_remote_post( $cron_url, array('timeout' =&amp;gt; 0.01
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Can we have more information here please.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
What problem?
What fix are you suggesting?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>upgrade2.diff attached to Ticket #10193</title>
      
        <dc:creator>westi</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 21:03:22 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10193/upgrade2.diff</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10193/upgrade2.diff/1245186202000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
With the typo fixed and the debug removed
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10189 ([Opera] [2.81-beta] theme_editor disabled by protective layer) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>azaozz</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 21:01:59 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10189#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10189#comment:3/1245186119000000</guid>
      <description>invalid: &lt;p&gt;
CodePress (the plugin/theme editor) works as expected in Opera 9.64 (current stable) but not in Opera 10-beta. This may be fixed when Opera 10-final comes out. Feel free to reopen if it still fails there.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10193 (backto parameter used in database needs better validation) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 21:00:55 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10193#comment:6</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10193#comment:6/1245186055000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
with a $ even
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10193 (backto parameter used in database needs better validation) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 21:00:43 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10193#comment:5</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10193#comment:5/1245186043000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
There is a typo. It should be:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
#location = wp_validate_redirect($location, admin_url());
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10193 (backto parameter used in database needs better validation) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>westi</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 20:55:58 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10193#comment:4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10193#comment:4/1245185758000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
And yes, if you wondered the +1 is just there to help you test.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>upgrade-notice-free.diff attached to Ticket #10193</title>
      
        <dc:creator>westi</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 20:52:53 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10193/upgrade-notice-free.diff</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10193/upgrade-notice-free.diff/1245185573000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Also don't create a new notice
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10193 (backto parameter used in database needs better validation) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>westi</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 20:47:13 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10193#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10193#comment:3/1245185233000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Normal the redirection is handled as a redirect using wp_safe_redirect().
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Here we place it in a link which is different.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10193 (backto parameter used in database needs better validation) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 20:43:37 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10193#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10193#comment:2/1245185017000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
also save post, etc.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10193 (backto parameter used in database needs better validation) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 20:43:19 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10193#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10193#comment:1/1245184999000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
the same applies to login/register, no?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>upgrade.diff attached to Ticket #10193</title>
      
        <dc:creator>westi</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 20:37:23 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10193/upgrade.diff</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10193/upgrade.diff/1245184643000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Fix for the issue.  Creates new wp_validate_redirect function
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10193 (backto parameter used in database needs better validation) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>westi</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 20:36:42 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10193</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10193/1245184602000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
When the database upgrade completes you are offered a continue button to allow you to go back where you can from.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The backto link is escaped and sanitised but it is not validated to be for the local blog so could be used for a phishing style redirect
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10190 (Plugin Dependency Class API) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 20:15:38 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10190#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10190#comment:3/1245183338000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
how about this:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;function get_plugin_versions() {
    require_once(ABSPATH . '/wp-admin/includes/plugin.php');
    $plugins = array();
    $all_plugins = get_plugins();
    $active_plugins = get_option('active_plugins');
    foreach ($active_plugins as $file)
        $plugins[$file] = $all_plugins[$files]['Version'];
    return $plugins;
}
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10126 (Warning upon saving draft page) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 20:03:43 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10126#comment:13</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10126#comment:13/1245182623000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10126 (Warning upon saving draft page) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 20:03:34 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10126#comment:12</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10126#comment:12/1245182614000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
bee: please check in your wp-content folder, in case there's a db.php file.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10190 (Plugin Dependency Class API) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>logikal16</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 19:57:18 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10190#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10190#comment:2/1245182238000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Alternative: a function, get_plugin_versions() that prints an array of active plugins and their corresponding versions.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://pastebin.com/m68e29ea0"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://pastebin.com/m68e29ea0&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This would make it the plugin author's responsibility to check for plugin dependencies.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10126 (Warning upon saving draft page) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 19:53:54 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10126#comment:11</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10126#comment:11/1245182034000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
escape() should handle arrays.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/browser/tags/2.8/wp-includes/wp-db.php#L478"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://core.trac.wordpress.org/browser/tags/2.8/wp-includes/wp-db.php#L478&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10126 (Warning upon saving draft page) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 19:51:05 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10126#comment:10</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10126#comment:10/1245181865000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10126 (Warning upon saving draft page) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 19:50:54 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10126#comment:9</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10126#comment:9/1245181854000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
sheesh... must have been really tired when we wrote that initial patch. the attached patch should fix this.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>10126.diff attached to Ticket #10126</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 19:50:18 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10126/10126.diff</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10126/10126.diff/1245181818000000</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10126 (Warning upon saving draft page) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Beee</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 19:45:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10126#comment:8</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10126#comment:8/1245181552000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Only plugin I have (which could be related, responding to the reply above) is simply exclude to exclude pages from search results...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
don't think it's related to this though...
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10133 (Dashboard feeds not loading) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>pavelevap</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 19:43:39 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10133#comment:6</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10133#comment:6/1245181419000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
No, it is not related. There is no anonymous comment (only the first generated one from wordpress.org). I tried to apply updated dashboard.php from this ticket, but problem persist. I am not allowed to see error log, but I will try to write to my webhoster for some of them...
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10104 (PCLZIP_ERR_BAD_FORMAT (-10) after changeset 11524) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 19:40:04 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10104#comment:15</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10104#comment:15/1245181204000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
(In &lt;a class="changeset" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11588" title="Increase download_url() timeout from 30 to 60. see #10104 for 2.8.1"&gt;[11588]&lt;/a&gt;) Increase download_url() timeout from 30 to 60. see &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10104" title="#10104: defect (bug): PCLZIP_ERR_BAD_FORMAT (-10) after changeset 11524 (closed: fixed)"&gt;#10104&lt;/a&gt; for 2.8.1
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Changeset [11588]: Increase download_url() timeout from 30 to 60. see #10104 for 2.8.1</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 19:39:59 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11588</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11588/1245181199873058</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Increase download_url() timeout from 30 to 60. see &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10104" title="#10104: defect (bug): PCLZIP_ERR_BAD_FORMAT (-10) after changeset 11524 (closed: fixed)"&gt;#10104&lt;/a&gt; for 2.8.1
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>changeset</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10104 (PCLZIP_ERR_BAD_FORMAT (-10) after changeset 11524) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 19:39:33 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10104#comment:14</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10104#comment:14/1245181173000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
(In &lt;a class="changeset" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11587" title="Increase download_url() timeout from 30 to 60. see #10104"&gt;[11587]&lt;/a&gt;) Increase download_url() timeout from 30 to 60. see &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10104" title="#10104: defect (bug): PCLZIP_ERR_BAD_FORMAT (-10) after changeset 11524 (closed: fixed)"&gt;#10104&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Changeset [11587]: Increase download_url() timeout from 30 to 60. see #10104</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 19:39:31 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11587</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11587/1245181171198441</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Increase download_url() timeout from 30 to 60. see &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10104" title="#10104: defect (bug): PCLZIP_ERR_BAD_FORMAT (-10) after changeset 11524 (closed: fixed)"&gt;#10104&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>changeset</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10192 (Installer/Upgrader bugs and tweaks) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 19:37:21 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10192#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10192#comment:3/1245181041000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
(In &lt;a class="changeset" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11586" title="Plugin install fixes. Props Denis-de-Bernardy. see #10192 for 2.8.1"&gt;[11586]&lt;/a&gt;) Plugin install fixes. Props Denis-de-Bernardy. see &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10192" title="#10192: defect (bug): Installer/Upgrader bugs and tweaks (closed: fixed)"&gt;#10192&lt;/a&gt; for 2.8.1
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Changeset [11586]: Plugin install fixes. Props Denis-de-Bernardy. see #10192 for 2.8.1</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 19:37:11 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11586</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11586/1245181031877408</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Plugin install fixes. Props Denis-de-Bernardy. see &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10192" title="#10192: defect (bug): Installer/Upgrader bugs and tweaks (closed: fixed)"&gt;#10192&lt;/a&gt; for 2.8.1
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>changeset</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10192 (Installer/Upgrader bugs and tweaks) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 19:36:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10192#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10192#comment:2/1245181010000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
(In &lt;a class="changeset" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11585" title="Plugin install fixes. Props Denis-de-Bernardy. see #10192"&gt;[11585]&lt;/a&gt;) Plugin install fixes. Props Denis-de-Bernardy. see &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10192" title="#10192: defect (bug): Installer/Upgrader bugs and tweaks (closed: fixed)"&gt;#10192&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Changeset [11585]: Plugin install fixes. Props Denis-de-Bernardy. see #10192</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 19:36:48 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11585</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11585/1245181008219408</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Plugin install fixes. Props Denis-de-Bernardy. see &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10192" title="#10192: defect (bug): Installer/Upgrader bugs and tweaks (closed: fixed)"&gt;#10192&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>changeset</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10192 (Installer/Upgrader bugs and tweaks) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 19:15:23 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10192#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10192#comment:1/1245179723000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
first batch attached, for plugins.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
tested except for this part, which seemed very wrong:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;-	$update_plugins = get_option('update_plugins');
+	$update_plugins = get_transient('update_plugins');
...
-	delete_option('update_plugins');
+	delete_transient('update_plugins');
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
a few comments on the patch:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;changes to wp-includes/update.php merely make the code conform with the comments
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;the addition of the $res-&amp;gt;external allows to remove the link to "Plugin page on WordPress.org" thingy, which is irrelevant when the plugin is hosted elsewhere
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;$api-&amp;gt;rating was missing a conditional statement
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10010 (Pings and Trackbacks are not working) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>rioch</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 19:10:23 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10010#comment:43</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10010#comment:43/1245179423000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
There hasn't been much activity. Has my new information not helped?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I have also read that the problem may be due to cron not running. Is there a way I can test this? Does anyone have any other ideas for how I can come to the root cause?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>10192.diff attached to Ticket #10192</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 19:09:26 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10192/10192.diff</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10192/10192.diff/1245179366000000</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10184 (feed_links() cannot be removed from wp_head) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 18:20:49 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10184#comment:6</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10184#comment:6/1245176449000000</guid>
      <description>wontfix: &lt;p&gt;
100% it will, in fact.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10184 (feed_links() cannot be removed from wp_head) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 18:19:16 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10184#comment:5</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10184#comment:5/1245176356000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
if you add this on the init hook, it should work:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
automatic_feed_links(false);
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10192 (Installer/Upgrader bugs and tweaks) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 18:04:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10192</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10192/1245175476000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Will post a big patch when I'm done testing the entire thing.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10191 (WordPress not determining if a request is a 404) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 17:56:59 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10191#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10191#comment:1/1245175019000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Owner&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Component&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Milestone&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10190 (Plugin Dependency Class API) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 17:56:13 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10190#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10190#comment:1/1245174973000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
As much as I like the idea, I think this should be dealt with by the plugins themselves, or internally over in wordpress.org (using the readme files).
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10189 ([Opera] [2.81-beta] theme_editor disabled by protective layer) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 17:52:16 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10189#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10189#comment:2/1245174736000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Milestone&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10185 (wp_mail filter  does not return filtered strings) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 17:49:13 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10185#comment:4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10185#comment:4/1245174553000000</guid>
      <description>invalid</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10185 (wp_mail filter  does not return filtered strings) reopened</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 17:49:03 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10185#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10185#comment:3/1245174543000000</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>reopenedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Changeset [11584]: Bump</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 17:42:31 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11584</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11584/1245174151623935</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Bump
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>changeset</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10132 (PHP Warning at menu-header.php line 118) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 17:13:24 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:25</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:25/1245172404000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class="changeset" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11583" title="Trim query strings from menu entries before seeing if a corresponding ..."&gt;[11583]&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Changeset [11583]: Trim query strings from menu entries before seeing if a corresponding ...</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 17:12:33 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11583</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11583/1245172353494065</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Trim query strings from menu entries before seeing if a corresponding file exists. fixes &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132" title="#10132: defect (bug): PHP Warning at menu-header.php line 118 (closed: fixed)"&gt;#10132&lt;/a&gt; for 2.8.1
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>changeset</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10132 (PHP Warning at menu-header.php line 118) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 17:11:55 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:24</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:24/1245172315000000</guid>
      <description>fixed: &lt;p&gt;
(In &lt;a class="changeset" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11582" title="Trim query strings from menu entries before seeing if a corresponding ..."&gt;[11582]&lt;/a&gt;) Trim query strings from menu entries before seeing if a corresponding file exists. fixes &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132" title="#10132: defect (bug): PHP Warning at menu-header.php line 118 (closed: fixed)"&gt;#10132&lt;/a&gt; for trunk
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Changeset [11582]: Trim query strings from menu entries before seeing if a corresponding ...</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 17:11:53 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11582</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11582/1245172313596714</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Trim query strings from menu entries before seeing if a corresponding file exists. fixes &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132" title="#10132: defect (bug): PHP Warning at menu-header.php line 118 (closed: fixed)"&gt;#10132&lt;/a&gt; for trunk
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>changeset</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10191 (WordPress not determining if a request is a 404) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>sivel</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 17:07:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10191</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10191/1245172056000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Using the default permalinks or when you have any other permalink installed, but request a post/page/cat/tag/author/archive using the default permalink style it will not correctly identify that a request to a post/page/cat/tag/author/archive that does not exist is a 404.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Due to this, numerous notices are generated from wp_title, get_body_class, comments_open, pings_open, feed_extra_links and many more.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10132 (PHP Warning at menu-header.php line 118) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 16:43:51 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:23</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:23/1245170631000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Verified fixed.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10132 (PHP Warning at menu-header.php line 118) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 16:39:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:22</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:22/1245170392000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Updated the patch to fix submenu highlighting that was broken by a variable naming collision.  menu-header.php could stand a thorough cleanup, but let's save that for later.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10132 (PHP Warning at menu-header.php line 118) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 16:37:42 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:21</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:21/1245170262000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I was going for fast. Usually strpos and substr are faster than pregs.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>10132.2.diff attached to Ticket #10132</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 16:35:49 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10132/10132.2.diff</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10132/10132.2.diff/1245170149000000</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10132 (PHP Warning at menu-header.php line 118) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 16:34:47 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:20</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:20/1245170087000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Tested 10132.2.diff on PHP 5.2.9-2, IIS 7.5 via FastCGI.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10132 (PHP Warning at menu-header.php line 118) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 16:31:10 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:19</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:19/1245169870000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Using preg_replace('/\?.*$/',&lt;em&gt;,SUBJECT) seems to have better code readability.
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10132 (PHP Warning at menu-header.php line 118) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 16:28:29 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:18</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:18/1245169709000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Patch strips query from file names.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>plugin-dependency.php attached to Ticket #10190</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ShaneF</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 16:07:10 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10190/plugin-dependency.php</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10190/plugin-dependency.php/1245168430000000</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10132 (PHP Warning at menu-header.php line 118) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 16:06:39 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:17</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:17/1245168399000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Is it the query arg causing the problem.  Maybe we should trim '/\?.*$/'.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10190 (Plugin Dependency Class API) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ShaneF</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 16:02:03 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10190</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10190/1245168123000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
This is the start of my WP_Plugin_Dependency class.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This has "checks" to see if a plugin or theme can be activated based on it's requirements. The plugin-dependency.php file is placed in '/wp-admin/includes/'.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10184 (feed_links() cannot be removed from wp_head) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 15:31:19 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10184#comment:4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10184#comment:4/1245166279000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Milestone&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
A patch, if any, should be checked in to 2.8 as automatic_feed_links was designed to be modified by plugins according to &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8878" title="#8878: enhancement: Allow theme developers to have feed links automatically outputted (closed: fixed)"&gt;#8878&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10133 (Dashboard feeds not loading) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 15:26:48 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10133#comment:5</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10133#comment:5/1245166008000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
This could be related to &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10162" title="#10162: defect (bug): Dashboard fails on anonymous comment after upgrading to 2.8 (closed: fixed)"&gt;#10162&lt;/a&gt;.  Are there any errors in the error log?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10184 (feed_links() cannot be removed from wp_head) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 15:22:38 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10184#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10184#comment:3/1245165758000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
First of all, I am surprised that there are comments in the report but Trac has not notified me by email. Is there a bug in Trac?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
@dd32: I suspect that automatic_feed_links(false) is called by the plugin first, but then the templete calls automatic_feed_links(true).
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Changeset [11581]: Bump</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 15:21:22 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11581</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11581/1245165682715065</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Bump
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>changeset</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10189 ([Opera] [2.81-beta] theme_editor disabled by protective layer) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>demetris</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 15:16:18 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10189#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10189#comment:1/1245165378000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Cc&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The issue with Opera and the Code Editor in 2.8 is known.  You can click on Screen Options and select “Disable syntax highlighting”, and the editor will come back.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Unfortunately, there is currently nothing to inform users that this is a known issue with a workaround (disabling syntax highlighting from Screen Options).
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10189 ([Opera] [2.81-beta] theme_editor disabled by protective layer) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>CD7</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 14:42:34 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10189</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10189/1245163354000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
After upgrading to wp 2.81-beta the theme editor doesent let one edit the code. worked fine in 2.8 and earlier.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Just go to theme editor and see that code can only be seen and not edited. Works in firefox.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I have Opera 10.00 Beta and Win Vista
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5998 (Invalid Unicode characters) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>codedread</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 14:32:21 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5998#comment:9</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5998#comment:9/1245162741000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
The reporter's case is the following:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Turn on true XHTML serving in WordPress (i.e. serving the application/xhtml+xml MIME type).  Malicious commenters come in and inject invalid code points into a comment on the blog.  WordPress does not handle some invalid code points (U+FFFE and U+FFFF specifically) so the result is that the blog now has a "Yellow Screen Of Death".
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5998 (Invalid Unicode characters) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>hakre</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 14:16:48 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5998#comment:8</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5998#comment:8/1245161808000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The question is where the invalid bytes have their origin in. Illigeal code-points should be checked against in the application inputs stream (e.g. request data or data from the database) before touching the output logic. having a filter for the output would be too late.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
it would be good to know more about the originals reporter case. more details and maybe steps to reproduce.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10188 (Sorting by last modified) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>link2caro</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 13:01:19 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10188</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10188/1245157279000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
It would be great if there was an option to sort posts/pages/media and the archive page by modified_date.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10187 (wp_redirect and canonical redirect do not work as expected on IIS) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 13:00:14 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10187#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10187#comment:1/1245157214000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
This patch depends on &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10186" title="#10186: enhancement: Add global $server_version (closed: wontfix)"&gt;#10186&lt;/a&gt;. Tested with PHP 5.2.9-2 on IIS 5.1 via FastCGI.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10187 (wp_redirect and canonical redirect do not work as expected on IIS) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 12:59:19 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10187</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10187/1245157159000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
To address a bug affecting IIS &amp;lt;=5, wp_redirect use header("Refresh: 0; url=$location") instead of header("Location: $location") on all versions of IIS, which is unexpected.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10186 (Add global $server_version) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 12:52:29 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10186</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10186/1245156749000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
A number of workarounds/features are specific to IIS in WordPress Core. However, some workarounds/features apply to certain IIS versions only. I suggest adding a global $iis_version.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10185 (wp_mail filter  does not return filtered strings) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>anmari</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 12:32:13 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10185#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10185#comment:2/1245155533000000</guid>
      <description>fixed: &lt;p&gt;
Thanks for that confirmation - I thought I was going nuts going around in circles.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It must have been something I had in the code - after your positive confirmation, I cut the code down to absolute basics - it worked, then I built it up again and now it works, but I cannot see what I did that was different.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
anyway - yes it does work and very conveniently so - can now access the "to" and filter the message accordingly - sweet!
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10132 (PHP Warning at menu-header.php line 118) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 11:55:58 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:16</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:16/1245153358000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This patch (10132-disable-PHP-Warning.patch) disables PHP Warning, which fixes this report and probably also &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/7640" title="#7640: defect (bug): Upgrade has warnings when open_basedir is in effect (closed: fixed)"&gt;#7640&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5771" title="#5771: defect (bug): error_log in wp-db.php and install failures (closed: fixed)"&gt;#5771&lt;/a&gt;. Tested with PHP 5.2.9-2 NTS on IIS 7.5 via FastCGI as well.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>10132-disable-PHP-Warning.patch attached to Ticket #10132</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 11:52:57 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10132/10132-disable-PHP-Warning.patch</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10132/10132-disable-PHP-Warning.patch/1245153177000000</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10132 (PHP Warning at menu-header.php line 118) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 11:39:57 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:15</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:15/1245152397000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I have uploaded a patch that uses @file_exists to fix the problem. Tested it with PHP 5.2.9-2 NTS on IIS 7.5 via FastCGI.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
By the way, the PHP Warning in full is:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
PHP Warning: file_exists() [function.file-exists]: open_basedir restriction in effect. File(C:\wwwroot\wordpress/wp-content/plugins/edit-tags.php?taxonomy=post_tag) is not within the allowed path(s): (C:\wwwroot) in C:\wwwroot\wordpress\wp-admin\menu-header.php on line 118
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>10132.patch attached to Ticket #10132</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 11:38:49 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10132/10132.patch</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10132/10132.patch/1245152329000000</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10185 (wp_mail filter  does not return filtered strings) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>dd32</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 11:26:08 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10185#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10185#comment:1/1245151568000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
apply filters returns a string with "array" ?, so this code does not appear to work.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Are you sure your plugin is not incorrectly returning something on that filter? - It works as expected for me.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Further down the filters are applied again individually for 'wp_mail_from' and 'wp_mail_from_name' why not apply the wp_mail filters on the subject and body lines there rather?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As you can see in the code, Its mainly for legacy purposes that they're set separately.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Its possible to add them into the wp_mail filter.. but.. In the end, For back compat purposes, The other filters will remain in their current location, as well as the legacy code overriding the wp_mail filter..
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10132 (PHP Warning at menu-header.php line 118) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 11:24:42 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:14</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:14/1245151482000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I have tried the patch but it doesn't work. The PHP Warning remains blocking the Admin interface.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10132 (PHP Warning at menu-header.php line 118) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 11:18:25 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:13</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:13/1245151105000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
@peaceablewhale: the odd thing is, the patch I uploaded is what the reporter suggested fixed it for him. have you tried it in a setup similar to his?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10185 (wp_mail filter  does not return filtered strings) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>anmari</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 11:16:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10185</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10185/1245150996000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Firstly, if calling function wp_mail directly, one gets this message:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Warning: extract() [function.extract]: First argument should be an array in pluggable.php line 256
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The code is:
extract( apply_filters( 'wp_mail', compact( 'to', 'subject', 'message', 'headers', 'attachments' ) ) );
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
apply filters returns a string with "array" ?, so this code does not appear to work.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Further down the filters are applied again individually for 'wp_mail_from' and 'wp_mail_from_name'
why not apply the wp_mail filters on the subject and body lines there rather?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If I do this, it seems to work.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10183 (Thickbox in WordPress 2.8) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>kovshenin</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 10:49:12 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10183#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10183#comment:2/1245149352000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10183#comment:1" title="Comment 1"&gt;Denis-de-Bernardy&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
it's loaded in the footer and working fine in there. please update your plugin accordingly by making it a depend for your other js (it'll then load in the header) or moving your own script in the footer.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Ugh, you're right, most themes miss the wp_footer(); function before the closing body tag. That caused my plugin to break, sorry.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10184 (feed_links() cannot be removed from wp_head) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 10:22:21 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10184#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10184#comment:2/1245147741000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Type&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Milestone&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
adding to this, the filter (assuming we add any) should be in the function directly imo
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10183 (Thickbox in WordPress 2.8) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 10:20:24 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10183#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10183#comment:1/1245147624000000</guid>
      <description>invalid: &lt;p&gt;
it's loaded in the footer and working fine in there. please update your plugin accordingly by making it a depend for your other js (it'll then load in the header) or moving your own script in the footer.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10182 (XHTML well-formedness) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 10:14:01 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10182#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10182#comment:2/1245147241000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Component&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10180 (Add rel="prev" to previous_posts_link() and rel="next" to next_posts_link()) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 10:12:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10180#comment:5</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10180#comment:5/1245147120000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Component&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10180 (Add rel="prev" to previous_posts_link() and rel="next" to next_posts_link()) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 10:11:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10180#comment:4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10180#comment:4/1245147110000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Type&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Milestone&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10167 (red box when creating new items such as category, tag, meta data) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 10:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10167#comment:7</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10167#comment:7/1245146880000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I'm getting none of that on a mac
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5821 (Use Flash Uploader for WXR uploader) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 10:00:57 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5821#comment:5</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5821#comment:5/1245146457000000</guid>
      <description>duplicate: &lt;p&gt;
let's close as dup then
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10184 (feed_links() cannot be removed from wp_head) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>dd32</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 09:00:13 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10184#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10184#comment:1/1245142813000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Is there any reason why a plugin cannot call &lt;code&gt;automatic_feed_links(false)&lt;/code&gt; directly?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10182 (XHTML well-formedness) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>dd32</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 08:59:09 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10182#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10182#comment:1/1245142749000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Version&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Milestone&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
-1 to the patch. The urlencodes shouldnt be needed there.. Where ever its being outputted should be run through the esc_raw_url() function (Or whatever its called...)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
+1 for the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;  removal tho.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10180 (Add rel="prev" to previous_posts_link() and rel="next" to next_posts_link()) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>dd32</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 08:51:08 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10180#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10180#comment:3/1245142268000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8703" title="#8703: feature request: Add functions to display adjacent relational links in the head (closed: fixed)"&gt;#8703&lt;/a&gt; added next/prev/home for single browsing, But not for archive browsing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
/archive/2009/05/ should have a next for /archives/2009/06/ etc.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I'm pretty sure thats what this ticket is asking for.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10167 (red box when creating new items such as category, tag, meta data) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>dd32</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 08:40:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10167#comment:6</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10167#comment:6/1245141636000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Thats a CDATA end marker, I'm thinking its coming  from the JS XML Wp-ajax parser... Saving the page wont help since its dynamically generated.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I cant reproduce it though locally.. mind you, thats on Windows..  any mac users can verify?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10133 (Dashboard feeds not loading) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>pavelevap</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 08:35:43 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10133#comment:4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10133#comment:4/1245141343000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
No, this problem appears in all browsers for me. When I return back to Dashboard after more then (around) 24 hours, then Dashboard is loaded as the whole (but Blog, News and Plugin widgets there is only "Loading"). When I click somewhere else and then return back to Dashboard, then it is not loaded to the end (missing footer), no Javascript works, but Blog, News and Plugin widgets are loaded correctly... Please, could you test it somebody - I can give you login info (it is fresh install with no change)...
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10127 (User roles not translated) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>pavelevap</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 08:29:55 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10127#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10127#comment:2/1245140995000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Yes, of course. You can download Czech version for Wordpress 2.8 from Codex and try it... Everything works well except 5 user roles which stay in English...
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>10184.patch attached to Ticket #10184</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 08:10:02 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10184/10184.patch</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10184/10184.patch/1245139802000000</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10184 (feed_links() cannot be removed from wp_head) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 08:09:03 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10184</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10184/1245139743000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Due to the way feed_links() is added to wp_head in automatic_feed_links(), it cannot be removed by a plugin.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10011 (Use of add_theme_page() causes Wordpress on IIS to crash.) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 07:39:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10011#comment:36</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10011#comment:36/1245137990000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
However, that build is not officially supported by PHP and contains known security issues.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10011 (Use of add_theme_page() causes Wordpress on IIS to crash.) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>bforchhammer</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 07:37:38 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10011#comment:35</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10011#comment:35/1245137858000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10011#comment:34" title="Comment 34"&gt;peaceablewhale&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Is it really worth working around the PHP bug?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Considering that version 5.2.5 is the &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://www.fusionxlan.com/PHPx64.php"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;highest available 64bit version&lt;/a&gt; I think it is.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10183 (Thickbox in WordPress 2.8) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>kovshenin</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 07:16:56 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10183</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10183/1245136616000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
It's not working. wp_enqueue_script does not load the thickbox.js file. Hope I'm not the only one..
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Here's a temporary workaround: &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://kovshenin.com/894"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://kovshenin.com/894&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>wpXhtmlIssues.patch attached to Ticket #10182</title>
      
        <dc:creator>brettz95</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 07:11:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10182/wpXhtmlIssues.patch</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/10182/wpXhtmlIssues.patch/1245136306000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Patches for application/xhtml+xml well-formedness
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10182 (XHTML well-formedness) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>brettz95</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 07:11:19 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10182</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10182/1245136279000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Hi,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Just offering a patch of a few files which break Wordpress under application/xhtml+xml . Not sure if this is the best way to fix them, but it at least did the trick.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5682 (Clean permalinks and mod_rewrite support for IIS) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 04:25:43 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5682#comment:32</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5682#comment:32/1245126343000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Improving readability should be good :)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Perhaps we can leave this to the committer.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10132 (PHP Warning at menu-header.php line 118) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 04:22:16 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:12</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:12/1245126136000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Priority&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
see also &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/7640" title="#7640: defect (bug): Upgrade has warnings when open_basedir is in effect (closed: fixed)"&gt;#7640&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5771" title="#5771: defect (bug): error_log in wp-db.php and install failures (closed: fixed)"&gt;#5771&lt;/a&gt;, which are also related to open_basedir.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Disabling PHP Warning will also fix them.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10132 (PHP Warning at menu-header.php line 118) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 04:11:16 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:11</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:11/1245125476000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Actually, if error_reporting is set to E_ALL in php.ini, I can't even enter /wp-admin/... The PHP Warning blocked the access.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10132 (PHP Warning at menu-header.php line 118) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 04:04:22 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:10</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10132#comment:10/1245125062000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Summary&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
"open_basedir restriction in effect" is never a fatal error, and it is not limited to IIS I think.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
To fix it, we have to either ask PHP not to report any Warning or add @ before all file_exists calls. Which method is better?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10011 (Use of add_theme_page() causes Wordpress on IIS to crash.) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 03:58:59 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10011#comment:34</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10011#comment:34/1245124739000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I have confirmed that &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://bugs.php.net/bug.php?id=44412"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://bugs.php.net/bug.php?id=44412&lt;/a&gt; exists in PHP 5.2.5 with open_basedir set, the PHP script will not return anything until it times out.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The bug has been fixed since PHP 5.2.6. With open_basedir set, a PHP warning is returned: "PHP Warning: file_exists() [function.file-exists]: open_basedir restriction in effect.".
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Using @file_exists() will get "false".
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Is it really worth working around the PHP bug?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5821 (Use Flash Uploader for WXR uploader) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>beaulebens</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 03:56:10 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5821#comment:4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5821#comment:4/1245124570000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Cc&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
See Also: &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8822" title="#8822: enhancement: Use SWFUpload on importer tools (closed: wontfix)"&gt;#8822&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10135 (JavaScript Error In post.js When Using Internet Explorer) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>azaozz</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 03:50:20 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10135#comment:4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10135#comment:4/1245124220000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Or &lt;code&gt;window.autosave = ...&lt;/code&gt; as autosave is supposed to be in the global scope.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10136 (is_active_sidebar() should use wp_get_sidebars_widgets()) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>azaozz</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 03:10:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10136#comment:14</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10136#comment:14/1245121852000000</guid>
      <description>fixed: &lt;p&gt;
(In &lt;a class="changeset" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11580" title="is_active_sidebar() should use wp_get_sidebars_widgets(), props ..."&gt;[11580]&lt;/a&gt;) is_active_sidebar() should use wp_get_sidebars_widgets(), props greenshady and Denis-de-Bernardy, fixes &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10136" title="#10136: defect (bug): is_active_sidebar() should use wp_get_sidebars_widgets() (closed: fixed)"&gt;#10136&lt;/a&gt; for 2.8.1
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Changeset [11580]: is_active_sidebar() should use wp_get_sidebars_widgets(), props ...</title>
      
        <dc:creator>azaozz</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 03:10:49 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11580</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11580/1245121849074402</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
is_active_sidebar() should use wp_get_sidebars_widgets(), props greenshady and Denis-de-Bernardy, fixes &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10136" title="#10136: defect (bug): is_active_sidebar() should use wp_get_sidebars_widgets() (closed: fixed)"&gt;#10136&lt;/a&gt; for 2.8.1
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>changeset</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10181 (Warnings after post/page save) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 02:50:58 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10181#comment:8</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10181#comment:8/1245120658000000</guid>
      <description>fixed: &lt;p&gt;
(In &lt;a class="changeset" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11579" title="Don't write to htaccess every time page is saved.  Add hard/soft flush ..."&gt;[11579]&lt;/a&gt;) Don't write to htaccess every time page is saved.  Add hard/soft flush flag to flush_rules(). Make sure fopen is successful and silence errors. Props Viper007Bond. fixes &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10181" title="#10181: defect (bug): Warnings after post/page save (closed: fixed)"&gt;#10181&lt;/a&gt; for 2.8.1
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Changeset [11579]: Don't write to htaccess every time page is saved.  Add hard/soft flush ...</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 02:50:55 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11579</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11579/1245120655754782</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Don't write to htaccess every time page is saved.  Add hard/soft flush flag to flush_rules(). Make sure fopen is successful and silence errors. Props Viper007Bond. fixes &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10181" title="#10181: defect (bug): Warnings after post/page save (closed: fixed)"&gt;#10181&lt;/a&gt; for 2.8.1
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>changeset</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Changeset [11578]: Don't write to htaccess every time page is saved.  Add hard/soft flush ...</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 02:44:28 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11578</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/11578/1245120268286107</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Don't write to htaccess every time page is saved.  Add hard/soft flush flag to flush_rules(). Make sure fopen is successful and silence errors. Props Viper007Bond. fixes &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10181" title="#10181: defect (bug): Warnings after post/page save (closed: fixed)"&gt;#10181&lt;/a&gt; for trunk
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>changeset</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5682 (Clean permalinks and mod_rewrite support for IIS) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 01:24:57 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5682#comment:31</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5682#comment:31/1245115497000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
doh, trac got rid of the or thingies.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5682 (Clean permalinks and mod_rewrite support for IIS) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 01:24:22 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5682#comment:30</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5682#comment:30/1245115462000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
for readability's sake only. it's not needed in php.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="wiki"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;false &lt;td&gt; true &amp;amp;&amp;amp; true = false &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; ( true &amp;amp;&amp;amp; true ) = true
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5682 (Clean permalinks and mod_rewrite support for IIS) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>peaceablewhale</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 01:17:44 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5682#comment:29</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5682#comment:29/1245115064000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
+1 to the latest patch too. However, is it better to add a () to the second part of the new statement?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;empty( $_SERVER['REQUEST_URI'] ) || ( php_sapi_name() != 'cgi-fcgi' &amp;amp;&amp;amp; preg_match( '/^Microsoft-IIS\//' , $_SERVER['SERVER_SOFTWARE'] ) &amp;gt; 0 )
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10135 (JavaScript Error In post.js When Using Internet Explorer) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 01:17:03 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10135#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10135#comment:3/1245115023000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
@brianwhite - andrew is having issues reproducing, and, please try this:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
document.autosave = ...
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10181 (Warnings after post/page save) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 00:44:59 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10181#comment:7</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10181#comment:7/1245113099000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Haven't tested, but the logic seems correct. The other flush_rules need to be hard indeed. Had a doubt on the one for import, but seemed right too on second though.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5682 (Clean permalinks and mod_rewrite support for IIS) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 00:26:21 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5682#comment:28</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5682#comment:28/1245111981000000</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I'm +1 for the latest patch
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item>
   </channel>
</rss>