<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>WordPress Trac</title>
    <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/timeline</link>
    <description>Trac Timeline</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <generator>Trac 1.2.2</generator>
    <image>
      <title>WordPress Trac</title>
      <url>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/chrome/site/your_project_logo.png</url>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/timeline</link>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>Ticket #16517 (What about / Whom to ask for full/missing wordpress source-code?) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Otto42</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 23:30:03 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:20</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:20/1298071803391669</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
BTW, the major reason that we don't include the MIT license is probably because the main SWFUpload package itself doesn't include a copy of the license either.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16517 (What about / Whom to ask for full/missing wordpress source-code?) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Otto42</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 23:26:54 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:19</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:19/1298071614807279</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:18" title="Comment 18"&gt;hakre&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Otto, the worpdress.org homepage states that the package I can download is licensed under GNU GPL.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The package is GPL, yes. The individual files do not have to be, as long as they're under less restrictive licenses.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
See, you're correct in that the GPL provides for including files from multiple sources. This is what is meant by GPL-Compatible. A GPL-Compatible license is one that is less restrictive than the GPL itself.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The MIT license can be found on GNU's license compatibility page as the "X11 License": &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/license-list.html"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/license-list.html&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So in fact, while the SWFUpload code is not licensed under the GPL, it is licensed under something that is even *less* restrictive than the GPL. The MIT license does not require you to distribute sources. It also does not require you to make modifications available. You may note that on that GNU page, it mentions that it is a non-copyleft license.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Take it another way: What if we only had the binary? No sources available. Well, the binary is still free to use for any purpose. It's still under a less restrictive license than the GPL. It is still GPL-Compatible, even as a binary alone. Because it's GPL-compatible, it can be repackaged and included with GPL software. Nobody says it better than here: &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl-faq.html#WhatDoesCompatMean"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl-faq.html#WhatDoesCompatMean&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
What does it mean to say a license is “compatible with the GPL?”
It means that the other license and the GNU GPL are compatible; you can combine code released under the other license with code released under the GNU GPL in one larger program.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Now, somebody did point out this clause in the MIT license which I had not noticed before: "The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the Software."
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So we do need to include a copy of the license along with the SWFUpload.swf file. But that's all their license requires. Here's what the MIT license says, in full:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Copyright (C) &amp;lt;year&amp;gt; by &amp;lt;copyright holders&amp;gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy
of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"), to deal
in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights
to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell
copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is
furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in
all copies or substantial portions of the Software.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE
AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM,
OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN
THE SOFTWARE.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16517 (What about / Whom to ask for full/missing wordpress source-code?) reopened</title>
      
        <dc:creator>hakre</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 23:12:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:18</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:18/1298070756195082</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Otto, the worpdress.org homepage states that the package I can download is licensed under GNU GPL.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If that information is "wrong" because some files therein do not fall under the packages licensing (that's how I read you), then I would like to know how I and other users can know that for each file in there. That's all for the moment.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The wordpress.org homepage is not offering any other information then that the files in the package are under GPL.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>reopenedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10201 (Remove user-specific caps) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan_b</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 22:59:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10201#comment:61</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10201#comment:61/1298069990723220</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Cc&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
what if instead of doing away with user specific capabilities, we did away with roles.  I mean since when does it make sense to link a user to an arbitrary grouping (ie role) that just links to the actual capabilities.  Best I can tell this was done for simplicity, most average user's want to make a user an editor, not make a user who has capabilities a, b, c, 1, 2, 3, x, y, and z if you know what I mean.  That is all fine and good and I can understand that.  But who says you have to link the user to a role.  Picture this, you add a new table let's call it usercaps (yes, you could use usermeta for this but it'll probably be cleaner to do this is a different table) that will link users to caps, with an arbitrary auto incremented number to act as primary key, the scheme would be like this:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
ID (pk) = 1&lt;br /&gt;
User ID = 1&lt;br /&gt;
Capability = manage_options
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
ect...this can be done either way, select * from usercaps where User ID = 1 and Capability = manage_options to see if the user has the cap, select UserID from usercaps where Capability = manage_options to see who has manage_options, or select Capability from usercaps where User ID = 1 to see what caps user 1 has.
Now what about the general user, we want to keep simple things simple while remaining flexible is the key, you we will still have something called roles, it will be much like a template of capabilities to give the user, the net effect cleanner in the db, keeps the simple role system for the general user, but it's flexible for those power users.
Now for the power users, there would be an API that a plugin could utilize to replace the role selector with a direct capability selector so now each user can have their own distinct set of capabilities, if needed.  This would be done via Plugin API with a plugin only for those requiring something more flexible than just the basic roles.
This way you change out your old V6 roles/capabilities engine with a more powerful v8, while keeping things simple for the average user but remaining flexible for advanced users giving them more power if they need it (hey that's a good analogy, I'll have to remember that one, lol).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I mentioned this in wp-hacker's this question was raised: but if you would want to add a capability to a role, you don't know which user has which role.
so you would have to do this for every user.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Which was a fair point, my response to that was there are really two options, option one is you could determain the current role by caps, ie if they can manage_options you know they are an admin, if not check a cap first avalible at the next level, or introduce a role specific cap (bring back levels for instance).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The other option, perhaps what may work best, is to still store the role in user meta, this way you can still display in the admin panel the specific role for a given user like today, it keeps things very familiar to the user.  Also for those using the full capability editor which would be accessed either by plugin or setting an option somewhere, you could still let then choose roles, then customize them further, then if they are not using the exact role setup but a customized set of capabilities you could give them a textbox to name the "role" which would just describe the capability set, such as "Author + Edit Widgets", this would be stored in the role meta value.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So what do you think of this method, i'm always interested in feedback.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16525 (Clarification of license for phpatomlib / AtomLib) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Otto42</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 22:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16525#comment:8</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16525#comment:8/1298068920203372</guid>
      <description>invalid: &lt;p&gt;
What's the problem here? The license is GPLv2. No conflicts that I can see. That's WP's license too.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16591 (Some package downloads and their checksums give 404) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Otto42</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 22:37:51 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16591#comment:4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16591#comment:4/1298068671244996</guid>
      <description>fixed: &lt;p&gt;
IIS links to nonexistent tar.gz files removed.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16517 (What about / Whom to ask for full/missing wordpress source-code?) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Otto42</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 22:20:12 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:17</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:17/1298067612358465</guid>
      <description>invalid: &lt;p&gt;
WordPress doesn't need to offer the sources, &lt;strong&gt;because you can get them from the original source&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
SWFUpload is a &lt;em&gt;free&lt;/em&gt; package, licensed under the MIT license.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://www.swfupload.org/"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://www.swfupload.org/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://swfupload.googlecode.com/"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://swfupload.googlecode.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
WordPress has made no modifications to their sources whatsoever. You can just go download them yourself. We have links to their sources right there in the JS files associated with them.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Plus, I'm still totally at sea as to why you keep using the word "sources". There is ONE binary file in the package (not counting images). The source is clearly pointed out, both in the files and here. It's under a totally free license, even freer than GPL. and their license does not require us to provide their source code.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Please stop reopening this unless you have a valid point that has not been addressed. I will just close it again if you do.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16517 (What about / Whom to ask for full/missing wordpress source-code?) reopened</title>
      
        <dc:creator>hakre</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 22:11:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:16</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:16/1298067106278980</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
So far I assume the GNU GPL used on software packages regulates rights and responsibilities in connection to the software contained therein.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
However, Ottos argumentation creates the image, that wordpress.org can and does deny to offer sources for some of the files in the package and therefore not complete source(s) for the package as a whole.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If wordpress.org maintains it's position as outlined above, then I would like to know where I can find the terms of use for each individual file in the package offered for download.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Without clarifying this question first, the main inquiry of my ticket about sources can't even be solved.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>reopenedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16587 (wp_list_categories hide_empty  counts unpublished posts) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ocean90</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 20:17:54 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16587#comment:4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16587#comment:4/1298060274366701</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Milestone&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16593 (wp_set_object_terms not creating links when in a save_post action) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>grandslambert</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 19:30:21 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16593</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16593/1298057421192677</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I have a custom post type and a custom taxonomy for a recipe plugin. The edit page for the post type has a meta box where ingredients are added, and the ingredient name is the custom taxonomy. I have a hook into the 'save_post' action that then calls a function to save the ingredients. Within that function is code to loop through and either match an existing term, or create a new term in the taxonomy. This part works without a problem. While doing this, I create an array of data related to the term to use in wp_set_object_terms().
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I then call:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;code&gt;wp_set_object_terms($post_id, $postIngredients, 'recipe-ingredient', false);&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
where $post_id is the ID of the post, and $postIngredients is the data I collected earlier. I have tried an array of term IDs, names, and slugs, all with the same result. Even though wp_set_object_terms() returns a list of "affected" IDs, the data does not appear to be saved. When I go back to the edit screen for that post, it does not show an updated list of ingredients.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The code is included in the RecipePress plugin and appears in the /classes/recipe-press-core.php file.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I also have an importer and front end form that uses the same function to save the ingredients. Both of these do exactly what they are supposed to do. It just does not work when the function is called from the 'save_post" action.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16587 (wp_list_categories hide_empty  counts unpublished posts) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>grandslambert</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 19:11:47 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16587#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16587#comment:3/1298056307140792</guid>
      <description>duplicate: &lt;p&gt;
It is with a custom taxonomy and would be related to &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/14084" title="#14084: defect (bug): Custom taxonomy count includes draft &amp;amp; trashed posts (closed: invalid)"&gt;#14084&lt;/a&gt; - but that also does not show any resolution. I will follow that ticket for now. Thank you.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16389 (register_shutdown_function isn't run in SHORTINIT mode) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>jtclarke</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 17:36:16 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16389#comment:14</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16389#comment:14/1298050576655214</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
hello?  anyone?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16591 (Some package downloads and their checksums give 404) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>westi</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 16:46:49 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16591#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16591#comment:3/1298047609694348</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Correct IIS is zip file only.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Just because there is a link there doesn't mean the file ever existed
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16592 (Faq/FAQ (#2)) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ocean90</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 16:22:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16592#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16592#comment:2/1298046172861486</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Milestone&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16592 (Faq/FAQ (#2)) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>SergeyBiryukov</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 16:17:30 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16592#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16592#comment:1/1298045850627367</guid>
      <description>duplicate: &lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16580" title="#16580: defect (bug): Faq/FAQ in the admin (closed: fixed)"&gt;#16580&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #13847 (WP increasing the memory above other server limit) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>wpmuguru</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 15:49:51 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/13847#comment:25</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/13847#comment:25/1298044191423193</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>13847.2.diff attached to Ticket #13847</title>
      
        <dc:creator>wpmuguru</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 15:48:58 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/13847/13847.2.diff</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/13847/13847.2.diff/1298044138163490</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
apply the admin_memory_limit filter throughout wp-admin
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #15821 (Faq/FAQ) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>hakre</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 15:13:40 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/15821#comment:5</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/15821#comment:5/1298042020747048</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Related:  &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16592" title="#16592: defect (bug): Faq/FAQ (#2) (closed: duplicate)"&gt;#16592&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16592 (Faq/FAQ (#2)) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>hakre</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 15:13:33 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16592</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16592/1298042013233894</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
When installing a plugin from the admin, it's still “Faq” there - see &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/15821" title="#15821: enhancement: Faq/FAQ (closed: fixed)"&gt;#15821&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #11436 (Adding wmode transparent to flash videos) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>hakre</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 15:07:04 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/11436#comment:20</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/11436#comment:20/1298041624679730</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
@SergeyBiryukov: My review of your last patch.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>11436.3.patch attached to Ticket #11436</title>
      
        <dc:creator>hakre</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 15:06:27 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/11436/11436.3.patch</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/11436/11436.3.patch/1298041587035563</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16485 (XML-RPC Response Parsing Failed error caused by functions.php) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>hakre</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 14:57:23 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16485#comment:8</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16485#comment:8/1298041043709015</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Type&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #13847 (WP increasing the memory above other server limit) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>prettyboymp</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 14:01:23 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/13847#comment:24</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/13847#comment:24/1298037683265153</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Cc&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Would love to see this get some movement.  I've often run into issues where I need to boost the memory limit while running imports and the media handling constantly drops it back down to 256MB.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16134 (Check capabilities/role before adding comment links to email) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>tislam100</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 13:49:57 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16134#comment:8</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16134#comment:8/1298036997132028</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
any alternative to user_can() that works in wordpress 3.0.5?
Can it be done with user role?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Thanks
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16591 (Some package downloads and their checksums give 404) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>dd32</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 13:34:28 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16591#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16591#comment:2/1298036068674216</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Milestone&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
All the IIS releases are .zip files, I don't think they're supposed to have a .tar.gz file.. Those links should probably be removed.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As for the checksums.. Thats a bit weird as well, is it for the .zip or the .tar.gz?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16457 (Issues with DIRECTORY_SEPARATOR) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>scribu</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 13:16:18 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16457#comment:5</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16457#comment:5/1298034978383311</guid>
      <description>worksforme</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16591 (Some package downloads and their checksums give 404) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>hakre</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 13:06:24 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16591#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16591#comment:1/1298034384910777</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Forgot: Page in question is: &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://wordpress.org/download/release-archive/"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://wordpress.org/download/release-archive/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16591 (Some package downloads and their checksums give 404) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>hakre</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 13:05:38 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16591</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16591/1298034338526782</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I had problems to retrieve the following files from the download archive:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.8.4-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.8.4-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.8.4a-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.8.4a-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.8.4b-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.8.4b-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.8.5-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.8.5-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.8.6-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.8.6-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.9-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.9-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.9.1-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.9.1-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.9.2-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.9.2-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.0-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.0-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.0.1-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.0.1-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.0.2-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.0.2-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.0.3-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.0.3-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.0.5-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.0.5-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.7.1-IIS-RC1.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.7.1-IIS-RC1.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.8.6-beta1-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.8.6-beta1-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.9-beta-1-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.9-beta-1-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.9-beta-2-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.9-beta-2-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.9-RC1-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.9-RC1-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.9.1-beta1-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.9.1-beta1-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.9.1-RC1-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-2.9.1-RC1-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.0-beta1-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.0-beta1-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.0-beta2-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.0-beta2-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.0-RC1-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.0-RC1-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.0-RC2-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.0-RC2-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.0-RC3-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.0-RC3-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.1-beta1-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.1-beta1-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.1-beta2-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.1-beta2-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.1-RC2-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.1-RC3-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.1-RC2-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.1-RC3-IIS.md5
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.1-RC4-IIS.tar.gz
Error: Http Code not OK (200):404 - Url: http://wordpress.org/wordpress-3.1-RC4-IIS.md5
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16590 (get_page_by_title doesn't work for cutom pages) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>duck_</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 11:18:40 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16590#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16590#comment:2/1298027920389651</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you mean it's not working for custom post types are you correctly specifying the post type you want to look up?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The function signature is:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;code&gt;get_page_by_title($page_title, $output = OBJECT, $post_type = 'page')&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So if you want to retrieve an 'album' post type, for example, you would use:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;code&gt;get_page_by_title( 'Album Title', OBJECT, 'album' )&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16590 (get_page_by_title doesn't work for cutom pages) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>o----o</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 11:08:45 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16590#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16590#comment:1/1298027325090004</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
sorry, I have forgotten WP 3.0.5
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16590 (get_page_by_title doesn't work for cutom pages) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>o----o</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 11:05:35 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16590</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16590/1298027135031500</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
get_page_by_title() queried for custom pages returns NULL
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16589 (Localized version stats) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>pavelevap</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 10:59:28 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16589#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16589#comment:1/1298026768415508</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Cc&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>15782.2.diff attached to Ticket #15782</title>
      
        <dc:creator>garyc40</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 09:17:20 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/15782/15782.2.diff</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/15782/15782.2.diff/1298020640083776</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
remove redundant &lt;code&gt;admin_script_globals()&lt;/code&gt; function
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16587 (wp_list_categories hide_empty  counts unpublished posts) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>garyc40</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 09:13:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16587#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16587#comment:2/1298020416494418</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I can't reproduce this when &lt;code&gt;wp_list_categories()&lt;/code&gt; is using the default &lt;code&gt;category&lt;/code&gt; taxonomy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you're using &lt;code&gt;wp_list_categories()&lt;/code&gt; with a custom taxonomy, then this is a duplicate of &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/14084" title="#14084: defect (bug): Custom taxonomy count includes draft &amp;amp; trashed posts (closed: invalid)"&gt;#14084&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Otherwise, please paste the code snippet in which you're using &lt;code&gt;wp_list_category()&lt;/code&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16589 (Localized version stats) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>SergeyBiryukov</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 08:52:48 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16589</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16589/1298019168206841</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
There have been some discussions on localized version stats:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://lists.automattic.com/pipermail/wp-polyglots/2009-November/003812.html"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://lists.automattic.com/pipermail/wp-polyglots/2009-November/003812.html&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://lists.automattic.com/pipermail/wp-polyglots/2009-December/003868.html"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://lists.automattic.com/pipermail/wp-polyglots/2009-December/003868.html&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://lists.automattic.com/pipermail/wp-polyglots/2010-July/004859.html"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://lists.automattic.com/pipermail/wp-polyglots/2010-July/004859.html&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://wppolyglots.wordpress.com/2010/12/01/ive-found-some-discussions-about-local-2/"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://wppolyglots.wordpress.com/2010/12/01/ive-found-some-discussions-about-local-2/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://wppolyglots.wordpress.com/2010/08/18/i-am-having-some-problems-with-site-stat/"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://wppolyglots.wordpress.com/2010/08/18/i-am-having-some-problems-with-site-stat/&lt;/a&gt; (related)
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Many translators would agree that it would be nice to have them back.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16588 (is_admin_bar_showing can return true when it isn't) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>westi</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 08:25:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16588</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16588/1298017552321374</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
is_admin_bar_showing returns true on wp-login.php if you are logged in but it will never be shown.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It shouldn't
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16134 (Check capabilities/role before adding comment links to email) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>solarissmoke</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 07:58:21 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16134#comment:7</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16134#comment:7/1298015901217792</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Trunk is the latest development version of Wordpress, as opposed to the latest stable version. The patch (and your plugin) will not work in Wordpress 3.0.5 because it uses the &lt;code&gt;user_can()&lt;/code&gt; function is new to Wordpress 3.1. It works in 3.1 however.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16134 (Check capabilities/role before adding comment links to email) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>tislam100</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 07:42:55 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16134#comment:6</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16134#comment:6/1298014975879396</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
What is trunk? Did you try the plugin I made? Maybe there is a bug in the plugin. can you take a look at it?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Thank you.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10630 (Patch to make wp_enqueue_script work on login_head (wp-login.php)) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>lloydbudd</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 07:34:16 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10630#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10630#comment:2/1298014456548608</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Solved with it's own hooks login_enqueue_scripts in &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16586" title="#16586: defect (bug): Don't fire the wp_enqueue_scripts hook on wp-login.php (closed: fixed)"&gt;#16586&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Changeset [17468]: Bump</title>
      
        <dc:creator>markjaquith</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 06:08:35 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/17468</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/17468/1298009315389639</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Bump
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>changeset</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Changeset [17467]: Bump</title>
      
        <dc:creator>markjaquith</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 06:08:07 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/17467</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/17467/1298009287272116</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Bump
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>changeset</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16587 (wp_list_categories hide_empty  counts unpublished posts) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>greuben</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 05:49:16 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16587#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16587#comment:1/1298008156524926</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Related/dupe &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/14084" title="#14084: defect (bug): Custom taxonomy count includes draft &amp;amp; trashed posts (closed: invalid)"&gt;#14084&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16586 (Don't fire the wp_enqueue_scripts hook on wp-login.php) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>nacin</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 05:17:42 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16586#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16586#comment:3/1298006262521069</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class="changeset" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/17465" title="Do not attach wp_enqueue_scripts to login_head. New ..."&gt;[17465]&lt;/a&gt; for trunk.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16586 (Don't fire the wp_enqueue_scripts hook on wp-login.php) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>markjaquith</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 05:15:28 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16586#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16586#comment:2/1298006128999760</guid>
      <description>fixed: &lt;p&gt;
(In &lt;a class="changeset" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/17466" title="Do not attach wp_enqueue_scripts to login_head. New ..."&gt;[17466]&lt;/a&gt;) Do not attach wp_enqueue_scripts to login_head. New login_enqueue_scripts hook. props nacin. fixes &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16586" title="#16586: defect (bug): Don't fire the wp_enqueue_scripts hook on wp-login.php (closed: fixed)"&gt;#16586&lt;/a&gt; for 3.1
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Changeset [17466]: Do not attach wp_enqueue_scripts to login_head. New ...</title>
      
        <dc:creator>markjaquith</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 05:15:26 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/17466</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/17466/1298006126991905</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Do not attach wp_enqueue_scripts to login_head. New login_enqueue_scripts hook. props nacin. fixes &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16586" title="#16586: defect (bug): Don't fire the wp_enqueue_scripts hook on wp-login.php (closed: fixed)"&gt;#16586&lt;/a&gt; for 3.1
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>changeset</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Changeset [17465]: Do not attach wp_enqueue_scripts to login_head. New ...</title>
      
        <dc:creator>markjaquith</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 05:10:58 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/17465</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/17465/1298005858895200</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Do not attach wp_enqueue_scripts to login_head. New login_enqueue_scripts hook. props nacin. fixes &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16586" title="#16586: defect (bug): Don't fire the wp_enqueue_scripts hook on wp-login.php (closed: fixed)"&gt;#16586&lt;/a&gt; for trunk
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>changeset</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #14510 (comment_notes_before does not work.) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>solarissmoke</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 04:51:54 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/14510#comment:16</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/14510#comment:16/1298004714896457</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Related &lt;a class="new ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16576" title="#16576: enhancement: comment_form() fields being displayed only for non logged in users (new)"&gt;#16576&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16576 (comment_form() fields being displayed only for non logged in users) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>solarissmoke</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 04:51:26 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16576#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16576#comment:1/1298004686456897</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Related &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/14510" title="#14510: enhancement: comment_notes_before does not work. (closed: maybelater)"&gt;#14510&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16586 (Don't fire the wp_enqueue_scripts hook on wp-login.php) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>nacin</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 04:11:23 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16586#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16586#comment:1/1298002283543867</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Description&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Correcting the admin_enqueue_scripts hook name in the description.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16587 (wp_list_categories hide_empty  counts unpublished posts) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>grandslambert</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 02:55:11 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16587</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16587/1297997711138649</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
The template tag &lt;strong&gt;wp_list_categories()&lt;/strong&gt; has an option to &lt;em&gt;hide_empty&lt;/em&gt;, however, this only hides categories that have no posts, no just no &lt;em&gt;published&lt;/em&gt; posts. The result is that categories with only posts that are draft or pending show on the front end, and the links go to blank pages. It would be better if this argument for the tag would display only categories with published posts.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16457 (Issues with DIRECTORY_SEPARATOR) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>grandslambert</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 02:51:12 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16457#comment:4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16457#comment:4/1297997472106839</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I removed the use of DIRECTORY_SEPARATOR in my code after reading more and due to the comments here. I have asked my plugin testers to let me know if there are issues with the scripts and images loading, but they seem to be working now.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>16586.diff attached to Ticket #16586</title>
      
        <dc:creator>nacin</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 02:29:35 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/16586/16586.diff</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/16586/16586.diff/1297996175344118</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16586 (Don't fire the wp_enqueue_scripts hook on wp-login.php) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>nacin</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 02:27:39 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16586</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16586/1297996059495455</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
admin_enqueue_scripts and wp_enqueue_scripts actions are ideally where wp_enqueue_script() calls should be attached to -- one for the admin, and one for the theme.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class="changeset" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/16000" title="Remove the ghetto code and use the script loader properly on the login ..."&gt;[16000]&lt;/a&gt; attached wp_enqueue_scripts() to login_head, which is a wrapper function to fire the wp_enqueue_scripts action. This means that a theme attaching a script to the frontend via wp_enqueue_scripts -- even if wrapped in an unnecessary is_admin() check -- will get their JS printed on the login form. This has the potential to throw JS errors, which is what happens in P2 for example.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The fix is to come up with a new action name.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16581 (Meta widget: properly redirect user after logging in / out) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>nacin</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 02:11:07 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16581#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16581#comment:1/1297995067662757</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
-1. Many people use the meta widget cause they don't know how to get to their admin area otherwise. The logged out link should indeed redirect to wherever they came from. But not the logged in link.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #8775 (Numbers in quotation marks get wrong smart quotes) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>filosofo</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 01:16:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8775#comment:19</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8775#comment:19/1297991810100703</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
We have a patch.  It's the prerequisite &lt;code&gt;wptexturize&lt;/code&gt; unit tests that are missing.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #8775 (Numbers in quotation marks get wrong smart quotes) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Denis-de-Bernardy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 01:06:32 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8775#comment:18</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8775#comment:18/1297991192564886</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8775#comment:17" title="Comment 17"&gt;Viper007Bond&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It's still a valid issue. Just because progress isn't being made isn't reason enough to close the ticket.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Any chances you've got a patch? :-)
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16577 (The register_setting function doesn't exist in Network Admin area) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>nacin</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 00:44:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16577#comment:5</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16577#comment:5/1297989876531496</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Milestone&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
No problem.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16577 (The register_setting function doesn't exist in Network Admin area) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>cgrymala</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 00:36:26 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16577#comment:4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16577#comment:4/1297989386840009</guid>
      <description>invalid: &lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16577#comment:3" title="Comment 3"&gt;nacin&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It's only available in the admin. So admin_init, not init. That should solve your problem.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
That seems to have worked. Sorry for erroneously reporting a bug. Thanks for the help.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16585 (Proposed changes to wp enqueueing and shortcode handling) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>scribu</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 00:25:12 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16585#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16585#comment:3/1297988712620775</guid>
      <description>wontfix: &lt;p&gt;
We had a lengthy discussion in IRC, which can be summarised as follows:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;a solution for Core would need to avoid DB writes on the front-end and bulk re-processing of posts on plugin activation (we couldn't find said solution)
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;most shortcodes shouldn't have heavy JS/CSS anyway, so it shouldn't be such a big deal if they're loaded on all pages
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16585 (Proposed changes to wp enqueueing and shortcode handling) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>scribu</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 23:53:39 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16585#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16585#comment:2/1297986819842182</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This can be achieved by storing a list of used shortcode tags within a pages meta, likely while saving a post or page, that can later be used as a conditional check with, among others, wp_enqueue_script and wp_enqueue_style.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Big -1. As described in IRC:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;(01:40:45 AM) scribu: scenario: you make a simple shortcode that doesn't need additional css/js and you release it as a plugin
(01:41:21 AM) scribu: afterwards, you make it fancier and now you do need a some additional css/js
(01:41:36 AM) scribu: you release the updated version of the plugin and the user updates
(01:41:52 AM) scribu: but wait, the user already has posts that use the previous version of the shortcode
(01:41:58 AM) scribu: what happens then?
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16574 (Lazy load ancestors) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>johnjamesjacoby</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 23:23:16 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16574#comment:8</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16574#comment:8/1297984996221483</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Using get_post here also reduces cache misses with no adverse effects for things like single blog post views, where the next and previous posts are automatically added to wp_head, and then loaded again in the content area. Without this method, ancestor queries aren't cached. Same goes for pages in nav menus, etc...
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #11955 (Plugin Compatibility page for WordPress 2.9) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Otto42</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 22:51:02 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/11955#comment:7</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/11955#comment:7/1297983062146527</guid>
      <description>wontfix: &lt;p&gt;
Closing as wontfix for now, as there has got to be a better way. When somebody thinks of it, then we'll do that instead. Big lists that don't get maintained are pointless.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16580 (Faq/FAQ in the admin) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>dd32</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 22:45:57 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16580#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16580#comment:1/1297982757006023</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I'd like to move some of this business logic back to the API. Section names should come down from .org, as well as links should be absolute rather than relative.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #15232 (Empty single quote strings are visible in the editor but not the codex ...) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Otto42</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 22:44:59 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/15232#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/15232#comment:3/1297982699900455</guid>
      <description>wontfix: &lt;p&gt;
Double single quote strings is wiki-markup for italics. If you need to have code in the wiki with items in it like this, wrap it in &amp;lt;pre&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/pre&amp;gt; code to prevent wiki markup from being used.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #15366 (WordPress Development Blog feed can't redirect) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Otto42</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 22:39:16 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/15366#comment:5</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/15366#comment:5/1297982356263905</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
nacin: Do you have the patch for this? Send it to me. I tried a simple .htaccess mod, but it still redirected due to canonical URLs. And if you have it, it'd save me some time. :)
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16585 (Proposed changes to wp enqueueing and shortcode handling) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>kawauso</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 22:38:56 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16585#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16585#comment:1/1297982336924737</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Cc&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16585 (Proposed changes to wp enqueueing and shortcode handling) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Jester831</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 22:31:27 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16585</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16585/1297981887102571</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Currently, the only way for a programmer to avoid loading their scripts/css on every page is to either peek through the_content() for their shortcode and enqueue accordingly, or to use their shortcode handler to set a boolean for doing a conditional script print after partially loading a page. While this is certainly feasible, it's largely unused and the majority of plugins overload css and js unnecessarily.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I propose that instead of operating under the expectation that all programmers do this, we instead implement a mechanism to do this solely through wp_enqueue_script and wp_enqueue_style.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This can be achieved by storing a list of used shortcode tags within a pages meta, likely while saving a post or page, that can later be used as a conditional check with, among others, wp_enqueue_script and wp_enqueue_style.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
A new optional parameter would be then added to wp_enqueue_script and wp_enqueue_style that would check said meta, or potentially other meta, and conditionally load, without the requirement of any further coding.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16584 (Media Gallery sorts images by two columns despite get_posts not ...) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>smerriman</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 22:25:55 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16584</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16584/1297981555705578</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
In the get_media_items function in wp-admin/includes/media.php, attachments are sorted first by menu order, then by post ID by the following line:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;$attachments = get_children( array( 'post_parent' =&amp;gt; $post_id, 'post_type' =&amp;gt; 'attachment', 'orderby' =&amp;gt; 'menu_order ASC, ID', 'order' =&amp;gt; 'DESC') );
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
However, the get_posts in wp-admin/includes/query.php function does not properly support this. It splits up orderby by spaces, and then throws out 'ASC,' as it does not match a valid value. Due to a lucky coincidence, it turns into ORDER BY menu_order, ID DESC which still works in the same way.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I often want to display the first x uploaded images to a post, but allow changing which images are considered the first x via menu_order. If I solely order by ID ASC, that won't work. If I solely order by menu_order ASC, that won't work either, since the ones at the top of the list (latest uploaded) become first in the menu order. The only way to get it to work is to sort by menu_order DESC, ID ASC - but using
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
{{'orderby' =&amp;gt; 'menu_order DESC, ID', 'order' =&amp;gt; 'ASC'}}
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
doesn't not work since the 'DESC,' gets ignored.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There are two possible interpretations of this bug:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
a) Remove 'ASC,' in the line I mentioned since it's not valid according to the current rules for get_posts
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
b) Make get_posts properly support the above method by not having it throw out the extra order condition.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16577 (The register_setting function doesn't exist in Network Admin area) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>nacin</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 22:19:41 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16577#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16577#comment:3/1297981181454304</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
It's only available in the admin. So admin_init, not init. That should solve your problem.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16577 (The register_setting function doesn't exist in Network Admin area) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>cgrymala</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 21:50:54 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16577#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16577#comment:2/1297979454488759</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
If you look at the source of the class-extended-super-admins.php file for version 0.4a of the &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/extended-super-admins/"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;Extended Super Admins&lt;/a&gt; plugin (function excerpted below - the function shown below is hooked to the 'init' action), you will see how I was trying to use the register_setting function.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Version 0.5a now uses the add_filter() function if the register_setting() function is not available. Keep in mind that I am talking about using this within the &lt;strong&gt;Network Admin&lt;/strong&gt; area, not the &lt;strong&gt;Site Admin&lt;/strong&gt; area.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;		function _init() {
			if( function_exists( 'load_plugin_textdomain' ) )
				load_plugin_textdomain( ESA_TEXT_DOMAIN, false, ESA_PLUGIN_PATH . '/lang/' );
			if( is_admin() &amp;amp;&amp;amp; isset( $_REQUEST['page'] ) &amp;amp;&amp;amp; $_REQUEST['page'] == ESA_OPTIONS_PAGE ) {
				if( function_exists( 'register_setting' ) )
					register_setting( ESA_OPTION_NAME, ESA_OPTION_NAME, array( $this, 'verify_options' ) );
				if( function_exists( 'wp_enqueue_script' ) ) {
					wp_enqueue_script( 'esa_admin_scripts' );
				}
				if( function_exists( 'wp_enqueue_style' ) ) {
					wp_enqueue_style( 'esa_admin_styles' );
				}
			}
		}
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
In earlier versions of the plugin, I was getting a PHP error about the fact that the &lt;code&gt;register_setting()&lt;/code&gt; function didn't exist, which is why I added the check to see if the function exists or not.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As I said, in version 0.5a of the plugin (and beyond), I started using the following function to get around the issue.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;		function _init() {
			if( function_exists( 'load_plugin_textdomain' ) )
				load_plugin_textdomain( ESA_TEXT_DOMAIN, false, ESA_PLUGIN_PATH . '/lang/' );
			if( is_admin() &amp;amp;&amp;amp; isset( $_REQUEST['page'] ) &amp;amp;&amp;amp; $_REQUEST['page'] == ESA_OPTIONS_PAGE ) {
				if( function_exists( 'register_setting' ) )
					register_setting( ESA_OPTION_NAME, ESA_OPTION_NAME, array( $this, 'verify_options' ) );
				else
					add_filter( 'sanitize_option_' . ESA_OPTION_NAME, array( $this, 'verify_options' ) );
				if( function_exists( 'wp_enqueue_script' ) ) {
					wp_enqueue_script( 'esa_admin_scripts' );
				}
				if( function_exists( 'wp_enqueue_style' ) ) {
					wp_enqueue_style( 'esa_admin_styles' );
				}
			}
		}
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Just in case it makes a difference, here is how I'm instantiating the class for my plugin (includes a check to see if any of the multi-network plugins are installed, as well):
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;function instantiate_extended_super_admins() {
	if( !is_multisite() )
		return;
	if( is_multinetwork() ) {
		require_once( 'class-wpmn_super_admins.php' );
		$wpsa = new wpmn_super_admins;
		$wpsa-&amp;gt;is_multi_network = true;
		return $wpsa;
	} else {
		require_once( 'class-extended_super_admins.php' );
		$wpsa = new extended_super_admins;
		$wpsa-&amp;gt;is_multi_network = false;
		return $wpsa;
	}
}
add_action( 'plugins_loaded', 'instantiate_extended_super_admins' );
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Then, within the &lt;code&gt;__construct()&lt;/code&gt; method of my class, I have the following call:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;			add_action( 'init', array( $this, '_init' ) );
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
With version 0.4a of the plugin (using just the &lt;code&gt;register_setting()&lt;/code&gt; function), everything worked fine in version 3.0.5 of WordPress. However, in version 3.1, the &lt;code&gt;register_setting()&lt;/code&gt; function is unavailable.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I hope this helps. Thank you.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16583 (Move/Add the details of an update to updates.php) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>mimecine</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 21:15:13 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16583</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16583/1297977313054511</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Sorry for the fuzzy language below, have no current updates waiting, so I don't see the exact behaviour.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Something that has bugged me for some time is that you get a link to see the details of an upgrade in the plugins at plugins.php, but no such link exists on the update-core.php page.   To me it makes most sense to have it at update-core.php  so I could go through each available update and see if/why I need to upgrade that specific plugin. A direct link to the changelog would be most helpful, but even the same overlay with plugin info would be better than nothing.
And, stupid as I am - since I sometimes blindly do upgrades (yes I know it's a bad practice) - it would be great to have that same link in the resulting list where it says "Upgrade succeded for XYZ".
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I'd take a crack at it myself, but I failed to find the file where the list is generated.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16582 (Ticket fields are too wide in Firefox) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>SergeyBiryukov</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 20:46:13 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16582#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16582#comment:1/1297975573134400</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
E-mail can exceed the width too: &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://i54.tinypic.com/esj8ub.jpg"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://i54.tinypic.com/esj8ub.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16582 (Ticket fields are too wide in Firefox) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>scribu</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 20:00:23 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16582</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16582/1297972823771184</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
See screenshot:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://i.imgur.com/UajQf.png"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://i.imgur.com/UajQf.png&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
( feeling meta about creating a ticket about the ticket creation page :)
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16581 (Meta widget: properly redirect user after logging in / out) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>garyc40</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 19:20:11 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16581</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16581/1297970411685787</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Inside Meta widget, there's a login link. However, the href attribute doesn't contain a redirection query argument.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So, there's a usability problem when someone is reading a post and want to comment, but can't because he's not logged in (and the blog requires logging in to comment). After logging in using the link inside Meta widget, the user is redirected to the admin area, instead of to the post he was reading. It would be a few clicks too many to go back to the post to comment.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The same thing can be applied to the Log out link (when the user's currently logged in). Instead of showing the blank &lt;code&gt;wp-login.php&lt;/code&gt; form, he should be redirected back to the page where he clicked the link.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #14143 (Make readme files #hash-URL linkable) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Otto42</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 17:20:06 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/14143#comment:6</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/14143#comment:6/1297963206853250</guid>
      <description>fixed: &lt;p&gt;
Seems reasonable enough. Done.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You'll have to actually update the readme.txt before you'll see those appear, but I force updated json-api to make it work there first.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Also, I don't like underscores. So I used dashes instead:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/json-api/other_notes/#3.-Request-arguments"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/json-api/other_notes/#3.-Request-arguments&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #14143 (Make readme files #hash-URL linkable) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>dphiffer</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 17:08:59 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/14143#comment:5</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/14143#comment:5/1297962539423520</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Otto, yes exactly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Basically I'd like to make this link jump to the "Request arguments" part of the page.
&lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/json-api/other_notes/#3._Request_arguments"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/json-api/other_notes/#3._Request_arguments&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #15917 ("Propose an Idea" page not working.) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Otto42</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 17:07:24 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/15917#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/15917#comment:3/1297962444231830</guid>
      <description>fixed: &lt;p&gt;
Added the default role code to ideas. That should fix this.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #15917 ("Propose an Idea" page not working.) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Otto42</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 17:04:37 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/15917#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/15917#comment:2/1297962277085325</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
After investigating several reports of this, I've determined it was due to those members being "inactive" on the ideas site for some reason. I'm looking at the activation code now to figure out what the deal is.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #14143 (Make readme files #hash-URL linkable) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Otto42</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 17:02:11 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/14143#comment:4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/14143#comment:4/1297962131935390</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I'm confused by this. What h3's are you referring to here? On the plugin page in extend?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16579 ($groupby should be set for 'meta_query' too) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>SergeyBiryukov</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 16:58:01 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16579#comment:4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16579#comment:4/1297961881690757</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16579#comment:3" title="Comment 3"&gt;ryan&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
link to whatever codex page was updated
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://codex.wordpress.org/index.php?title=Function_Reference/query_posts&amp;amp;diff=100662&amp;amp;oldid=100579"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://codex.wordpress.org/index.php?title=Function_Reference/query_posts&amp;amp;diff=100662&amp;amp;oldid=100579&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;code&gt;meta_query&lt;/code&gt; is array of arrays (was a simple array in the example).
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16577 (The register_setting function doesn't exist in Network Admin area) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 16:52:51 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16577#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16577#comment:1/1297961571039160</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I can't reproduce the problem. Can you show how you are registering the setting?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16579 ($groupby should be set for 'meta_query' too) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 16:32:21 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16579#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16579#comment:3/1297960341369708</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Could we describe the symptoms, provide sample code that exhibits the problem, and link to whatever codex page was updated.  This ticket jumps right to the fix. :-)
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #12563 (New action on body open) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>saracup</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 15:50:30 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/12563#comment:12</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/12563#comment:12/1297957830772109</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Version&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
As more and more of us are deploying Wordpress as a CMS (not just a blogging platform), there is greater need for global navigational elements, which usually occur right after the opening of the body tag. To have to develop themes to address this cuts out Wordpress as a viable open source platform without having to rely on a framework like Hybrid which has inserted hooks to enable this kind of thing. You are leaving to the developers something that, if in the core, would enable non-developers to deploy plugins without hiring someone. This is vital for our organization, and means the difference between tying into a premium framework, hiring a development firm, or being able to enhance our themes with global navigation elements ourselves. As a higher education institution with few resources, we would benefit very much from this. It helps chosen themes scale better for an institution that wants a unified look and feel but the flexibility of Wordpress. Please, please consider putting this in the core.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10142 (Add metadata support for taxonomy terms) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>scribu</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 15:47:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10142#comment:29</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10142#comment:29/1297957670436825</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10142#comment:27" title="Comment 27"&gt;sirzooro&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
BTW, CC list is getting longer and longer. Is it possible to include this ticket in 3.2 (preferable as Task)?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This won't become a task until consensus is reached, firstly on the usefulness of the feature, and secondly on the approach.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #10142 (Add metadata support for taxonomy terms) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>scribu</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 15:45:34 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10142#comment:28</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/10142#comment:28/1297957534887179</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Currently, terms can be shared between taxonomies, although there is a trend against that: &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5809" title="#5809: defect (bug): Updating a term in one taxonomy affects the term in every taxonomy (closed: fixed)"&gt;#5809&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
With such a shared term, it's much more likely that you will want to associate different metadata for different taxonomies.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Therefore, as it is now, if we add a term meta table, it should be connected via taxonomy_term_id only.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Flipping the coin, if we connect it via term_id only, it's easy to differentiate based on taxonomy, by adding the taxonomy name to the meta key, for example.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
My point is that we should have one or the other, not both.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>16580.patch attached to Ticket #16580</title>
      
        <dc:creator>SergeyBiryukov</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 15:45:13 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/16580/16580.patch</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/16580/16580.patch/1297957513220500</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16580 (Faq/FAQ in the admin) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>SergeyBiryukov</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 15:44:40 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16580</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16580/1297957480938923</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
In &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/15821" title="#15821: enhancement: Faq/FAQ (closed: fixed)"&gt;#15821&lt;/a&gt;, “Faq” on plugin pages was replaced with “FAQ”.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
However when installing a plugin from the admin, it's still “Faq” there.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #5809 (Updating a term in one taxonomy affects the term in every taxonomy) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>scribu</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 15:35:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5809#comment:17</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/5809#comment:17/1297956950860207</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Cc&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #15821 (Faq/FAQ) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Otto42</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 15:26:19 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/15821#comment:4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/15821#comment:4/1297956379403795</guid>
      <description>fixed: &lt;p&gt;
That needs to be a separate ticket. That code is generated by WordPress itself, it doesn't come from the .org site.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #15821 (Faq/FAQ) reopened</title>
      
        <dc:creator>SergeyBiryukov</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 15:25:27 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/15821#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/15821#comment:3/1297956327676792</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
When installing a plugin from the admin, it's still “Faq” there.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>reopenedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16517 (What about / Whom to ask for full/missing wordpress source-code?) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>chipbennett</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 15:00:30 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:15</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:15/1297954830730897</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:14" title="Comment 14"&gt;Otto42&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Download the "core" package.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Unzip it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In there you will find a directory called "Flash".
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
That contains the source code and binary for the swfupload.swf file. The "source" is more than one file, although the majority of it is in SWFUpload.as.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Okay, so the following files correspond to the &lt;em&gt;swfupload.swf&lt;/em&gt; binary?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;ExternalCall.as
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;FileItem.as
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;SWFUpload v2.as3proj
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;SWFUpload.as
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;deploy.bat
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If that's true, then I'm satisfied.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16517 (What about / Whom to ask for full/missing wordpress source-code?) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Otto42</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 14:53:53 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:14</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:14/1297954433159649</guid>
      <description>invalid: &lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:13" title="Comment 13"&gt;chipbennett&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Look: I don't know Flash. Those files are all Greek to me. Rather than condescendingly smacking your head on your desk, could you instead simply point out which one of those text files corresponds to the binary in question? If you'll kindly do that, I'll be done here, as at that point, I will believe that the concerns of the ticket itself have been satisfied.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Download the "core" package.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Unzip it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In there you will find a directory called "Flash".
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
That contains the source code and binary for the swfupload.swf file. The "source" is more than one file, although the majority of it is in SWFUpload.as.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16517 (What about / Whom to ask for full/missing wordpress source-code?) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>chipbennett</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 14:50:47 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:13</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:13/1297954247754465</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I'm really not interested in generating or engaging a GPL flame war. We apparently disagree on the clause in question, and neither will change the other's mind on the matter. So, I'm just going to cut to the relevant comments.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:12" title="Comment 12"&gt;Otto42&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:11" title="Comment 11"&gt;chipbennett&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So where is this "designated place" from which WordPress offers for licensees to download source files for the binary in question?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
From swfupload.js:
/&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;SWFUpload: &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://www.swfupload.org"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://www.swfupload.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://swfupload.googlecode.com"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://swfupload.googlecode.com&lt;/a&gt;
*
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;mmSWFUpload 1.0: Flash upload dialog - &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://profandesign.se/swfupload/"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://profandesign.se/swfupload/&lt;/a&gt;,  &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://www.vinterwebb.se/"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://www.vinterwebb.se/&lt;/a&gt;
*
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;SWFUpload is (c) 2006-2007 Lars Huring, Olov Nilzén and Mammon Media and is released under the MIT License:
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://www.opensource.org/licenses/mit-license.php"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://www.opensource.org/licenses/mit-license.php&lt;/a&gt;
*
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;SWFUpload 2 is (c) 2007-2008 Jake Roberts and is released under the MIT License:
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://www.opensource.org/licenses/mit-license.php"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://www.opensource.org/licenses/mit-license.php&lt;/a&gt;
*
*/
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;
From both of those two URLs at the beginning: &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://www.swfupload.org"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://www.swfupload.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://swfupload.googlecode.com"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://swfupload.googlecode.com&lt;/a&gt; you can find several "Download" links. Downloading would give you the source code. 15 seconds of investigation would give you that.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Please don't antagonize. I linked to the project repository already. You don't need to point it out to me again, sarcastically.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Okay, so the link provided goes to the SWFUpload project website, which itself links to a googlecode repository for the code itself. Is the swfupload.swf source file &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://code.google.com/p/swfupload/source/browse/swfupload/trunk/core/Flash"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;somewhere in here&lt;/a&gt;?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The main download page is right here: &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://code.google.com/p/swfupload/downloads/list"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://code.google.com/p/swfupload/downloads/list&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The "core" package contains the SWF file and the source you need to build it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I will 100% agree that WordPress is in the clear, &lt;em&gt;if someone can point out where the swfupload.swf source file is made available&lt;/em&gt;. I assume that, if it's available, &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://code.google.com/p/swfupload/source/browse/swfupload/trunk/core/Flash"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;it's here somewhere&lt;/a&gt;?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Which, really, would put a quick end to this ticket.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
*headdesk*
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
By &lt;em&gt;source file&lt;/em&gt;, I am referring to the GPL definition of the term: the editable file, not the binary. I see the source &lt;em&gt;binary&lt;/em&gt; file, but have no clue which one is the corresponding source text file.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Look: I don't know Flash. Those files are all Greek to me. Rather than condescendingly smacking your head on your desk, could you instead simply point out which one of those text files corresponds to the binary in question? If you'll kindly do that, I'll be done here, as at that point, I will believe that the concerns of the ticket itself have been satisfied.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16517 (What about / Whom to ask for full/missing wordpress source-code?) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Otto42</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 14:42:13 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:12</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:12/1297953733444852</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:11" title="Comment 11"&gt;chipbennett&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I think you're misreading that clause.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
No, I'm not. Really.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The binary in question is not being distributed by WordPress &lt;em&gt;as a separate work&lt;/em&gt;, but rather as a component of the whole package.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
True, but only the whole package is what is being licensed. The license cannot apply to SWFUpload when you pull it out and consider it separately.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
And that was sort of my point. WordPress, the package, is GPL licensed. SWFUpload is not, even when you get it by taking it out of WordPress, the package.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Thus, we must consider the next clause:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But &lt;strong&gt;when you distribute the same sections as part of a whole which is a work based on the Program, the distribution of the whole must be on the terms of this License&lt;/strong&gt;, whose &lt;strong&gt;permissions for other licensees extend&lt;/strong&gt; to the entire whole, and thus &lt;strong&gt;to each and every part&lt;/strong&gt; regardless of who wrote it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
That's pretty clear: GPL &lt;em&gt;permissions for other licensees extend... to each and every part [of the whole]&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
To each and every part [of the whole], yes, but only when they are in the whole.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This is very important: you cannot, ever, under any circumstances whatsoever, relicense something that you do not own. It makes absolutely no difference what any license text says, you cannot put a different license on somebody else's work. A license is a statement that grants rights to other people. If you don't have the copyright, then you cannot grant rights to others.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If I take the WordPress package and pull SWFUpload out of it, then that specific piece is not GPL licensed. It's only the work as a whole that is GPL, and all the parts of it which WordPress owns the copyrights to that it can grant rights under the GPL for.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
And that's what that phrase really means. If I take a bunch of files I created and say "this package is GPL", then all the parts in it are GPL'd individually as well... If I have the copyright and thus the power to grant rights to other people. But I can't grant conditional rights to code that I don't own.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So where is this "designated place" from which WordPress offers for licensees to download source files for the binary in question?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
From swfupload.js:
/&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;SWFUpload: &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://www.swfupload.org"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://www.swfupload.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://swfupload.googlecode.com"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://swfupload.googlecode.com&lt;/a&gt;
*
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;mmSWFUpload 1.0: Flash upload dialog - &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://profandesign.se/swfupload/"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://profandesign.se/swfupload/&lt;/a&gt;,  &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://www.vinterwebb.se/"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://www.vinterwebb.se/&lt;/a&gt;
*
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;SWFUpload is (c) 2006-2007 Lars Huring, Olov Nilzén and Mammon Media and is released under the MIT License:
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://www.opensource.org/licenses/mit-license.php"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://www.opensource.org/licenses/mit-license.php&lt;/a&gt;
*
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;SWFUpload 2 is (c) 2007-2008 Jake Roberts and is released under the MIT License:
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://www.opensource.org/licenses/mit-license.php"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://www.opensource.org/licenses/mit-license.php&lt;/a&gt;
*
*/
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;
From both of those two URLs at the beginning: &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://www.swfupload.org"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://www.swfupload.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://swfupload.googlecode.com"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://swfupload.googlecode.com&lt;/a&gt; you can find several "Download" links. Downloading would give you the source code. 15 seconds of investigation would give you that.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Okay, so the link provided goes to the SWFUpload project website, which itself links to a googlecode repository for the code itself. Is the swfupload.swf source file &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://code.google.com/p/swfupload/source/browse/swfupload/trunk/core/Flash"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;somewhere in here&lt;/a&gt;?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The main download page is right here: &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://code.google.com/p/swfupload/downloads/list"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://code.google.com/p/swfupload/downloads/list&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The "core" package contains the SWF file and the source you need to build it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I will 100% agree that WordPress is in the clear, &lt;em&gt;if someone can point out where the swfupload.swf source file is made available&lt;/em&gt;. I assume that, if it's available, &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://code.google.com/p/swfupload/source/browse/swfupload/trunk/core/Flash"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;it's here somewhere&lt;/a&gt;?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Which, really, would put a quick end to this ticket.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
*headdesk*
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16517 (What about / Whom to ask for full/missing wordpress source-code?) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>chipbennett</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 14:29:48 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:11</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:11/1297952988846071</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:10" title="Comment 10"&gt;Otto42&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:9" title="Comment 9"&gt;chipbennett&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Wait, what? I find this response confusing. Either WordPress is distributed 100% GPL or it is not. If WordPress is 100% GPL, then the source-code provision applies to 100% of the code (including erstwhile MIT-licensed code that has been re-licensed as GPL for distribution with WordPress). If WordPress is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; 100% GPL, then don't we have a bigger problem?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You both misunderstand the nature of the GPL, GPL-Compatible, and how licensing works.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Code &lt;strong&gt;cannot&lt;/strong&gt; be "relicensed" by anybody other than the copyright holder. You cannot put licensing terms on code that you do not own, period.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I realized after I hit "submit" that I used a poor choice of phrasing there. I meant "GPL-compatible".
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So we can't "relicense" the SWFUpload code any more than I could take code you released and put my own terms on it and then re-release it. That's theft.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The term "GPL-Compatible" means that the code has licensing terms on it that are equal to or less restrictive than the GPL itself. This means that we can release it as part of a larger work which is GPL. The individual pieces can have their own terms, but the work-as-a-whole is GPL'd.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The terms in section 2 make this clear:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;These requirements apply to the modified work as a whole. If identifiable sections of that work are not derived from the Program, and can be reasonably considered independent and separate works in themselves, then this License, and its terms, do not apply to those sections when you distribute them as separate works. But when you distribute the same sections as part of a whole which is a work based on the Program, the distribution of the whole must be on the terms of this License, whose permissions for other licensees extend to the entire whole, and thus to each and every part regardless of who wrote it.
&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So the GPL applies to WordPress as-a-whole, but not to the individual and independent parts of it, such as SWFUpload, when they are separated out. SWFUpload has not be "re-licensed", it's been included in another work which has a more restrictive license than it itself has.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I think you're misreading that clause. Let's parse:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If identifiable sections of that work are not derived from the Program, and can be reasonably considered independent and separate works in themselves, then this License, and its terms, do not apply to those sections &lt;strong&gt;when you distribute them as separate works&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The binary in question is not being distributed by WordPress &lt;em&gt;as a separate work&lt;/em&gt;, but rather as a component of the whole package. Thus, we must consider the next clause:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But &lt;strong&gt;when you distribute the same sections as part of a whole which is a work based on the Program, the distribution of the whole must be on the terms of this License&lt;/strong&gt;, whose &lt;strong&gt;permissions for other licensees extend&lt;/strong&gt; to the entire whole, and thus &lt;strong&gt;to each and every part&lt;/strong&gt; regardless of who wrote it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
That's pretty clear: GPL &lt;em&gt;permissions for other licensees extend... to each and every part [of the whole]&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Bottom line: whomever is responsible for distributing WordPress (i.e. the WordPress Foundation, or currently more accurately, Matt Mullenweg, as the owner and responsible party for the wordpress.org web site), &lt;em&gt;is under obligation&lt;/em&gt; to provide full source code for 100% of WordPress.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
No, he is not. GPL, Section 3:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;If distribution of executable or object code is made by offering access to copy from a designated place, then offering equivalent access to copy the source code from the same place counts as distribution of the source code, even though third parties are not compelled to copy the source along with the object code.
&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So where is this "designated place" from which WordPress offers for licensees to download source files for the binary in question?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
And that is for the case where the code was GPL to begin with. Which, as I stated before, does not apply to the SWFUpload code as it is not GPL, but MIT licensed. Furthermore, the files accompanying the SWFUpload code give its URL and the place to download it. SWFUpload is included in WordPress in an unmodified format. There are no changes to it that need their source code included.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
*Runs off to check core...*
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Okay, so the link provided goes to the SWFUpload project website, which itself links to a googlecode repository for the code itself. Is the swfupload.swf source file &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://code.google.com/p/swfupload/source/browse/swfupload/trunk/core/Flash"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;somewhere in here&lt;/a&gt;?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
WordPress is being distributed, ostensibly licensed 100% under GPL - and whomever is responsible for that distribution is responsible for fulfilling the terms of the GPL, including full source disclosure.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The GPL makes absolutely no such requirement to begin with. You are misunderstanding the terms.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
No, I'm not. Let me quote them again:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
But &lt;strong&gt;when you distribute the same sections as part of a whole which is a work based on the Program, the distribution of the whole must be on the terms of this License&lt;/strong&gt;, whose &lt;strong&gt;permissions for other licensees extend&lt;/strong&gt; to the entire whole, and thus &lt;strong&gt;to each and every part&lt;/strong&gt; regardless of who wrote it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
SWFUpload is being distributed as part of the whole of a work that is licensed under GPL, and is itself derived from another GPL-licensed work. Thus, the license of the work as a whole, in order to conform to the terms of the license, must extend to the entire whole, and &lt;em&gt;thus to each and every part&lt;/em&gt; of the whole.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Let's say I write a work and release it in object form only. An executable. I then say that that executable is licensed under the GPL. Do I now have to release the source code for it? Absolutely not. It's my work, I wrote it, I own it. I am not under the terms of the GPL, I am making it available to *other people* under those terms.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
That's nice, but not germane. WordPress itself is a derived work. The copyright holder for SWFUpload did not directly contribute the work to WordPress, but rather the work is being &lt;em&gt;redistributed&lt;/em&gt;. So, none of what you just said has any bearing whatsoever on the matter at hand.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I'll state it one more time: WordPress.org (the group doing the releasing of WP) is under no obligation to provide the source code for a work that they have not modified,  and when they have given the location where it may be obtained from the original source, and when it is not GPL licensed to begin with.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I will 100% agree that WordPress is in the clear, &lt;em&gt;if someone can point out where the swfupload.swf source file is made available&lt;/em&gt;. I assume that, if it's available, &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://code.google.com/p/swfupload/source/browse/swfupload/trunk/core/Flash"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;it's here somewhere&lt;/a&gt;?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Which, really, would put a quick end to this ticket.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16579 ($groupby should be set for 'meta_query' too) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>scribu</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 14:26:48 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16579#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16579#comment:2/1297952808019345</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I updated the Codex page. Thanks for reporting.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16579 ($groupby should be set for 'meta_query' too) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>scribu</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 14:26:20 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16579#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16579#comment:1/1297952780814065</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Summary&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Description&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Milestone&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16517 (What about / Whom to ask for full/missing wordpress source-code?) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Otto42</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 13:49:24 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:10</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:10/1297950564469284</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:9" title="Comment 9"&gt;chipbennett&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Wait, what? I find this response confusing. Either WordPress is distributed 100% GPL or it is not. If WordPress is 100% GPL, then the source-code provision applies to 100% of the code (including erstwhile MIT-licensed code that has been re-licensed as GPL for distribution with WordPress). If WordPress is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; 100% GPL, then don't we have a bigger problem?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
You both misunderstand the nature of the GPL, GPL-Compatible, and how licensing works.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Code &lt;strong&gt;cannot&lt;/strong&gt; be "relicensed" by anybody other than the copyright holder. You cannot put licensing terms on code that you do not own, period.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So we can't "relicense" the SWFUpload code any more than I could take code you released and put my own terms on it and then re-release it. That's theft.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The term "GPL-Compatible" means that the code has licensing terms on it that are equal to or less restrictive than the GPL itself. This means that we can release it as part of a larger work which is GPL. The individual pieces can have their own terms, but the work-as-a-whole is GPL'd.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The terms in section 2 make this clear:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;These requirements apply to the modified work as a whole. If identifiable sections of that work are not derived from the Program, and can be reasonably considered independent and separate works in themselves, then this License, and its terms, do not apply to those sections when you distribute them as separate works. But when you distribute the same sections as part of a whole which is a work based on the Program, the distribution of the whole must be on the terms of this License, whose permissions for other licensees extend to the entire whole, and thus to each and every part regardless of who wrote it.
&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So the GPL applies to WordPress as-a-whole, but not to the individual and independent parts of it, such as SWFUpload, when they are separated out. SWFUpload has not be "re-licensed", it's been included in another work which has a more restrictive license than it itself has.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Bottom line: whomever is responsible for distributing WordPress (i.e. the WordPress Foundation, or currently more accurately, Matt Mullenweg, as the owner and responsible party for the wordpress.org web site), &lt;em&gt;is under obligation&lt;/em&gt; to provide full source code for 100% of WordPress.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
No, he is not. GPL, Section 3:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;If distribution of executable or object code is made by offering access to copy from a designated place, then offering equivalent access to copy the source code from the same place counts as distribution of the source code, even though third parties are not compelled to copy the source along with the object code.
&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
And that is for the case where the code was GPL to begin with. Which, as I stated before, does not apply to the SWFUpload code as it is not GPL, but MIT licensed. Furthermore, the files accompanying the SWFUpload code give its URL and the place to download it. SWFUpload is included in WordPress in an unmodified format. There are no changes to it that need their source code included.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
WordPress is being distributed, ostensibly licensed 100% under GPL - and whomever is responsible for that distribution is responsible for fulfilling the terms of the GPL, including full source disclosure.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The GPL makes absolutely no such requirement to begin with. You are misunderstanding the terms.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Let's say I write a work and release it in object form only. An executable. I then say that that executable is licensed under the GPL. Do I now have to release the source code for it? Absolutely not. It's my work, I wrote it, I own it. I am not under the terms of the GPL, I am making it available to *other people* under those terms.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I'll state it one more time: WordPress.org (the group doing the releasing of WP) is under no obligation to provide the source code for a work that they have not modified,  and when they have given the location where it may be obtained from the original source, and when it is not GPL licensed to begin with.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16578 (TinyMCE plugins are not loaded as .dev.js when SCRIPT_DEBUG is enabled) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>solarissmoke</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 13:31:40 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16578#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16578#comment:2/1297949500179492</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
No, there are only a couple of TinyMCE plugins loaded using script-loader.php, and that's because they have dependencies. The rest are loaded differently, and that's where the issue it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Try any of the other TinyMCE plugins: wpeditimage, wordpress, inlinepopups, spellchecker, tabfocus etc.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>query.patch attached to Ticket #16579</title>
      
        <dc:creator>kerekesjoco</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 13:23:06 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/16579/query.patch</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/16579/query.patch/1297948986709627</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16578 (TinyMCE plugins are not loaded as .dev.js when SCRIPT_DEBUG is enabled) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>kawauso</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 13:17:25 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16578#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16578#comment:1/1297948645701005</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
All the instances in core of TinyMCE plugin loading I could find use the &lt;code&gt;$suffix&lt;/code&gt; variable, which add &lt;code&gt;.dev&lt;/code&gt; as necessary. Couldn't reproduce on my trunk install either.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/browser/trunk/wp-includes/script-loader.php#L268"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://core.trac.wordpress.org/browser/trunk/wp-includes/script-loader.php#L268&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16579 ($groupby should be set for 'meta_query' too) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>kerekesjoco</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 12:38:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16579</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16579/1297946330869621</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
See patch.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16517 (What about / Whom to ask for full/missing wordpress source-code?) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>chipbennett</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 12:31:23 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:9</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:9/1297945883169156</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:5" title="Comment 5"&gt;Otto42&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Firstly, the only binary file I can find any reference to is SWFUpload, and that is MIT Licensed, not GPL. The MIT License has no requirement for providing source code.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Wait, what? I find this response confusing. Either WordPress is distributed 100% GPL or it is not. If WordPress is 100% GPL, then the source-code provision applies to 100% of the code (including erstwhile MIT-licensed code that has been re-licensed as GPL for distribution with WordPress). If WordPress is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; 100% GPL, then don't we have a bigger problem?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As for the GPL, we are under no obligation to provide anything at all.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
That depends on who &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; are? You are correct, if by &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; you are referring to the individual code contributors. However, I didn't see the ticket call out by name you or any other specific code contributor - and quite frankly, trying to divert the point at hand away from the WordPress project to the individual contributors is less-than-helpful.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Bottom line: whomever is responsible for distributing WordPress (i.e. the WordPress Foundation, or currently more accurately, Matt Mullenweg, as the owner and responsible party for the wordpress.org web site), &lt;em&gt;is under obligation&lt;/em&gt; to provide full source code for 100% of WordPress.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Understand that the people here wrote the code and share a joint ownership of it. The GPL places no obligation whatsoever on the actual copyright holders of the code. They can release it anyway they like. The GPL only applies to licensees of the code in question; the downstream people using and redistributing that code.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Downstream&lt;/em&gt; is not required, but rather only &lt;em&gt;distribution&lt;/em&gt;. WordPress is being distributed, ostensibly licensed 100% under GPL - and whomever is responsible for that distribution is responsible for fulfilling the terms of the GPL, including full source disclosure.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;There is no requirement for WordPress to release the source code for a single binary file which they did not write and which is not GPL licensed to begin with.&lt;/strong&gt; Your argument is invalid.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I can't believe you actually just said that.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16578 (TinyMCE plugins are not loaded as .dev.js when SCRIPT_DEBUG is enabled) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>solarissmoke</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 06:58:15 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16578</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16578/1297925895499294</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
In trunk, when SCRIPT_DEBUG is enabled, TinyMCE does not load plugins using  &lt;code&gt;.dev.js&lt;/code&gt; scripts. It would be nice if it did.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #14380 (Caption shortcode inserts inline style forcing width of containing div) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>solarissmoke</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 06:21:55 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/14380#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/14380#comment:3/1297923715408900</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
First pass at a fix is attached.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Taking away the width property causes "alignnone" captions to fill the whole width of the container. I have fixed this by modifying the style in TwentyTen, but this may have unintended consequences, so needs to be tested.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I realised while doing this that SCRIPT_DEBUG does load .dev scripts for tinyMCE plugins - you have to switch them round manually, which is a bit messy. I might open another ticket to see if this can be changed.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>14380.diff attached to Ticket #14380</title>
      
        <dc:creator>solarissmoke</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 06:20:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/14380/14380.diff</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/14380/14380.diff/1297923650301356</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16380 (Whitespace missing between strings) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>solarissmoke</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 04:18:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16380#comment:5</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16380#comment:5/1297916330690340</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
That makes sense
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16134 (Check capabilities/role before adding comment links to email) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>solarissmoke</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 04:18:18 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16134#comment:5</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16134#comment:5/1297916298157693</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16134#comment:4" title="Comment 4"&gt;tislam100&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I tried your patch by making a plugin. Now, whenever I post a comment I get a blank page.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Works fine for me. Are you using trunk?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16577 (The register_setting function doesn't exist in Network Admin area) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>cgrymala</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 02:21:26 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16577</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16577/1297909286676105</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
In the 3.0.x branch of WordPress, plugin authors could use the &lt;code&gt;register_setting()&lt;/code&gt; function to whitelist either individual site options (the 'options' table) or network options (the 'sitemeta' table). If a network option was registered using the &lt;code&gt;register_setting()&lt;/code&gt; function, calling &lt;code&gt;add_site_option()&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;update_site_option()&lt;/code&gt; would invoke the sanitization callback included in the &lt;code&gt;register_setting()&lt;/code&gt; function.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
However, in the current trunk version of WordPress 3.1, the &lt;code&gt;register_setting()&lt;/code&gt; function is not instantiated when working within the Network Admin area. In my case, I've chosen to use &lt;code&gt;add_filter( 'sanitize_option_' . $plugin_name, 'plugin_sanitize_callback' );&lt;/code&gt; instead.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I'm not sure if this is intended behavior or not. If the &lt;code&gt;register_setting()&lt;/code&gt; function is supposed to be available when working on settings within the Network Admin area, hopefully it will be easy to fix. If that function is not supposed to be available, please feel free to ignore this ticket.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Either way, the codex entries for the various functions probably should be updated to include definitive information about whether the sanitize callback will be invoked automatically for Network options or not.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #8775 (Numbers in quotation marks get wrong smart quotes) reopened</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Viper007Bond</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 01:40:21 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8775#comment:17</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/8775#comment:17/1297906821893478</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
It's still a valid issue. Just because progress isn't being made isn't reason enough to close the ticket.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>reopenedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Changeset [17464]: Bump</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 01:31:56 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/17464</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/17464/1297906316840442</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Bump
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>changeset</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Changeset [17463]: Bump</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 01:30:56 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/17463</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/17463/1297906256290218</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Bump
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>changeset</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #16517 (What about / Whom to ask for full/missing wordpress source-code?) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>hakre</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 00:18:17 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:8</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:8/1297901897454649</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/16517#comment:5" title="Comment 5"&gt;Otto42&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Understand that the people here wrote the code and share a joint ownership of it. The GPL places no obligation whatsoever on the actual copyright holders of the code. They can release it anyway they like. The GPL only applies to licensees of the code in question; the downstream people using and redistributing that code.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Pardon?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Maybe you have just overlooked that the package forked from b2/cafelog? And that the actual copyright holder of the code includes contributors whose code got used by project members to add it to the software?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item>
   </channel>
</rss>