<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>WordPress Trac</title>
    <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/timeline</link>
    <description>Trac Timeline</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <generator>Trac 1.2.2</generator>
    <image>
      <title>WordPress Trac</title>
      <url>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/chrome/site/your_project_logo.png</url>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/timeline</link>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>Ticket #41612 ("URL" field in Media Modal confusing for newer users) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>afercia</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 19:16:13 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/41612#comment:7</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/41612#comment:7/1517080573496623</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Related: &lt;a class="reviewing ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43169" title="#43169: defect (bug): Media views: avoid to move focus programmatically when not strictly ... (reviewing)"&gt;#43169&lt;/a&gt; (for the focus issue)
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43169 (Media views: avoid to move focus programmatically when not strictly ...) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>afercia</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 19:15:33 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43169#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43169#comment:1/1517080533038255</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Partially related: &lt;a class="new ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/41612" title="#41612: enhancement: &amp;#34;URL&amp;#34; field in Media Modal confusing for newer users (new)"&gt;#41612&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43169 (Media views: avoid to move focus programmatically when not strictly ...) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>afercia</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 19:13:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43169</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43169/1517080430081770</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Ideally, focus should be managed programmatically only to "repair" the native tab order and avoid focus losses. For example, when opening a modal dialog focus needs to be moved to the modal and when closing it, focus must be moved back to the control that opened the modal.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In the media views, in many cases, moving focus is designed for a mouse-based interaction flow and, generally, it appears it was designed with a specific workflow in mind, that is: the workflow the developers felt was "right". In other words: based on assumptions.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
While I understand the intent was good, this is very problematic for keyboard users. Let's make a couple examples:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a style="padding:0; border:none" href="https://cldup.com/SpSTMrgvdn.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://cldup.com/SpSTMrgvdn.png" alt="https://cldup.com/SpSTMrgvdn.png" crossorigin="anonymous" title="https://cldup.com/SpSTMrgvdn.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
When adding an attachment to a post, for example selecting an image in the media grid, focus is moved to the URL field in the details sidebar. This is not an issue for mouse users: they can click another image at any time. Now, say a keyboard users is trying to add a gallery and needs to select multiple images: every time the user selects an image pressing the Spacebar, focus goes to the sidebar. Now the user is forced to tab many times, potentially hundreds of times depending on the number of images in the grid, to go to the grid again and select another image. Not to mention screen reader users will hardly understand why the context is changed and what the next step is.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In this case, focus should just stay in place on the selected image. It is far better to avoid an abrupt change of context rather than assuming that moving focus to the URL field is of any help for users.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
One more example:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a style="padding:0; border:none" href="https://cldup.com/xmCQcKmGST.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://cldup.com/xmCQcKmGST.png" alt="https://cldup.com/xmCQcKmGST.png" crossorigin="anonymous" title="https://cldup.com/xmCQcKmGST.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Over time, the media modal has been adapted and used also for other core features. In the screenshot above, that is what happens when editing an image attached to an Image widget in the widgets screen. Focus is moved to the URL field, if the image is linked (when it's not linked, there's no URL field displayed). Notice this happens only the first time the modal opens, not sure why.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Regardless, for keyboard and screen reader users big part of the content of the modal gets "skipped" and they land in the middle of some content without any context or meaningful information about what just happened.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I'd like to propose to remove any focus management from the media views, except for the cases where keeping focus within the modal is necessary. It is far better to keep the native tab order: users will find their way, once they learn how the interface is structured. Worth reminding assistive technologies users already have tools to jump to different part of the content, if the content is semantic and well structured.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I'd also like to quote what the React team states in their documentation dedicated to accessibility, they say it very well, far better than I could ever say:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class="ext-link" href="https://reactjs.org/docs/accessibility.html#programmatically-managing-focus"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;https://reactjs.org/docs/accessibility.html#programmatically-managing-focus&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Use it (Ed. focus management) to repair the keyboard focus flow when it is disturbed, &lt;strong&gt;not to try and anticipate how users want to use applications&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>iris picker z-index.png attached to Ticket #43168</title>
      
        <dc:creator>crstnio</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 18:58:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/43168/iris%20picker%20z-index.png</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/43168/iris%20picker%20z-index.png/1517079526147780</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Iris color picker handle z-index bug
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43168 (Customizer: Iris color picker handle above section title) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>crstnio</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 18:58:05 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43168</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43168/1517079485085770</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
When Iris color picker is opened, the handle displays bevor the section title – if section is visible during scroll-up.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Section title styles:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;#customize-controls .customize-info.is-in-view,
#customize-controls .customize-section-title.is-in-view {
    z-index: 9;
}
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Handle styles:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;.iris-picker .iris-square-handle {
    z-index: 10;
}
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43167 (Unable to install worpress, error on wp-admin/setup-config.php) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>irecinius</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 18:47:43 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43167</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43167/1517078863649799</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Install Step 2: fails with message
"WordPress database error Unknown column 'wp_' in 'field list' for query SELECT wp_"
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
MYSQL -&amp;gt; SELECT VERSION();
RESPONSE -&amp;gt; '5.6.38-83.0-log'
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Bug:
Setup-Config@L310
&lt;a class="ext-link" href="https://github.com/WordPress/WordPress/blob/master/wp-admin/setup-config.php#L310"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;https://github.com/WordPress/WordPress/blob/master/wp-admin/setup-config.php#L310&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Running the query:
$wpdb-&amp;gt;query( "SELECT $prefix" );
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
MYSQL -&amp;gt; SELECT wp_
RESPONSE -&amp;gt; Error Code: 1054. Unknown column 'wp_' in 'field list'
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Observations, query fails regardless if prefix exists or not, tested on a working database, same query fails with same message
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43166 (4.9 broke uploaded images' paths on my network installation) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>pasqal</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 18:05:07 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43166</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43166/1517076307440273</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I run a network installation. I upgraded from 4.8.2 to 4.9 back in December but found out that images were broken on all of my network's sites.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
My network's sites are as follows:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Site 1: &lt;a class="ext-link" href="https://www.mybrand.com/es/blog/"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;https://www.mybrand.com/es/blog/&lt;/a&gt;
Site 2: &lt;a class="ext-link" href="https://www.mybrand.com/en/blog/"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;https://www.mybrand.com/en/blog/&lt;/a&gt;
Site 3: &lt;a class="ext-link" href="https://www.mybrand.co.uk/en/blog/"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;https://www.mybrand.co.uk/en/blog/&lt;/a&gt;
Site 4: &lt;a class="ext-link" href="https://www.mybrand.it/it/blog/"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;https://www.mybrand.it/it/blog/&lt;/a&gt;
etc.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
4.9 converts a 4.8.2 working image URL on Site 1, such as:
&lt;a class="ext-link" href="https://www.mybrand.com/es/blog/wp-content/uploads/sites/1/2016/09/image.jpg"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;https://www.mybrand.com/es/blog/wp-content/uploads/sites/1/2016/09/image.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
...into the following non-existent URL:
&lt;a class="ext-link" href="https://www.mybrand.com/es/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/image.jpg"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;https://www.mybrand.com/es/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/image.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
... thus resulting in a 404 response for the image load.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Since I had upgraded some plugins together with the Wordpress core, what I tried first was deactivating those, with no success. So I ended up downgrading the core back to 4.8.2, which fixed the bug.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Last week I again tried upgrading to 4.9.2, with the same result (the image bug is still there). This time I downgraded to 4.8.5, which works fine.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
All sites use the Twenty Sixteen template.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
My current install includes the following plugins at the network level:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;AddToAny Share Buttons Version 1.7.23
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;All In One SEO Pack Version 2.4.4.1
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Autoptimize Version 2.3.2
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Broken Link Checker Version 1.11.5
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Custom Meta Widget Version 1.4.8
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Custom Permalinks Version 1.2.12
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Customize Login Image Version 3.3.1
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Disable REST API Version 1.4.2
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;External Links Version 6.8.1
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Google Analytics for WordPress by MonsterInsights Version 6.2.7
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Google Captcha (reCAPTCHA) by BestWebSoft Version 1.33
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;HREFLANG Tags Lite Version 1.5.6 | By DCGWS
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Jetpack by WordPress.com Version 5.7.1
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;kk Star Ratings Version 2.6
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Simple 301 Redirects Version 1.07
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;W3 Total Cache Version 0.9.6
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;wBounce Version 1.8
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;WordPress Importer Version 0.6.3
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;WP Downgrade Version 1.1.4
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;WP Login Flow Version 1.0.0
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;WP Rollback Version 1.5
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I actually installed WP Downgrade and WP Rollback after 4.9 broke my installation, to help downgrade to a working version.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
All templates and plugins are up to date.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43163 (Did you know? CSS notification needs a Dismiss button to close) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>afercia</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 17:08:09 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43163#comment:5</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43163#comment:5/1517072889349931</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Although @pracko makes a point when says experienced users don't need a persistent reminder and argues that editing in the 253 pixels wide (!) editor in the Customizer is any better than using the classic theme editor (well actually this depends on the use cases), going through &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/42100" title="#42100: task (blessed): File editor warning copy / UI tweaks (closed: fixed)"&gt;#42100&lt;/a&gt; and looking a bit at WordPress history, there are other cases of persistent notices or other persistent "hints". I'd rather point out that there's no consistency though:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a style="padding:0; border:none" href="https://cldup.com/PjW6Q2vxnC.png"&gt;&lt;img src="https://cldup.com/PjW6Q2vxnC.png" alt="https://cldup.com/PjW6Q2vxnC.png" crossorigin="anonymous" title="https://cldup.com/PjW6Q2vxnC.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Designconsistency"&gt;Design consistency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I'm not sure why the Editor screen uses the new notice, while the Widgets and Menus screens use the "Manage with Live Preview" button (which I always found not so nice looking, to be fair). Historically, the persistent notices have been used for pages that were going to be dismissed, or their usage discouraged, like the Custom Header and Custom Background pages. For pages still in use, the choice has been the less invasive "Manage" button.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I'm pretty sure there were good argumentation when these buttons and notices were introduced but now it's probably time to try to introduce some consistency and improve things. Consistency is key. I'd lean towards the notices just because the buttons bother me, and I'd prefer to have the main heading on its own reserved space, without any additional element close to it. But that's just my personal preference.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="Languageconsistency"&gt;Language consistency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
What is the proper name to use for the Customizer? As a user, I have no idea what a &lt;code&gt;built-in CSS editor&lt;/code&gt; is. And I have no idea clicking on a link that says &lt;code&gt;built-in CSS editor&lt;/code&gt; actually brings me to the Customizer. Links purpose/destination should always be clear, even when the link is read out of context. The link text should include the word "Customizer" or "Live Preview" or whatever the hte Customizer should be named.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I seem to recall there was a long discussion when the "Manage" buttons were introduced, focused on avoiding to use the word "Customizer". I guess that's the reason why the buttons use "Live Preview" with title case: to indicate the name of a WordPress feature. However, the old Custom Header/Background pages use "Customizer". I'd agree this is a minor case since these pages are hidden by default. By the way, the word "Customizer" is now used in a very prominent place: the 4.9 About page:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Major Customizer Improvements, Code Error Checking, and More!&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Welcome to an improved Customizer workflow ...&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Customizer Workflow Improved&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Customizer JS API Improvements&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;code&gt;We’ve made numerous improvements to the Customizer JS API ...&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I'm not a native English speaker and I do know "Customizer" is very difficult to translate. In the Italian translation, it's always translated with "Personalizza", which is the verb imperative mood "Customize" and I can tell you that's far from ideal. On the other hand, any Italian people I talk with, they call it with the English word "Customizer" because that just makes more sense. In my country, we're not opposed to using non-italian terms, when that makes sense. However, this may not apply to other countries and cultures. A more generic term like "Live Preview" might be a better option. Regardless of the final choice, there should be some consistency in the interface. Right now, WordPress is using both "Live Preview" and "Customizer", which is confusing for users.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Minor: does "live preview" needs a hyphen when used as a verb? There's no consistency here either:
&lt;code&gt;There’s no need to change your CSS here — you can edit and live preview CSS changes in the built-in CSS editor.&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;code&gt;You can now manage and live-preview Custom Header in the Customizer.&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I do realize the considerations about naming are a bit out of the scope of this ticket, glad to create a new one if there's consensus.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
/cc @melchoyce @helen
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #39242 (Add caching to count_user_posts()) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>milindmore22</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 12:51:52 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/39242#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/39242#comment:2/1517057512138321</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Focuses&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Yes, performances of websites using REST is highly affected.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I have added a patch based on WP VIP function below.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="wiki-code"&gt;&lt;div class="code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;?php&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="sd"&gt;/**
 * Cached version of count_user_posts, which is uncached but doesn't always need to hit the db
 *
 * count_user_posts is generally fast, but it can be easy to end up with many redundant queries
 * if it's called several times per request. This allows bypassing the db queries in favor of
 * the cache
 */&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;wpcom_vip_count_user_posts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$user_id&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;!&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;is_numeric&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$user_id&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$cache_key&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'vip_'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;int&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$user_id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$cache_group&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'user_posts_count'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;false&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;===&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$count&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;wp_cache_get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$cache_key&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$cache_group&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$count&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;count_user_posts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$user_id&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="nx"&gt;wp_cache_set&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$cache_key&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$count&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$cache_group&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;MINUTE_IN_SECONDS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$count&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Do we need proper cache invalidation or  5 Min expiration timeout will do ?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I think we should handle this in 5.0 thoughts ?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>39242.diff attached to Ticket #39242</title>
      
        <dc:creator>milindmore22</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 12:45:24 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/39242/39242.diff</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/39242/39242.diff/1517057124251125</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Cache for count_user_posts
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>contributor-list-issue-with-plugin-details.png attached to Ticket #43165</title>
      
        <dc:creator>alkesh7</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 12:33:43 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/43165/contributor-list-issue-with-plugin-details.png</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/43165/contributor-list-issue-with-plugin-details.png/1517056423668002</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Issue with Contributor list - Showing username instead of name
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43165 (Contributors 'Username' displaying instead of 'Name' with plugin's ...) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>alkesh7</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 12:32:31 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43165</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43165/1517056351279828</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I noticed that there is an issue with showing a list of contributor names with WordPress backend panel.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There might be an issue with Backend API call or variable selection.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Let me explain,
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I picked one plugin &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class="ext-link" href="https://wordpress.org/plugins/blog-designer/"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;Blog Designer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for reference. Just scroll down and check list of &lt;strong&gt;Contributors &amp;amp; Developers&lt;/strong&gt;. You will see that name of those plugin's contributors.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
While, I'm checking that same exact plugin contributor's list on &lt;em&gt;Add New&lt;/em&gt; plugin page within &lt;span class="underline"&gt;WordPress backend panel&lt;/span&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
That showing username of those contributors. Please check attachment for more details.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Please correct the contributor listing call with proper field selection in coding.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #39165 (Add page to assist with debugging and support) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Clorith</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 11:39:57 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/39165#comment:64</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/39165#comment:64/1517053197726612</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Good spots, I was running my test with the plugin active and did not catch the missing class.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Active plugins should be listed, the active theme is more prominent because it's not something you often swap in and out like plugins I presume (the inspiration for that field came from the WooCommerce implementation of their own debug area, that is my understanding of that field at least).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Fixing title cases, relabling the site language bit and the local switch as well as typo are excellent.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As for the loopback checker, I'm wondering if it would make sense to take the loopback test that was put in for the theme and plugin editors and split it into a stand alone function for better reusability? It's currently part of &lt;code&gt;wp_edit_theme_plugin_file()&lt;/code&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #39165 (Add page to assist with debugging and support) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>swissspidy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 11:23:42 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/39165#comment:63</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/39165#comment:63/1517052222348072</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
This is coming along well, thanks @Clorith!
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Some minor notes:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Why is the active theme listed, but not the active plugins
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Minor detail: "Active theme" is written with a small "T", "Inactive Plugins" with a capital "P". I think title case should be used for all sections
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;In this line: &lt;code&gt;( ! empty( $locale ) ? $original_locale : get_locale() )&lt;/code&gt; — &lt;code&gt;$original_locale&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;$locale&lt;/code&gt; are not defined. That's a remnant from the locale switching in the plugin. Just use &lt;code&gt;get_locale()&lt;/code&gt;. And perhaps rename the section to "Site Language" for clarification.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;$loopback = Health_Check_Loopback::can_perform_loopback(); &lt;/code&gt; — the class obviously doesn't exist in core, leading to a fatal error.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Typo: "this is information that may be considers private" -&amp;gt; "considered"
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #39165 (Add page to assist with debugging and support) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Clorith</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 11:20:10 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/39165#comment:62</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/39165#comment:62/1517052010088281</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
You are absolutely right, hazards of copying :)
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>39165.10.patch attached to Ticket #39165</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Clorith</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 11:19:40 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/39165/39165.10.patch</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/39165/39165.10.patch/1517051980522854</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #39165 (Add page to assist with debugging and support) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>joostdevalk</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 11:06:02 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/39165#comment:61</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/39165#comment:61/1517051162183336</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
One thing @Clorith, I think you need to drop the text-domain :-)
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #39165 (Add page to assist with debugging and support) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>joostdevalk</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 11:03:34 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/39165#comment:60</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/39165#comment:60/1517051014853826</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I don't think it should be in the side menu. This looks good to me. @SergeyBiryukov could you have a look?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #38157 (Add tests for get_post_type_labels()) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>swissspidy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 10:22:20 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/38157#comment:8</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/38157#comment:8/1517048540545251</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
@birgire Good call! I haven't closely looked at the tests, but yes, that should generally be avoided. I'll try to have a look at it soon. Perhaps even by going through _all_ tests to improve this.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>not-gettexted-0.mo attached to Ticket #42818</title>
      
        <dc:creator>soulseekah</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 10:10:43 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/42818/not-gettexted-0.mo</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/42818/not-gettexted-0.mo/1517047843656748</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Compiled test translation changes
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #42818 (i18n Tools have PHP 7.2 compatibility issues) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>soulseekah</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 10:08:34 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/42818#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/42818#comment:3/1517047714497594</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Attached two patches that address the issue.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The first patch takes care of makepot.php, the create_function call there simply wraps the input into curly braces, so the fix is simple - move to a function of its own.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The second patch handles the two calls inside not-gettexted.php. Their usage was is a bit tricker, relying on dynamic state, so the functionality was moved into stateful classes, and a method is returned instead of a function.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The second patch also fixes two test issues in not-gettexted:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;A failing case in the replace test: http vs https URLs in the expected result, seems like links to wordpress.org in PHP files were replaced to their secure counterparts but the po/mos were not touched, so the translation was not being found
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;construct vs setUp for initialization on the test case
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;
All tests pass with both patches applied.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>42818.2.diff attached to Ticket #42818</title>
      
        <dc:creator>soulseekah</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 10:01:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/42818/42818.2.diff</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/42818/42818.2.diff/1517047310537872</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>42818.patch attached to Ticket #42818</title>
      
        <dc:creator>soulseekah</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 08:51:47 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/42818/42818.patch</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/42818/42818.patch/1517043107815069</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #39165 (Add page to assist with debugging and support) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Clorith</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 01:04:48 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/39165#comment:59</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/39165#comment:59/1517015088030341</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a class="attachment" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/39165/39165.9.patch" title="Attachment '39165.9.patch' in Ticket #39165"&gt;39165.9.patch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="trac-rawlink" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/raw-attachment/ticket/39165/39165.9.patch" title="Download"&gt;​&lt;/a&gt; Introduces the footer link, basic styling to keep tables aligned for readability and an updated &lt;code&gt;info.php&lt;/code&gt; file that's brought in line with the &lt;code&gt;Debug information&lt;/code&gt;tab in the Health Check plugin at this time.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I'm still not sold on adding it to the side menu in wp-admin, it's not something we hope will need to be directly accessed in such a "grand" manner often, but the footer link works.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>39165.9.patch attached to Ticket #39165</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Clorith</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 01:00:54 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/39165/39165.9.patch</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/39165/39165.9.patch/1517014854461595</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43163 (Did you know? CSS notification needs a Dismiss button to close) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>pracko</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 00:26:15 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43163#comment:4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43163#comment:4/1517012775989013</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43163#comment:3" title="Comment 3"&gt;Clorith&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I am actually in favor of the messages at the top of the editor pages being non-dismissible. We want to encourage users to stick with the tools they're given that will prevent them from accidentally losing the changes they've made.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I am up for hearing arguments for it needing to be dismissible though.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
OK, here's one: the warning takes up too much space. As an experienced designer who knows what he's doing, I don't need a bulky reminder constantly nagging me to use the narrow and virtually unusable CSS editor in the customizer. I want to be able to remove nags when I don't find them useful or applicable to my situation. The warning is helpful, but not necessary to be persistent; therefore it should be dismissable.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #41074 (Create new Dashicons (4.9)) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>netweb</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 23:43:55 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/41074#comment:44</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/41074#comment:44/1517010235879952</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
A new dashicon for [make.wordpress.org/tide Tide] is also being worked on in &lt;a class="ext-link" href="https://github.com/WordPress/dashicons/issues/248"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;dashicons/issues/248&lt;/a&gt;, refreshed patch will also need to include this.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43140 (WordPress does not allow HTML tags in the Name field of Links (blogroll)) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>mdifelice</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 21:33:37 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43140#comment:4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43140#comment:4/1517002417299719</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Sorry @swissspidy. I meant @CRCulver.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43140 (WordPress does not allow HTML tags in the Name field of Links (blogroll)) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>swissspidy</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 21:22:33 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43140#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43140#comment:3/1517001753913325</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Why do you ask me? :-) I merely fixed the spelling in the ticket.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;a href="…" lang="xy"&amp;gt;…&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is totally fine. You don't need an additional &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; inside a link.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Note that the blogroll feature in WordPress is deprecated and as such I don't really see a point in making any changes to it. People are encouraged to use custom nav menus as they are much more flexible.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43140 (WordPress does not allow HTML tags in the Name field of Links (blogroll)) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>mdifelice</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 21:18:32 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43140#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43140#comment:2/1517001512897932</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Hi @swissspidy, it would not achieve the same effect if you include the lang attribute in the A tag that prints the link?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #42814 (PHP 7.2 Warning: ...wp-includes/post-template.php on line 284) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Kelderic</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 21:13:20 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/42814#comment:25</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/42814#comment:25/1517001200439052</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I just ran into this when I began testing with PHP 7.2. In my &amp;lt;head&amp;gt; section of my theme, I call &lt;code&gt;get_the_excerpt&lt;/code&gt; as part of Open Graph meta tags. I have tried passing the post ID using &lt;code&gt;get_the_ID&lt;/code&gt;, and passing &lt;code&gt;$post&lt;/code&gt;, but I can't get rid of the error.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If we add:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="wiki-code"&gt;&lt;div class="code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="x"&gt;if ( ! is_array($pages) ) {
        $pages = [];
}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;
At line 283 of post-template.php, we correct the issue. Long term, we need to check that all expected arrays are really arrays, and convert &lt;code&gt;NULL&lt;/code&gt; values to empty arrays before calling &lt;code&gt;count()&lt;/code&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #42987 (is_active_sidebar returns true on after plugin deactivation) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>mdifelice</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 21:12:12 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/42987#comment:6</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/42987#comment:6/1517001132914064</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
The &lt;code&gt;retrieve_widgets()&lt;/code&gt; documentation says it &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://core.trac.wordpress.org/browser/tags/4.8/src/wp-includes/widgets.php#L1100"&gt;has to run at least on each theme change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Should not be called when a plugin is deactivated too?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>link-template.php.diff attached to Ticket #43164</title>
      
        <dc:creator>mt8.biz</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 20:49:34 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/43164/link-template.php.diff</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/43164/link-template.php.diff/1516999774495537</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43164 (Function Description : wp-includes/link-template.php) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>mt8.biz</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 20:49:22 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43164</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43164/1516999762072855</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
There is no descrption for global vars
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43163 (Did you know? CSS notification needs a Dismiss button to close) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Clorith</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 20:40:10 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43163#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43163#comment:3/1516999210197602</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Version&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
I am actually in favor of the messages at the top of the editor pages being non-dismissible. We want to encourage users to stick with the tools they're given that will prevent them from accidentally losing the changes they've made.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
See &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/42100" title="#42100: task (blessed): File editor warning copy / UI tweaks (closed: fixed)"&gt;#42100&lt;/a&gt; for discussions on the various warnings shown, and &lt;a class="changeset" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/changeset/42013" title="Code Editors: Add a persistent notification on CSS files, encouraging ..."&gt;r42013&lt;/a&gt; which makes a specific mention of it being intentionally persistent.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I am up for hearing arguments for it needing to be dismissible though.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43160 (Reduce wp-admin/update-core.php load time by half) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>lano1106</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 20:26:19 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43160#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43160#comment:1/1516998379929630</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Hi, I have new info concerning my wp-admin/update-core.php slowness issue. It is caused by the plugin Ad Inserter Pro (author contacted) who does this:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="wiki-code"&gt;&lt;div class="code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;?php&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nx"&gt;add_filter&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'http_headers_useragent'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'ai_http_headers_useragent'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;ai_http_headers_useragent&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$useragent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$useragent&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;get_bloginfo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'url'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;span class="k"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$useragent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This appears to disrupt all the other premium plugins when they contact their servers to check the license validity. One of the things that they do remotely is to authenticate the request by checking the user-agent header field. By messing with it, it disrupts a LOT of stuff. and makes a lot of things VERY slow.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
http_headers_useragent filter hook appears to be VERY VERY risky hook...
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43162 (Deleting a site from a multisite network leaves orphaned database ...) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>johnjamesjacoby</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 19:12:10 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43162#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43162#comment:2/1516993930737552</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Version&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Type&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Hey @bluep92877, thanks for opening this issue up, and congrats on your first ticket here on WordPress Trac.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I think you've brought up good points, and these are all areas where clarification and improvements are necessary.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Re: &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/30673" title="#30673: enhancement: plugin uninstall.php not called when multisite site is deleted (closed: wontfix)"&gt;#30673&lt;/a&gt;, I agree that "uninstall" in the context of a multisite installation implies that all relevant data is removed from all sites, which seems heavy handed under most circumstances, though I can imagine why that might be necessary.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Plugins can (and should) use the &lt;code&gt;wpmu_drop_tables&lt;/code&gt; filter to add their custom database tables to the array of tables that are dropped when a site is deleted.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Database tables and Uploads are both pretty sacred, IMO. If we are deleting one, we can safely delete the other. Dropping large database tables can be costly on the database server in a similar fashion to unlinking a directory. It looks like &lt;code&gt;wpmu_delete_blog()&lt;/code&gt; does try to delete both the database tables and the uploads directory. Maybe something is wrong with the &lt;code&gt;$drop&lt;/code&gt; logic, or something else is in the way?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
That said, permanent deletion is so scary; I'm always hesitant to give anyone that power (even super admins.) 1 click to ruin it all is a lot of responsibility, even 2 or 3 clicks with warning signs and notices.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I think erring on the side of caution here is OK. Only delete stuff if we are 100% certain it's OK to do so, and leave it untouched if there is any doubt. This might result in orphaned tables or files, but I think that's better than blindly deleting them without explicit say-so.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I guess, now that I type this, we could (should) do a quick check on that &lt;code&gt;delete-site&lt;/code&gt; confirmation screen that says "Here are all of the database tables this site has, and it contains 2GB of uploads. Are you sure you want to delete all of this stuff?"
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43162 (Deleting a site from a multisite network leaves orphaned database ...) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>mdifelice</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 18:51:18 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43162#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43162#comment:1/1516992678320248</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Hello. I do think that when you uninstall a plugin it will only delete the tables that it created for that specific site. Of course it depends on the plugin, and whether the plugin was network activated or only activated on the specific site.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Either way, I think that it would be a good addition what you propose. About the tables, it would be nice if WP listed all those orphan tables before deleting the site and ask the user what to do with them: delete or keep them.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
About the media files, I think that each site has a particular folder assigned to them, and simply deleting it it would remove all the associated media.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Another doubt that I have is whether WP really deletes a site or it keeps like in a hidden status. Because if that is the case the idea is that the site could be recover at any time and in those cases files and extra tables should be kept.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Regards.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43163 (Did you know? CSS notification needs a Dismiss button to close) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>pracko</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 18:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43163#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43163#comment:2/1516992420181071</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Thanks JB, very helpful!
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #30359 (Widget Areas should stick to the browser viewport) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>ajensen</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 18:30:54 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/30359#comment:13</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/30359#comment:13/1516991454716722</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/30359#comment:12" title="Comment 12"&gt;sboisvert&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I had a few questions :)
When I look at the patch I see some blank lines being added. Was this intentional?
Can you elaborate on the decision to put the CSS inside widgets.php? Are there other places that might be suitable?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Thanks so much for the feedback @sboisvert! To answer your questions...
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
No, those blank lines were not intentional, opps.  Also, I decided to place the CSS in the widgets.php in response to @srikat's comment "We can do this easily by loading the following CSS on the /wp-admin/widgets.php page" However, another more fitting place would be in the widgets.css placed properly amongst the other media queries.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Lastly, I definitely think some JS is feasible. I'll be attempting @dd32's suggestion shortly.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>62ca30cd95993aa19d7d15674309ab8c.gif attached to Ticket #43163</title>
      
        <dc:creator>audrasjb</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 17:49:50 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/43163/62ca30cd95993aa19d7d15674309ab8c.gif</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/43163/62ca30cd95993aa19d7d15674309ab8c.gif/1516988990950659</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Dismissible notice
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43163 (Did you know? CSS notification needs a Dismiss button to close) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>audrasjb</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 17:49:12 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43163#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43163#comment:1/1516988952266876</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Hi @pracko
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Thanks for your issue.
I fixed it by adding &lt;code&gt;is-dismissible&lt;/code&gt; class to this notice.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Cheers,
Jb
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>43163.diff attached to Ticket #43163</title>
      
        <dc:creator>audrasjb</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 17:46:19 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/43163/43163.diff</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/43163/43163.diff/1516988779429175</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Add is-dismissible class to "Did you know?" notice
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43159 (Introduce helper function for XMLRPC checks) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>birgire</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 17:40:12 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43159#comment:3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43159#comment:3/1516988412569727</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43159#comment:2" title="Comment 2"&gt;NathanAtmoz&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I don't see &lt;code&gt;wp_doing_xmlrpc()&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;wp-cron.php&lt;/code&gt; in the patch? Am I missing something?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This part was meant to be a general note why it wasn't replaced in &lt;code&gt;wp-cron.php&lt;/code&gt;, sorry that wasn't made more clear ;-)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I also checked in the &lt;code&gt;tests/&lt;/code&gt; directory and didn't find any use of &lt;code&gt;XMLRPC_REQUEST&lt;/code&gt; there.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43163 (Did you know? CSS notification needs a Dismiss button to close) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>pracko</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 17:09:30 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43163</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43163/1516986570106190</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
The CSS notification bar at the top of the Edit Themes editor needs a Dismiss button so that it can be closed.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The notification bar I'm referring to says:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
Did you know?
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There’s no need to change your CSS here — you can edit and live preview CSS changes in the built-in CSS editor.&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>43159.2.diff attached to Ticket #43159</title>
      
        <dc:creator>NathanAtmoz</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 17:04:37 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/43159/43159.2.diff</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/43159/43159.2.diff/1516986277242297</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43159 (Introduce helper function for XMLRPC checks) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>NathanAtmoz</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 17:04:17 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43159#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43159#comment:2/1516986257818931</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
@birgire: Thanks for looking at the patch.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Replying to &lt;a class="ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43159#comment:1" title="Comment 1"&gt;birgire&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I don't think we should add &lt;code&gt;wp_doing_xmlrpc()&lt;/code&gt; in that line in &lt;code&gt;wp-cron.php&lt;/code&gt;, because that file can be requested directly, (see e.g. within &lt;code&gt;spawn_cron()&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href="https://core.trac.wordpress.org/browser/tags/4.9/src/wp-includes/cron.php#L353"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; ) and then &lt;code&gt;wp_doing_xmlrpc()&lt;/code&gt; wouldn't be defined and resulting in a PHP error.  Some users rely on Unix Cron instead, requesting that file from there.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I don't see &lt;code&gt;wp_doing_xmlrpc()&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;wp-cron.php&lt;/code&gt; in the patch? Am I missing something?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="citation"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I found an extra &lt;code&gt;defined( 'XMLRPC_REQUEST' )&lt;/code&gt; check in &lt;code&gt;spawn_cron()&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href="https://core.trac.wordpress.org/browser/tags/4.9/src/wp-includes/cron.php#L275"&gt;src&lt;/a&gt;), but I noticed that &lt;code&gt;defined( 'DOING_AJAX' )&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;defined( 'DOING_CRON' )&lt;/code&gt; have not been replaced. Most likely a reason for that, but we could look further into that.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I originally didn't use &lt;code&gt;wp_doing_xmlrpc()&lt;/code&gt; here because the other constants hadn't been replaced. But this function is loaded really early, and the only place it's called in core is hooked to &lt;code&gt;init&lt;/code&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43148 (Email domain whitelist checks should be case-insensitive) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>greatislander</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 16:56:22 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43148#comment:4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43148#comment:4/1516985782099251</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43162 (Deleting a site from a multisite network leaves orphaned database ...) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>bluep92877</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 16:15:02 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43162</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43162/1516983302562428</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Looking at the table structure of a typical multisite install, I see that tables for individual sites within the network are prefixed with wp_{siteid}_ tablename. When I delete a site from the from the network, all standard WP tables for that particular site ID are deleted; however, several plugin tables are not.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As well, looking at the uploads/sites directory, the directory for that site (represented by its ID) is also still there along with all its files (media and other uploads).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
an earlier &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/30673" title="#30673: enhancement: plugin uninstall.php not called when multisite site is deleted (closed: wontfix)"&gt;ticket:30673&lt;/a&gt; suggested that this should be caught when uninstalling a plugin from the master site. But, I'd have to disagree. Most uninstall scripts use a type of {TABLEPREFIX} before its table names. This would delete the tables for every site in the network, wouldn't it? and that's not what the goal would be.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Aside from the plugin issue are the media files that are also orphaned. Media file uploads is part of core, and that's not something a plugin author could approach.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
When deleting a site from the network, this is irrevocable. Wordpress even create an extra confirmation page upon delete saying so just to make sure. If that's the case, and this is by design, what's the point of keeping these extra files and tables if they are never going to be used again?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Shouldn't all site specific db tables and all files in the uploads directory be deleted when a site is deleted? Or, perhaps as an enhancement, on the Delete Site confirmation page, could we have two checkboxes: "1) delete all tables associated with this site" and "2) delete all files associated with this site"
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Currently I have a script setup to alert me as to when a site is deleted. I then open up a cli to manually delete the db tables for that install, and then its files from the uploads directory.  This doesn't feel like the intended workflow to handle the orphaned elements of the site.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43159 (Introduce helper function for XMLRPC checks) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>birgire</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 14:55:10 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43159#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43159#comment:1/1516978510242769</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Thanks for the patch @NathanAtmoz
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I'm not sure what the consensus is regarding &lt;code&gt;wp_doing_xmlrpc()&lt;/code&gt; but we now have &lt;code&gt;wp_doing_ajax()&lt;/code&gt; since 4.7 and &lt;code&gt;wp_doing_cron()&lt;/code&gt; since 4.8. So it would seem logical to introduce it. Also the discussion in &lt;a class="closed ticket" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/25669" title="#25669: enhancement: Introduce helper function for AJAX checks (closed: fixed)"&gt;#25669&lt;/a&gt; doesn't seems to be against such a function, if I understand it correctly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I reviewed &lt;a class="attachment" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/43159/43159.diff" title="Attachment '43159.diff' in Ticket #43159"&gt;43159.diff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="trac-rawlink" href="http://core.trac.wordpress.org/raw-attachment/ticket/43159/43159.diff" title="Download"&gt;​&lt;/a&gt; and here are some notes:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;I don't think we should add &lt;code&gt;wp_doing_xmlrpc()&lt;/code&gt; in that line in &lt;code&gt;wp-cron.php&lt;/code&gt;, because that file can be requested directly, (see e.g. within &lt;code&gt;spawn_cron()&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href="https://core.trac.wordpress.org/browser/tags/4.9/src/wp-includes/cron.php#L353"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; ) and then &lt;code&gt;wp_doing_xmlrpc()&lt;/code&gt; wouldn't be defined and resulting in a PHP error.  Some users rely on Unix Cron instead, requesting that file from there.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It removes the &lt;code&gt;|| defined( 'DOING_AJAX' )&lt;/code&gt; check in &lt;code&gt;is_admin_bar_showing()&lt;/code&gt;. I think that removal must have been accidental and should be reverted.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I found an extra &lt;code&gt;defined( 'XMLRPC_REQUEST' )&lt;/code&gt; check in &lt;code&gt;spawn_cron()&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href="https://core.trac.wordpress.org/browser/tags/4.9/src/wp-includes/cron.php#L275"&gt;src&lt;/a&gt;), but I noticed that &lt;code&gt;defined( 'DOING_AJAX' )&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;defined( 'DOING_CRON' )&lt;/code&gt; have not been replaced. Most likely a reason for that, but we could look further into that.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I also found an extra &lt;code&gt;defined( 'XMLRPC_REQUEST' )&lt;/code&gt; check in &lt;code&gt;_publish_post_hook()&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href="https://core.trac.wordpress.org/browser/tags/4.9/src/wp-includes/post.php#L6003"&gt;src&lt;/a&gt;), that seems to be valid for replacement with &lt;code&gt;wp_doing_xmlrpc()&lt;/code&gt;.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #40522 (Twenty Seventeen: Youtube videos are left aligned in Safari) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>slackbot</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 14:10:23 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/40522#comment:6</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/40522#comment:6/1516975823359615</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;This ticket was mentioned in &lt;a class="ext-link" href="https://make.wordpress.org/chat/"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; in #forums by zoonini. &lt;a class="ext-link" href="https://wordpress.slack.com/archives/forums/p1516975822000003"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;View the logs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #42814 (PHP 7.2 Warning: ...wp-includes/post-template.php on line 284) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Greg Raven</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 13:32:06 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/42814#comment:24</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/42814#comment:24/1516973526771452</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
I’m seeing the same issue on one of my WordPress sites. When I use any version of PHP up to 7.1, the page is fine. When I switch to 7.2, I get this error message:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="wiki"&gt;Warning: count(): Parameter must be an array or an object that implements Countable in /wp-includes/post-template.php on line 284
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
So, I compared post-template.php from one of my sites that works fine under PHP 7.2 and the one giving me the error. Each is running version 4.9.2 WordPress. However, there are subtle differences between the two post-template.php files! None of the differences is anywhere near line 284, but I’m still baffled how two supposedly identical files can have different content.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>a43160.diff attached to Ticket #43160</title>
      
        <dc:creator>kitchin</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 12:37:39 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/43160/a43160.diff</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/43160/a43160.diff/1516970259905450</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Here it is as a patch against trunk. Not tested.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43161 (add_theme_support('custom-header')) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>netweb</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 08:54:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43161#comment:2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43161#comment:2/1516956886926121</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Milestone&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43161 (add_theme_support('custom-header')) closed</title>
      
        <dc:creator>santipm</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 08:22:25 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43161#comment:1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43161#comment:1/1516954945241067</guid>
      <description>invalid</description>
      <category>closedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43161 (add_theme_support('custom-header')) created</title>
      
        <dc:creator>santipm</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 07:50:02 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43161</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43161/1516953002981301</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
No Working
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="wiki-code"&gt;&lt;div class="code"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="cp"&gt;&amp;lt;?php&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$defaults&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;array&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'default-image'&lt;/span&gt;          &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;''&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'width'&lt;/span&gt;                  &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'height'&lt;/span&gt;                 &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'flex-height'&lt;/span&gt;            &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'flex-width'&lt;/span&gt;             &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'uploads'&lt;/span&gt;                &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'random-default'&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'header-text'&lt;/span&gt;            &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'default-text-color'&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'#000'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'wp-head-callback'&lt;/span&gt;       &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'_entro'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'admin-head-callback'&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'admin_header_style'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                        &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'admin-preview-callback'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;''&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nx"&gt;add_theme_support&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'custom-header'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$defaults&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;//Access Panel admin Aparencce-&amp;gt;Header
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;admin_header_style&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'&amp;lt;script type=""text/javascript"&amp;gt;console.log("admin script")&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;//its works
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;add_action&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'admin-head'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'admin_header_style'&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <category>newticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #43153 (Theme Preview doesn't work) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>CG-TEAM</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 07:34:06 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43153#comment:4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/43153#comment:4/1516952046143257</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
i take screenshot form console and network of two site. one is work fine but other not work.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>not work2.jpg attached to Ticket #43153</title>
      
        <dc:creator>CG-TEAM</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 07:33:36 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/43153/not%20work2.jpg</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/43153/not%20work2.jpg/1516952016561075</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>not work.jpg attached to Ticket #43153</title>
      
        <dc:creator>CG-TEAM</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 07:33:28 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/43153/not%20work.jpg</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/43153/not%20work.jpg/1516952008385588</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>work1.jpg attached to Ticket #43153</title>
      
        <dc:creator>CG-TEAM</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 07:33:18 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/43153/work1.jpg</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/43153/work1.jpg/1516951998766548</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>work.jpg attached to Ticket #43153</title>
      
        <dc:creator>CG-TEAM</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 07:33:06 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/43153/work.jpg</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/43153/work.jpg/1516951986537965</guid>
      <description></description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #17133 (Code Editor: Register ctrl + s event for plugin/theme editor) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Junaidkbr</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 03:56:16 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/17133#comment:24</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/17133#comment:24/1516938976487254</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
@westonruter Please review my patch and provide your feedback on it. I didn't know about this ticket but worked on the feature on my own. I was about to create a new ticket but found this one on my first search.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Anyway, my patch is not modifying &lt;code&gt;code-editor.js&lt;/code&gt; because this file is also used in &lt;strong&gt;Custom CSS&lt;/strong&gt; editor. In &lt;code&gt;code-editor.js&lt;/code&gt;, we don't have a context of which editor is this, or at least I didn't find any.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
There's another neat way to handle the document save with CodeMirror but I couldn't access the &lt;code&gt;commands&lt;/code&gt; property anywhere. Ref: &lt;a class="ext-link" href="http://codemirror.net/doc/manual.html#commands"&gt;&lt;span class="icon"&gt;​&lt;/span&gt;http://codemirror.net/doc/manual.html#commands&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;About the patch:&lt;/strong&gt;
Calling &lt;code&gt;component.submit&lt;/code&gt; directly from the shortcut event isn't possible because &lt;code&gt;componenet.save&lt;/code&gt; needs a parameter which is the form submit event. Due to this limitation, the patch is initiating the form submit event by &lt;code&gt;component.form.submit()&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>Ticket #17133 (Code Editor: Register ctrl + s event for plugin/theme editor) updated</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Junaidkbr</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 03:51:07 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/17133#comment:23</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/ticket/17133#comment:23/1516938667870319</guid>
      <description>&lt;i&gt;Keywords&lt;/i&gt; changed&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <category>editedticket</category>
    </item><item>
      <title>17133.patch attached to Ticket #17133</title>
      
        <dc:creator>Junaidkbr</dc:creator>

      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 03:50:32 GMT</pubDate>
      <link>http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/17133/17133.patch</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://core.trac.wordpress.org/attachment/ticket/17133/17133.patch/1516938632753647</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
Patch for codeMirror editor.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <category>attachment</category>
    </item>
   </channel>
</rss>